<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2013 20:08:10 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_entertainment" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_entertainment"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Photos: Alec Baldwin's public battles</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2013/11/14/showbiz/celebrity-news-gossip/alec-baldwin-battles-gallery/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~3/mDeZLwB-m0g/index.html</link>
<description>&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~4/mDeZLwB-m0g" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2013 06:38:35 EST</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.cnn.com/2013/11/14/showbiz/celebrity-news-gossip/alec-baldwin-battles-gallery/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>By Lisa Respers France, CNN
November 14, 2013 -- Updated 1528 GMT (2328 HKT)
Alec Baldwin recently testified against Genevieve Sabourin (both seen here leaving a Manhattan court house) who is accused of stalking the actor. She claims the pair had a relationship. It's not the first time the "30 Rock" star has found his personal matters at the center of a public battle....
Baldwin had a contentious divorce from actress Kim Basinger in 2002, which included a custody battle over their daughter, Ireland. The pair reportedly had a passionate and stormy nine-year marriage.
Baldwin and his daughter, model Ireland Baldwin, appear to have a close relationship judging by their appearance together at the 65th Emmy Awards in Los Angeles in September. But back in 2007 a voicemail was leaked of the actor yelling at a then 11-year-old Ireland and calling her a "rude, thoughtless little pig."
In 2011, the actor was booted from an American Airlines flight for refusing to turn off his cell phone after the doors had closed. He complained via Twitter that it was all over his playing the online game Words with Friends.
In June 2013, Baldwin once again took to Twitter to slam a reporter who claimed Baldwin's wife Hilaria was tweeting during the funeral of "The Sopranos" star James Gandolfini.
In August 2013, both Baldwin and a photographer called the police to report an incident in New York. Apparently a standoff ensued after the photographer got too close for Baldwin's liking while he was with Hilaria. Baldwin has had several altercations with paparazzi.
HIDE CAPTION
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
