<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2014 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 09:49:44 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_entertainment" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_entertainment"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>How we'll remember Cosby?</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2014/12/08/showbiz/celebrity-news-gossip/bill-cosby-future/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~3/guvlV96Dp3I/index.html</link>
<description>It's as if the other Bill Cosby never existed. The admired Bill Cosby of many years has been almost forgotten amid the allegations against him.&lt;img src="//feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~4/guvlV96Dp3I" height="1" width="1" alt=""/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 22:22:16 EST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141208171102-bill-cosby-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141208171102-bill-cosby-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.cnn.com/2014/12/08/showbiz/celebrity-news-gossip/bill-cosby-future/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>How will we remember Bill Cosby?
By Todd Leopold, CNN
December 9, 2014 -- Updated 0322 GMT (1122 HKT)
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
Until recent allegations, Bill Cosby was admired and considered a role model
Other celebrities have -- fairly or unfairly -- been brought down by allegations
Fellow entertainers, some journalists are left shaken by Cosby story
Crisis management consultant: Cosby should go directly to public
(CNN) -- It's as if the other Bill Cosby never existed.
You remember the other Bill Cosby. For a long time, he was the only Bill Cosby.
Bill Cosby's life in the spotlight
He was a groundbreaking comedian, famed for his shaggy-dog storytelling on routines such as "Noah" and "To Russell, My Brother, Whom I Slept With." He worked clean, even when other comedians went blue.
He was "television's Jackie Robinson," the first African-American to star in a dramatic role on TV, and he earned three Emmys for his work on "I Spy," the series on which he broke the barrier.
For more than 50 years, Bill Cosby has been one of America's leading entertainers: a noted comedian, an Emmy-winning actor and an innovative producer. However, his reputation has been tarnished by allegations of rape. Here's a look at how Cosby, shown here in 2013, has changed through the years:
Cosby, shown here in 1969, began his career in the nightclubs of Greenwich Village as a standup comedian. His clean-cut style became a career mainstay.
Cosby first made his name with his comedic storytelling, often based on his childhood experiences. In 2011, SPIN magazine put "To Russell, My Brother, Whom I Slept With" at the top of its "40 Greatest Comedy Albums of All Time" list. Here, Cosby feeds one of his children in the mid-1960s.
Cosby won three Emmys for his portrayal of Alexander Scott, an Oxford-educated spy who travels undercover as a trainer with his tennis-playing partner, Kelly Robinson (Robert Culp) in "I Spy," which aired on NBC from 1965 to 1968. Cosby was the first African-American to star in an American dramatic series.
In 1972, Cosby starred in "The New Bill Cosby Show," a variety program. Among his guests was Ray Charles, whose version of "Night Time Is the Right Time" would play such a standout role on "The Cosby Show" years later.
In 1972, Cosby helped create "Fat Albert and the Cosby Kids," a Saturday morning TV series that ran for more than a decade. It later became a 2004 live-action film starring Kenan Thompson as Fat Albert.
Cosby's biggest TV hit, "The Cosby Show," premiered in 1984. Phylicia Rashad played his wife, Clair Huxtable.
After "The Cosby Show," the star cast about for other projects. Among them was another sitcom, "Cosby," which aired from 1996 to 2000. Cosby played retired airline agent Hilton Lucas. The show also starred T'Keyah Crystal Keymáh.
President Bill Clinton chats with Cosby and TV correspondent Linda Ellerbee at a 1996 conference on children's television. Cosby, who has a doctorate in education, is a strong believer in using television to send educational messages.
In 1997, Cosby suffered the loss of his son, Ennis, who was killed on the side of an Los Angeles freeway. Cosby's series' "Little Bill" used the phrase "Hello, friend" -- Ennis' regular greeting -- in tribute to his son.
Cosby shares a laugh with baseball great Hank Aaron after they both received the Presidential Medal of Freedom during a 2002 ceremony. The medal is America's highest civilian award.
Comedian Jerry Seinfeld and Cosby embrace at the Mark Twain Prize for American Humor at Washington's Kennedy Center in 2009. Cosby declined the prize twice before accepting. His mother read Twain to him as a child -- a huge influence on his storytelling.
Cosby accepts the Marian Anderson Award in 2010 at the Kimmel Center for the Performing Arts in Philadelphia.
Cosby speaks at the 20th anniversary of Rev. Al Sharpton's organization, the National Action Network, in 2011. In recent years, Cosby has been outspoken on the subjects of poverty, family and responsibility in the black community, which have earned him both praise and criticism.
Cosby speaks onstage during the 100th anniversary celebration of the Beverly Hills Hotel &amp; Bungalows supporting the Motion Picture &amp; Television Fund and the American Comedy Fund. The comedian is active in several charitable causes.
Bill Cosby: Evolution of an icon
Bill Cosby: Evolution of an icon
Bill Cosby: Evolution of an icon
Bill Cosby: Evolution of an icon
Bill Cosby: Evolution of an icon
Bill Cosby: Evolution of an icon
Bill Cosby: Evolution of an icon
Bill Cosby: Evolution of an icon
Bill Cosby: Evolution of an icon
Bill Cosby: Evolution of an icon
Bill Cosby: Evolution of an icon
Bill Cosby: Evolution of an icon
Bill Cosby: Evolution of an icon
Bill Cosby: Evolution of an icon
Bill Cosby: Evolution of an icon
HIDE CAPTION
Bill Cosby: Evolution of an icon
How Cosby scandal came to light
Cosby accusers: There are more women
Lemon welcomes five Cosby accusers
He was a promoter of education and values through "Fat Albert and the Cosby Kids" ( "if you're not careful, you may learn something" ) and his philanthropy. He was an amusing, trusted pitchman, known for Jell-O and Coca-Cola commercials. He was a beloved TV father, the patriarch of "The Cosby Show."
He was wealthy; he was generous; he was admired.
Who is Bill Cosby now?
In recent weeks, the news has provided a steady drip-drip-drip of rape accusations against the 77-year-old comedian. At least 20 women have spoken out to various media outlets, accusing Cosby of sexual misconduct. Many of the accusations date back decades.
Bill Cosby facing litany of allegations
Cosby has lost concert bookings and had a proposed NBC show scuttled and a concert movie premiere postponed. TV Land yanked the "Cosby Show" reruns from its lineup. He's cut ties with his beloved Temple University, where he served on the board. His star on the Hollywood Walk of Fame was defaced . Even the Navy revoked an honorary title granted Cosby in 2011.
It should be noted that Cosby has never faced a judge or jury, let alone been convicted, over the allegations. His camp has repeatedly and vigorously denied them.
It defies common sense that "so many people would have said nothing, done nothing, and made no reports to law enforcement or asserted civil claims if they thought they had been assaulted over a span of so many years," said Cosby's attorney, Martin D. Singer, in a written statement sent to CNN.
But it's clear that many people have already tried Cosby in their minds.
"The court of public opinion has cost him all of his projects," said Michael Bilello, who heads Centurion Strategies, a PR and crisis-management shop. "His inactions, his mishandling of PR, his legal maneuvering -- those are characteristics you do not want to display, especially when you're accused of rape."
The suddenness of Cosby's tumble reminds Bilello of the downfall of Penn State football coach Joe Paterno. For 50 years, Paterno was venerated as "Joe Pa," a figure of such rectitude and honor that the college built a monument to him. Then, as the sexual abuse charges against his former assistant Jerry Sandusky accumulated, Paterno was accused of a cover-up and fired. He died two months later. His statue was later removed from campus.
"Cosby's looking at the same sentence," Bilello said. "He's looking at this overshadowing everything he's done simply because there is guilt by assumption."
New Cosby accuser: 12 more were raped
Cosby accusers meet for the first time
Janice Dickinson breaks down
'This story keeps just getting told'
Cosby is far from the first celebrity to be lowered, fairly or unfairly, from his pedestal.
In the 1920s, silent film star Fatty Arbuckle -- one of the most influential comedians of his day, a mentor to Charlie Chaplin and Buster Keaton -- was accused of rape and manslaughter in the case of an actress, Virginia Rappe, who had attended a party for Arbuckle.
The case was tried three times. The first two trials ended in hung juries. Arbuckle, then 35, was acquitted in the third -- the jury even gave him a written apology -- but the damage was done: His reputation was shattered, his films were temporarily banned, and he had to take a pseudonym to find work. He died while attempting a comeback in the early '30s.
More recently, there is the case of Michael Jackson. In 2003, the singer was accused of child molestation, conspiracy and alcohol charges. Eighteen months later, a jury exonerated him . However, despite the court's decision, allegations of sexual abuse followed Jackson right up to his death in 2009.
What makes the Cosby situation even more challenging is that there has been no day in court, says Syracuse popular culture professor Robert Thompson.
"There was a trial (in Michael Jackson's case). Evidence was presented; process was gone through," he said. "Here, this story keeps just getting told, and it keeps getting told with very little new information."
In addition, Cosby is more than an entertainer, Thompson observes. He's also been an educator and a moralist, using his fame to promote schooling and propriety.
In that respect, says Thompson, the fall of Cosby can be compared to that of evangelists Jimmy Swaggart and Jim Bakker, who were brought down by scandals in the late 1980s. Swaggart was defrocked by his denomination; Bakker was convicted of fraud and served time. Though both resumed ministries, neither has the power or following they did 30 years ago.
'What do you say?'
However, those events all predated the social media age, which has kept Cosby's situation on the front page when it conceivably could have vanished down the memory hole. A handful of accusers first went public almost 10 years ago, in 2005, after Cosby was named by a Temple University staffer, Andrea Constand , in a civil suit.
But it was a viral video by comedian Hannibal Buress that brought the Cosby story out of the shadows, and it was an attempt at creating memes -- proposed by Cosby's own Twitter account -- that made it widespread.
It's shaken up many who normally would be defending a man who they greatly respect. In fact, with a handful of exceptions -- notably Jill Scott and Ben Vereen -- Cosby has received little support among entertainers, though many of them are reserving judgment.
"I don't know what to say. What do you say? I hope it's not true. That's all you can say. I really do," Chris Rock told New York magazine . "I grew up on Cosby. I love Cosby, and I just hope it's not true. It's a weird year for comedy. We lost Robin (Williams), we lost Joan (Rivers), and we kind of lost Cosby."
Cedric the Entertainer agreed. In an "Entertainment Tonight" interview on the red carpet for Rock's movie "Top Five," he expressed both admiration and sadness.
"We all grew up on him, and we know and respect him, not just as a comedian but for the things that he's done outside of comedy, with the colleges and giving back (to the community) and spending his money where his mouth is," he said. "But if the allegations have any truth to them, you want the truth to come out. You want justification for all the people. That's all you can really say. It's an unfortunate scenario."
Jerry Seinfeld was brief.
"It's sad and incomprehensible," he said.
At least one comedy celebrity has become notably anti-Cosby. Judd Apatow, the writer and director of such films as "Knocked Up" and "The 40-Year-Old Virgin," attacked Cosby on his Twitter feed.
"I have numerous personal connections to this situation and the victims. I think he is a coward and clearly a sociopath," Apatow wrote November 26 .
It's shaken up some journalists too, prompting many to offer mea culpas for not asking Cosby about the allegations.
Author Mark Whitaker, a former CNN managing editor who wrote a recent biography of Cosby, apologized for not including the accusations in his book. Ta-Nehisi Coates, who wrote a long piece grappling with Cosby's conservatism in 2008, recently wrote that he should have included more than "a brief and limp mention" of the allegations. And The New York Times' David Carr wrote that he should have asked Cosby about the accusations when interviewing him for an in-flight magazine.
Carr believes there's no repairing the damage to Cosby's reputation.
"For decades, entertainers have been able to maintain custody of their image, regardless of their conduct," he concluded . "Those days are history. It doesn't really matter now what the courts or the press do or decide. When enough evidence and pushback rears into view, a new apparatus takes over, one that is viral, relentless and not going to forgive or forget."
'He has to engage the public'
Is there any way for Cosby to restore his name?
Except for a short exchange with a South Florida publication, he has been silent on the matter -- literally so, in the case of a response to NPR's Scott Simon .
Bilello believes that Cosby is beyond the standard media apology tour, usually capped by a visit to Oprah Winfrey's couch. Cosby has been hurt by social media, he says, and only social media will save him.
"If he wants to have his final chapter written the way he wants to be recalled, he has to engage the public," he said. "Perhaps something social media-based, an open forum for maybe two hours, taking all questions -- and having a moderator who's not a celebrity." A Reddit AMA, say, or a live chat.
On the other hand, 15 Minutes Public Relations' Howard Bragman says Cosby should just stay quiet.
"He should shut the f*** up!" Bragman told TheWrap . "He should have his lawyers shut the f*** up and his PR people shut the f*** up."
Cosby does run the risk of becoming a sad punchline, says Thompson. He's seen it happen. When he shows "Roots" in his television history classes, his students burst out laughing when O.J. Simpson enters the picture.
"The entire mode of the show can't proceed," he said. "O.J. completely trumps everything else that's been happening in the episode."
Either way, says Thompson, Cosby is already fading into history. His college students know the comedian as "a grumpy guy" more familiar from parodies than from his actual work. After all, Dr. Cliff Huxtable, the fatherly Cosby of "The Cosby Show," left the air in 1992 -- more than two decades ago.
"Talk to a 20-year-old (about Cosby), and they think, 'Oh, that's really creepy, that old guy was hitting on women,' but they don't feel about Cliff Huxtable the way people a little older do," he says.
Cosby doesn't have to do anything, of course. For civil claims, the statute of limitations has expired for many of the claims about him, though it varies from state to state, observes Cornell law professor Cynthia G. Bowman. The statute of limitations also varies widely for criminal claims, she adds, but it would be "extremely difficult to reconstruct events," never mind prove anything so many decades later.
Cosby also remains one of America's wealthiest entertainers. He can return quietly to private life and enjoy the rest of his days in seclusion, if that's what he desires. He has about two dozen concert appearances still scheduled , but after a May date in Atlanta, there's nothing on his calendar.
Still, without a final word, Cosby goes from perceived hero to Greek-level tragedy. His circumstance brings to mind "The Natural's" Roy Hobbs, the exalted fictional baseball star who, in Bernard Malamud's novel, is left in ruins.
As the book ends, Hobbs buys a newspaper and reads of his demise.
"And there was also a statement by the baseball commissioner. 'If this alleged report is true, that is the last of Roy Hobbs in organized baseball. He will be excluded from the game and all his records forever destroyed.'
"Roy handed the paper back to the kid.
" 'Say it ain't true, Roy.'
"When Roy looked into the boy's eyes he wanted to say it wasn't but couldn't, and he lifted his hands to his face and wept many bitter tears."
CNN's Eliott C. McLaughlin, Ben Brumfield, Dana Ford, Ronni Berke, Katia Hetter and Ed Payne contributed to this story.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
