<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2014 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 09:49:44 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_entertainment" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_entertainment"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Tribute to Stuart Scott</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2014/12/09/showbiz/celebrity-news-gossip/stuart-scott-cancer-espn-hosts/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~3/J4OsW98ERyA/index.html</link>
<description>&lt;img src="//feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~4/J4OsW98ERyA" height="1" width="1" alt=""/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 11:02:03 EST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141209102339-stuart-scott-april-2014-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141209102339-stuart-scott-april-2014-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.cnn.com/2014/12/09/showbiz/celebrity-news-gossip/stuart-scott-cancer-espn-hosts/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>ESPN hosts pay tribute to Stuart Scott
By Lisa Respers France, CNN
December 9, 2014 -- Updated 1559 GMT (2359 HKT)
The "Monday Night Countdown" crew sent love and well wishes on December 8 to ESPN sportscaster Stuart Scott, who has been battling cancer for the third time. The group joined hands during the broadcast while Suzy Kolber offered some tearful words : "We want you to know we're sending you some extra strength and to keep fighting that fight."
Longtime Green Day guitarist Jason White has been diagnosed with a treatable form of tonsil cancer, the band recently announced on its website. "Thankfully they caught it early and he should make a full and speedy recovery," the statement said.
When "The Simpsons" co-creator Sam Simon learned that he had terminal colon cancer in 2013, he knew right away what he would do with the rest of his life: give away his fortune in support of good causes . In November, Simon said he's still fighting his health battle and is actively giving back through the Sam Simon Foundation.
Hugh Jackman underwent procedures in November 2013 and May and October 2014 to have basal cell carcinoma removed. His rep told People in October that the actor is "OK now."
Fans of singer Morrissey knew that the star had been ill after he canceled some U.S. tour stops in June, but it appears he has been battling cancer. "They have scraped cancerous tissues four times already, but whatever," Morrissey said told Spanish-language outlet El Mundo . "I am aware that in some of my recent photos I look somewhat unhealthy, but that's what illness can do. I'm not going to worry about that."
When former "Good Morning America" host Joan Lunden learned that she was facing an "aggressive" form of breast cancer, she was determined to face her health battle head-on. Knowing she would need chemotherapy, Lunden decided to remove her familiar blond hair before her locks could be affected by the treatment. "You know it's going to happen one of these days and you are wondering how or when," Lunden explained to People magazine , which she posed for without her wig in September. "So I just owned it."
Hugh Jackman took to Instagram on May 8 to share a photo of his nose, which was bandaged because of treatment he had on basal cell carcinoma.
Former "Dancing With the Stars" co-host Samantha Harris has breast cancer and will undergo a double mastectomy, according to People . Harris says she detected a lump during a self-exam and then followed up with a specialist after receiving a clean mammogram, the magazine reported.
Actress Brittany Daniel of "Sweet Valley High" and "The Game" has been quietly dealing with stage IV non-Hodgkin's lymphoma. Daniel recalls in an issue of People magazine that her 2011 diagnosis "happened so suddenly," but she's been able to face it with the support of her family.
Famed journalist Tom Brokaw revealed in February that he's been diagnosed with multiple myeloma , a cancer which affects blood cells in the bone marrow.
Getting a mammogram live on "Good Morning America" for cancer awareness month revealed to ABC's Amy Robach that she had breast cancer in November.
Radio personality Robin Quivers quietly battled cancer for months, but she had happy news to share with "Howard Stern" listeners in September 2013. On the show, Quivers revealed that her doctors now believe she's cancer-free after receiving treatment, including chemotherapy.
Singer Melissa Etheridge became an advocate for the use of medical marijuana after her 2004 breast cancer diagnosis.
Sharon Jones held off plans to tour and release a new album with the Dap-Kings after being diagnosed with stage 1 bile duct cancer in 2013.
Michael Douglas offered some interesting insight as to how he may have developed the throat cancer that he was diagnosed with in August 2010. Douglas later told the "Today" show that his tumor was gone.
Buffalo Bills Hall of Fame quarterback Jim Kelly has been diagnosed with cancer of the upper jaw bone . "Doctors have told me that the prognosis for my recovery is very good," Kelly said in a statement from his former club . Indeed, in August, Kelly was told that he was cancer-free.
Actress Christina Applegate had a bilateral mastectomy in 2008. Doctors had diagnosed her with cancer in her left breast and offered her the options of either radiation treatment and testing for the rest of her life or removal of both breasts.
In 2006, singer Sheryl Crow underwent minimally invasive surgery for breast cancer. In 2012, she revealed she had a noncancerous brain tumor.
KISS band member Peter Criss sat down with CNN's Elizabeth Cohen in 2009, a year after his battle with breast cancer. The musician said he wanted to increase awareness of the fact that men can also get the disease.
Cynthia Nixon not only joined the cast of Showtime's "The Big C," about a woman battling the disease, and portrayed a woman with cancer in the Broadway play "Wit" -- Nixon was diagnosed with breast cancer in 2006.
Zoraida Sambolin was diagnosed with breast cancer in April 2013, and she chose to have a double mastectomy. Sambolin said that Angelina Jolie's New York Times opinion piece about undergoing the procedure gave her courage to share her story.
"Good Morning America" co-host Robin Roberts had been cancer-free for five years in 2012 after beating breast cancer when she revealed she had been diagnosed with myelodysplastic syndrome, also called MDS.
"Three's Company" star Suzanne Somers spoke with CNN's Piers Morgan in 2012 about her stem cell surgery and her bout with breast cancer. She was diagnosed in 2001, which is when she began researching alternative methods to reconstructive surgery.
Olivia Newton-John was diagnosed in 1992, and the singer has become an advocate for breast self-examination.
Actress Kathy Bates didn't share news of her battle until 2012 , eight years after she was diagnosed with ovarian cancer.
Australian singer Kylie Minogue was only 36 when she was diagnosed with breast cancer in 2005.
HIDE CAPTION
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
