<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2014 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 09:49:44 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_entertainment" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_entertainment"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>#PottermoreChristmas kicks off this week </title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2014/12/08/showbiz/jk-rowling-pottermore-christmas/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~3/tvZuJPVf40I/index.html</link>
<description>J.K. Rowling has an early Christmas treat for Harry Potter fans. Readers will get 12 days of new writings by Rowling "and even a potion or two"&lt;img src="//feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~4/tvZuJPVf40I" height="1" width="1" alt=""/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 12:28:39 EST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/140911162843-jk-rowling-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/140911162843-jk-rowling-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.cnn.com/2014/12/08/showbiz/jk-rowling-pottermore-christmas/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>#PottermoreChristmas kicks off this week for Harry Potter fans
By Emanuella Grinberg, CNN
December 8, 2014 -- Updated 1714 GMT (0114 HKT)
Daniel Radcliffe proved on the October 28 edition of "The Tonight Show" that his talents go far beyond acting; Radcliffe's also a pretty great rapper, too. The 25-year-old will next appear in the Judd Apatow comedy "Trainwreck" in 2015. What's the rest of the cast up to these days?
Since portraying sharp witch Hermione in the "Harry Potter" series, Emma Watson has broken away from the supernatural with roles grounded in the (mostly) real world. After "My Week With Marilyn," "The Perks of Being A Wallflower" and "The Bling Ring," the 24-year-old actress also showed her sense of humor in Seth Rogen's outlandish summer comedy, "This Is the End." She'll next appear in the 2015 thriller, "Regression."
Rupert Grint kept it fairly low-key after he ended his 10-year run as one of Harry Potter's best friends, Ron Weasley. The 26-year-old took on a risky role with 2013's "CGBG" -- if you need proof that Grint's all grown-up, check out the trailer.
Bonnie Wright began playing Ginny Weasley at age 10, and since leaving the franchise has been on a steady diet of dramas. Wright appeared in "The Philosophers," followed by "Before I Sleep" with Tom Sizemore.
Just enough time has passed for us to stop cringing at the sight of Tom Felton, who came to be known as the weakling bully Draco Malfoy. Even while working on the "Potter" franchise, Felton dabbled in other films, like "The Disappeared" and "Get Him to the Greek." Felton has been busy since "Potter" wrapped, and appeared in the World War II movie "Ghosts of the Pacific" and the TNT cop drama "Murder in the First."
By the time the "Potter" movies wrapped, Matthew Lewis -- and his character, Neville Longbottom -- had morphed into quite the charming young man . Now 25, Lewis initially migrated over to TV for a spell with "The Syndicate" and "Bluestone 42."
The brothers who played the elder Weasleys -- George and Fred -- don't have the trademark ginger hair anymore , but they're still recognizable as the prankster pair. James (left) and Oliver Phelps are still happy to talk all things "Potter," even as they move on to other endeavors. James has been active on stage, and Oliver has been traveling in support of his website, JopWorld.com.
Evanna Lynch's Luna Lovegood showed up halfway through the "Potter" saga, but her character was so wonderfully strange she's easily among the most memorable. And if there's anyone who's eager for the "Harry Potter" spinoff films, it's Lynch: "Maybe 'Fantastic Beasts' will turn into a long ting like HP did &amp; I can play Luna as an old lady?" she tweeted . "Even if I'm too old to play Luna, can I go through 10 hours prosthetics to play a crumple-horned-snorkack. Please??"
Jamie Waylett's Vincent Crabbe appeared in the first half of the franchise, and life post-"Potter" hasn't been so easy for the actor. In May 2012, he was sentenced to two years in jail for his participation in the 2011 London riots.
Devon Murray's Seamus Finnigan was an easy character to love, and fans have missed seeing Murray (and hearing his accent) on the big screen. The 26-year-old actor assured a supporter from his unverified Twitter account in late September 2013 that he's "been offered a lead role in a new movie so could be seeing my mug soon :)"
HIDE CAPTION
'Harry Potter': Hogwarts class of '11
'Harry Potter': Hogwarts class of '11
'Harry Potter': Hogwarts class of '11
'Harry Potter': Hogwarts class of '11
'Harry Potter': Hogwarts class of '11
'Harry Potter': Hogwarts class of '11
'Harry Potter': Hogwarts class of '11
'Harry Potter': Hogwarts class of '11
'Harry Potter': Hogwarts class of '11
'Harry Potter': Hogwarts class of '11
&lt;&lt;
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
