<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2013 08:41:49 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>How to make 250 tons of kimchi</title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/11/15/travel/kimchi-festival/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/11/15/travel/kimchi-festival/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>Armed with aprons, rubber gloves and sanitary shower caps, a horde of Korean housewives brought in the kimchi season with a mass cabbage-stuffing event. </description>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2013 00:24:25 EST</pubDate>
<ExtractedText>In photos: 3,000 Korean housewives, 250 tons of kimchi
By Frances Cha, CNN
November 15, 2013 -- Updated 1343 GMT (2143 HKT)
If you thought one Korean ajumma (older Korean woman with a curly perm and a 'tude) was scary, try 3,000 in one place. Just kidding. These housewives are Seoul's warmest-hearted -- they gathered on Wednesday to make kimchi for poor households who can't make their own.
Travelers staying at The Plaza hotel (top right) were treated to an unusual sight: Seoul housewives filled the 13,207-square-meter Seoul City Plaza for the largest kimchi-making event to date.
Making kimchi is a labor-intensive process involving salting cabbage, mixing in pureed chili mixture and adding fish sauce and shrimp sauce. Rubber gloves are necessary to prevent chili burn.
When making kimchi, timing is key -- it takes around five to six hours for the cabbage to get properly rubbery, and only then is it ready to be stuffed with the complicated marinade.
A total of 61,700 cabbages were used this year to make 250 tons of everyone's favorite fermented side dish.
Given how complicated the process is, more and more households in South Korea are opting to buy pre-made kimchi in stores. According to a survey by research institute Gallup Korea last month, 67% of Korean households are making their own kimchi, compared to 95% of households in 1994.
According to the same survey, 71% of households responded that kimchi was "absolutely necessary" for every meal. That's a decrease from 85% in 2003.
To a Korean, this salted, choked-with-anchovy-sauce-and-pepper-powder slab of cabbage looks absolutely delicious.
HIDE CAPTION
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
