<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2013 08:41:49 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>'Missing' Pussy Riot inmate in Siberia</title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/11/15/world/europe/russia-pussy-riot-tolokonnikova/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/11/15/world/europe/russia-pussy-riot-tolokonnikova/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>Russian authorities have revealed the whereabouts of a convicted Pussy Riot punk rock band member, three weeks after she was moved from a prison where she went on hunger strike over its conditions.</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2013 07:15:15 EST</pubDate>
<ExtractedText>'Missing' Pussy Riot inmate Tolokonnikova in Siberian prison
By Alla Eshchenko and Susannah Cullinane, CNN
November 15, 2013 -- Updated 1704 GMT (0104 HKT)
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
Nadezhda Tolokonnikova was jailed in Russia last year for her part in a "punk prayer"
In September, the Pussy Riot band member went on hunger strike over prison conditions
In October, she was transferred and her family was not informed of her new location
Her husband said Friday that he had spoken to her at a Siberian prison where she is now held
(CNN) -- Russian authorities have revealed the whereabouts of a convicted Pussy Riot punk rock band member, three weeks after she was moved from a prison where she went on hunger strike over its conditions .
On November 2, Nadezhda Tolokonnikova's husband, Pyotr Verzilov, said his wife had not been heard from since she was transferred from a prison in Mordovia, more than 300 miles east of Moscow on October 24 or 25.
Under law, authorities had to inform her family about her transfer within 10 days of her arrival at a different penal colony.
Pussy Riot documentary director on band
Pussy Riot family speaks out
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
