<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2013 08:41:49 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Ashura</title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/05/01/world/defining-moments/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/05/01/world/defining-moments/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description/>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2013 06:34:13 EST</pubDate>
<ExtractedText>By Monica Sarkar and Ivana Kottasová , CNN
October 31, 2013 -- Updated 1258 GMT (2058 HKT)
NOVEMBER 15 - BIJAR, IRAN: Shiite Muslims cover themselves in mud during Ashura rituals. The holiday marks the death of Imam Hussein, the grandson of Islam's Prophet Muhammad and one of Shiite Islam's most beloved saints. Ashura celebrations are vital to the Shiite minority, who, unlike the Sunni, believe he is the rightful successor of Mohammed.
NOVEMBER 14 - IN SPACE: NASA has unveiled this image of the planet Saturn back lit by the sun. The photo was taken four months ago from the Cassini spacecraft. The ringed planet spans 404,880 miles (651,591 kilometers) across and Mars, Venus and Earth, are also visible in the picture.
NOVEMBER 13 - CUIABA, BRAZIL: Gaviao Indians participate in a tug of war competition during the 12th International Games of Indigenous People. Forty-eight indigenous tribes will present their cultural rituals during the games, which run until November 16.
NOVEMBER 12 - BEIJING, CHINA: A Chinese paramilitary officer patrols Tiananmen Square in front of the Great Hall of the People after the Communist Party concluded its third plenum. China watchers will be looking closely to see if this gathering becomes a launchpad for major new reforms , as the meetings have in the past.
NOVEMBER 11 - TACLOBAN, PHILIPPINES: Emily Ortega rests after giving birth to Bea Joy at an improvised clinic at Tacloban airport . Ortega had to swim to survive before finding safety at the airport when the storm flooded the city. The baby was named after her grandmother Beatrice, who is missing following the onslaught of typhoon Haiyan .
NOVEMBER 8 - CEBU CITY, PHILIPPINES: Filipinos brave powerful winds as Typhoon Haiyan pounds the country. The storm is perhaps one of the strongest ever recorded on the planet. It smashed into island after island across the central Philippines on Friday, threatening millions of people.
NOVEMBER 7 - KAZAKHSTAN: Cameramen film as the Olympic torch leaves Earth as part of its 123-day journey across Russia via the International Space Station, ending at the Black Sea resort of Sochi -- host venue for the 2014 Winter Games. The rocket was launched at 8:14 a.m. local time at the Baikonur Cosmodrome, which is a Russian-leased facility.
NOVEMBER 6 - NEW YORK CITY, U.S.: Newly-elected New York City Mayor Bill de Blasio waves to the crowd at his election night party on November 5. De Blasio will be the first Democratic mayor in New York City in two decades, after easily defeating Republican Joe Lhota by running a campaign that rejected the politics of his predecessor, Michael Bloomberg.
NOVEMBER 05 - MELBOURNE, AUSTRALIA: First run in 1861, Australia's $6 million Melbourne Cup is known as "the race that stops a nation." The 2013 contest was won by the favorite, Fiorente , ridden by Damien Oliver. More than 350,000 people attend the event, with hundreds of racegoers taking part in the "Fashions on the Field" competition .
NOVEMBER 4 - RAJASTHAN, INDIA: A man watches Diwali fireworks light up the night sky above Ajmer town. Millions of Indians set off fireworks for the Hindu Festival of Lights , which celebrates the triumph of good over evil.
NOVEMBER 1 - MADRID, SPAIN: A man walks through central Madrid while checking his phone. After Germany and France, Spain became the latest country to learn about U.S. intelligence spying on its citizens . Spanish media reported earlier this week that the NSA collected data from 60 million phone calls in the country .
OCTOBER 31 - MANILA, PHILIPPINES: Youngsters play basketball at a cemetery, marking one of the most important holidays for the largest Catholic nation in Asia, All Saints' Day . Filipinos traditionally visit cemeteries to hold vigils and large family reunions, but the atmosphere is far from sad, as the usually silent graveyards turn into parties with food and music.
OCTOBER 30 - GAZA: Palestinian prisoners' relatives wait behind a fence for their release at the Erez Crossing in northern Gaza on October 29. Israel freed 26 veteran prisoners early on October 30 as part of a deal put together by the U.S. to jump-start stalled Israeli-Palestinian peace talks.
OCTOBER 29 - CAIRO, EGYPT: Student supporters of ousted president Mohamed Morsy and the Muslim Brotherhood light up a flare as they demonstrate outside al-Azhar university in Cairo on October 28. Since Morsy's ouster and detention in July, his supporters have continued to take to the streets.
OCTOBER 28 - BOULOGNE, FRANCE: Large waves break against the harbor wall at the entrance of the port of Boulogne, northern France, on October 28, 2013. A fierce storm battered Europe and the south of England, leaving at least two people dead. Weather forecasters had said before the storm arrived that it could be the region's worst in a decade.
OCTOBER 25 - RAWALPINDI, PAKISTAN: 13-year-old Awais Shaukat lies in bed, sick with dengue fever . Dengue, a flu-like illness, is spread by the Aedes mosquito and unlike malaria, there are no drugs to prevent it. It spikes during the annual monsoons, when the insects breed in puddles of stagnant water. So far, attempts to develop a vaccine have been unsuccessful .
OCTOBER 24 - KABUL, AFGHANISTAN: Recruits perform drills at the Afghanistan National Army Officers' Academy. Afghans now lead security operations at home , with the remaining international forces responding only when asked. NATO troops are scheduled to leave in 2014.
OCTOBER 23 - YOGYAKARTA, INDONESIA: Rizki a five-year-old volunteer at Kraton, the Yogyakarta Sultanate's royal palace, attends the wedding of one of the five daughters of Sultan Hamengkubuwono X. The wedding celebrations will take three days, include a parade of 12 royal horse-drawn carriages, and culminate with the wedding vows.
OCTOBER 22 - HEILONGJIANG PROVINCE, CHINA: A man pushes his bike up a bridge during a day of extremely heavy smog. Visibility shrank to less than half a football field and small-particle pollution soared to a record 40 times the international safety standard in the northern Chinese region.
OCTOBER 21 - HASAKEH, TURKISH-IRAQI BORDER: Female Kurdish fighters guard a fortified wall, checking for activities by the Al Qaeda-affiliated opposition Jabat al-Nusra, which has been designated as a terrorist group by the U.S. Concerns about the Islamist rebel group Jabhat al-Nusra are at an all-time high with as many as 10,000 fighters and supporters inside Syria.
OCTOBER 18 - LITHGOW, AUSTRALIA: Sean Butler joins fellow residents to fight a fire in the historic township of Newnes Junction. A pink haze hung over the region as bush fires continued to burn uncontrolled across New South Wales . Authorities say hundreds of homes have been lost, with the worst hit areas in the World Heritage area of the Blue Mountains.
OCTOBER 17 - WASHINGTON, DC: Senator Ted Cruz answers questions from the media after the Senate announced that it had reached a bipartisan deal on funding the U.S. federal government. After weeks of bitter political fighting, Congress finally approved a bill to reopen the government and avoid defaulting on its debt -- for now .
OCTOBER 16 - RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL: A Black Bloc anarchist jumps a burning barricade, after a peaceful march of striking teachers ended in clashes between anarchist protesters and the police. People took to streets on Brazilian Teachers Day, demanding better pay and affordable housing for educators .
OCTOBER 15 - MECCA, SAUDI ARABIA: Pilgrims circle the Kaaba as they pray inside the Grand Mosque during the Hajj. Every Muslim is expected to take this journey to the holy city of Mecca during their lifetime. This year, the Saudi government asked people with weakened immunity to avoid the journey , due to an outbreak of MERS virus in the birthplace of Islam.
OCTOBER 14 - ST. PETERSBURG, RUSSIA: Gay rights activists are surrounded by police and anti-gay protesters during a rally in St. Petersburg, which ended in scuffles and violent clashes. An international backlash against Russia's recently-adopted anti-gay propaganda law is gathering speed, as the country prepares for the 2014 Winter Olympics in Sochi .
OCTOBER 11 - BEIRUT, LEBANON: A Syrian girl weeps while waiting for her flight to Germany, where she has been accepted as a refugee. More than 100,000 civilians were killed and 7 million forced to flee their homes during the two-year war. Recognizing its work in Syria, the 2013 Nobel Peace Prize was awarded to the Organisation for the Prohibition of Chemical Weapons.
OCTOBER 10, TAIPEI, TAIWAN: Students celebrate Taiwanese National Day in Taipei. The "Ten-Ten" day marks the anniversary of the 1911 uprising in China that led to the collapse of the nation's longstanding imperial system and the establishment of Taiwan. Beijing still claims Taiwan as part of its sovereign territory.
OCTOBER 9 - RAWALPINDI, PAKISTAN: Boys look out of the window of their classroom at their schoolmates chanting prayers to commemorate the anniversary of Malala's shooting by Taliban . One year after a bullet tried to silence Malala Yousufzai's demand for education , she has published a book and is a contender for the Nobel Peace Prize.
OCTOBER 8 - JERUSALEM: Mourners wait for the funeral procession of Rabbi Ovadia Yosef , 93, the spiritual leader of Israel's ultra-religious Shas political party. Half a million people bade farewell to the former Sephardic chief rabbi of Israel, who played a unique role in Israel's nation-building. He will be also remembered for his fiery rhetoric about Palestinians .
OCTOBER 7 - NEW JERSEY, U.S.: Wearing pink gloves and shoes to show support for breast cancer awareness campaign, David Wilson of the New York Giants celebrates a touchdown against the Philadelphia Eagles. NFL's "A Crucial Catch" initiative is aimed at highlighting the importance of annual screenings , especially for women over 40.
HIDE CAPTION
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
