<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2013 08:41:49 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Storm in numbers</title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/11/15/world/infographic-typhoon-hayian-numbers/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/11/15/world/infographic-typhoon-hayian-numbers/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description/>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2013 16:11:49 EST</pubDate>
<ExtractedText>Tracing Typhoon Haiyan's havoc
November 12, 2013 -- Updated 1205 GMT (2005 HKT)
The unbearable stench of rotting flesh. The search for relatives under heaps of rubble. The desperate pleas for food and water.
Emotional extremes for families of typhoon victims
November 13, 2013 -- Updated 0129 GMT (0929 HKT)
People thousands of miles from the Philippines still felt their hearts stop and their bearings spin as Typhoon Haiyan slammed into the island nation.
How to help Typhoon Haiyan survivors
November 14, 2013 -- Updated 0052 GMT (0852 HKT)
The stories coming out of the Philippines are unimaginable. Rushing water and wind tearing children away from their parents' arms. A city of 200,000 in which no buildings appear to have survived intact.
Could mystery man be patriarch of 30 missing?
November 14, 2013 -- Updated 0111 GMT (0911 HKT)
The image lasts just four seconds, flashed on the screen during the opening sequence of a Filipino news program posted online.
Typhoon creates health crisis
November 11, 2013 -- Updated 2316 GMT (0716 HKT)
The unprecedented natural disaster is a potential medical disaster for the Philippines, according to emergency crews on the ground.
Inmates threaten break out after Haiyan
November 12, 2013 -- Updated 0022 GMT (0822 HKT)
Prison inmates threaten a mutiny if they aren't given food in the aftermath of Typhoon Haiyan. Andrew Stevens reports.
November 11, 2013 -- Updated 2359 GMT (0759 HKT)
CNN reporters capture sounds and images of Typhoon Haiyan's devastating trek through Tacloban, Philippines.
Typhoon victim: This is worse than hell
November 11, 2013 -- Updated 2300 GMT (0700 HKT)
Officials worry the increasing number of decaying bodies will become a health hazard for survivors of Typhoon Haiyan.
November 16, 2013 -- Updated 1347 GMT (2147 HKT)
Typhoon Haiyan, one of the strongest storms in recorded history, left thousands of victims in its wake.
Devastation on the road to Tacloban
November 11, 2013 -- Updated 1719 GMT (0119 HKT)
CNN's Paula Hancocks reports on the grim scene around the city of Tacloban, Philippines, following Super Typhoon Haiyan.
Town crushed by 'giant hand'
November 11, 2013 -- Updated 1240 GMT (2040 HKT)
'I was gob-smacked as we made our final approach into the ruins of the airport in Tacloban,' says CNN's Ivan Watson.
November 11, 2013 -- Updated 2105 GMT (0505 HKT)
Flattened forests and flooded villages in the Philippines seen from the air.
Philippines official: Worst storm ever
November 11, 2013 -- Updated 2058 GMT (0458 HKT)
Christiane Amanpour speaks to the Philippines Secretary of Health about the devastation brought on by Super Typhoon Haiyan.
Typhoon Haiyan relief efforts
November 16, 2013 -- Updated 1345 GMT (2145 HKT)
Troops and aid organizations help Filipinos struggling to survive the aftermath of Typhoon Haiyan, one of the strongest storms in recorded history.
Tacloban residents plead for help
November 10, 2013 -- Updated 1403 GMT (2203 HKT)
CNN's Andrew Stevens was on the ground in Tacloban as Typhoon Haiyan brought a storm surge to the Philippines coast.
November 16, 2013 -- Updated 1402 GMT (2202 HKT)
The storm affected 4.3 million people in 36 provinces and displaced more than 340,000.
Children ripped from parents' arms
November 10, 2013 -- Updated 1637 GMT (0037 HKT)
No building in this coastal city of 200,000 residents appears to have escaped damage from Super Typhoon Haiyan.
Philippines gets more than its share of disasters
November 10, 2013 -- Updated 1954 GMT (0354 HKT)
Powered by ferocious winds, the fast-moving Super Typhoon Haiyan swept through the Philippines, a country of more than 92 million people all too familiar with destructive storms.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
