<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2016 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 15:11:53 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 15:11:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<item>
<title>'Fuller House': TV Review</title>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676982/s/4ddf77a9/sc/28/l/0L0Scnn0N0C20A160C0A20C250Centertainment0Cfuller0Ehouse0Etv0Eshow0Ethr0Efeat0Cindex0Bhtml0Deref0Frss0Ishowbiz/story01.htm</link>
<description>Nostalgia's taint has deluded viewers of a certain generation into believing that, with its hammy child performances, overplayed catchphrases and perfunctory hugs, "Full House" was a good TV show, rather than a show that pandered to the absolute basest of family-friendly instincts.&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392882155/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4ddf77a9/sc/28/rc/1/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392882155/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4ddf77a9/sc/28/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392882155/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4ddf77a9/sc/28/rc/2/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392882155/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4ddf77a9/sc/28/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392882155/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4ddf77a9/sc/28/rc/3/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392882155/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4ddf77a9/sc/28/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392882155/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4ddf77a9/sc/28/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392882155/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4ddf77a9/sc/28/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392882155/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4ddf77a9/sc/28/ach.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392882155/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4ddf77a9/sc/28/ach.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/247392882155/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4ddf77a9/sc/28/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi2.feedsportal.com/r/247392882155/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4ddf77a9/sc/28/a2t2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676982/s/4ddf77a9/sc/28/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 12:52:35 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2016/02/25/entertainment/fuller-house-tv-show-thr-feat/index.html</guid>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160126143855-fuller-house-netflix-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" lang="" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160126143855-fuller-house-netflix-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>Facebook Twitter Instagram
&lt;div class="banner" id="cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0_banner"&gt;&lt;span id="cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" class="_fwph"&gt;&lt;form id="_fw_form_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" style="display:none"&gt;&lt;input type="hidden" name="_fw_input_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" id="_fw_input_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" value="ptgt=s&amp;envp=g_js&amp;w=300&amp;h=250&amp;slau=300x250_sync&amp;adUnit=300x250_sync"&gt;&lt;/form&gt;&lt;span id="_fw_container_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" class="cn-shingle__ad"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
'Fuller House': TV Review
By Daniel Fienberg, The Hollywood Reporter
Updated 2331 GMT (0731 HKT) February 25, 2016
12 photos: 'Full House': Where are they now?
Fans of the the popular sitcom "Full House" have long been clamoring for a revival, and they'll finally get their wish. Netflix is working to bring back the show with original stars Candace Cameron Bure as D.J. and Andrea Barber as her best friend, Kimmy. Let's catch up with the cast.
Hide Caption
1 of 12
12 photos: 'Full House': Where are they now?
Former "Full House" stars, from left, John Stamos, Dave Coulier and Bob Saget got together again for a Dannon Oikos commercial for Super Bowl 2014.
Hide Caption
2 of 12
12 photos: 'Full House': Where are they now?
Candace Cameron Bure – Candace Cameron Bure, aka DJ Tanner, went on to play Summer Van Horne on ABC Family's "Make It or Break It." She also appeared on a 1997 episode of "Boy Meets World" and a 2007 episode of "That's So Raven." In addition to appearing on "Dancing With the Stars," she's continued to work as an actress and has written books about her life as a working wife and mother. She also made headlines in 2014 with statements about being "submissive" to her husband.
Hide Caption
3 of 12
12 photos: 'Full House': Where are they now?
Mary-Kate and Ashley Olsen – After playing Michelle, Mary-Kate and Ashley Olsen starred in "It Takes Two" and "Holiday in the Sun," among other flicks and TV series. Their last gig together was 2004's "New York Minute." Mary-Kate went on to play Tara on "Weeds" and appear in "The Wackness" and "Beastly." Offscreen, the twins have built an empire around several fashion labels, including The Row, Elizabeth and James, and Stylemint.
Hide Caption
4 of 12
12 photos: 'Full House': Where are they now?
Jodie Sweetin – After playing Stephanie, Jodie Sweetin appeared on "Party of Five" and "Yes, Dear." She hosted 2007's "Pants-Off Dance-Off," starred in 2008's "Small Bits of Happiness" and detailed her struggle with addiction in her 2010 memoir "unSweetened."
Hide Caption
5 of 12
12 photos: 'Full House': Where are they now?
Bob Saget – After playing Danny Tanner, Bob Saget channeled another widowed father on "Raising Dad." He hosted "America's Funniest Home Videos" and showed off his R-rated sense of humor in 2005's "The Aristocrats." Saget also narrated "How I Met Your Mother" on CBS.
Hide Caption
6 of 12
12 photos: 'Full House': Where are they now?
John Stamos – After playing Jesse Katsopolis, John Stamos went on to play Dr. Tony Gates on "ER." He appeared on "Glee's" second season, among other shows, and now stars in the Fox series "Grandfathered."
Hide Caption
7 of 12
12 photos: 'Full House': Where are they now?
Dave Coulier – Dave Coulier produced and starred in "Can't Get Arrested" and hosted "Animal Kidding" after playing Joey Gladstone. He appeared on "The Surreal Life" in 2004 and laced up his skates to compete on 2006's "Skating With Celebrities." He married girlfriend Melissa Bring in Montana in June 2014.
Hide Caption
8 of 12
12 photos: 'Full House': Where are they now?
Lori Loughlin – Lori Loughlin, or as we call her, Aunt Becky, starred on "Hudson Street" after "Full House" ended. She appeared on series  "Summerland" and "In Case of Emergency" before acting alongside Robin Williams and John Travolta in the 2009 flick "Old Dogs" and taking on the role of Debbie Wilson on "90210."
Hide Caption
9 of 12
12 photos: 'Full House': Where are they now?
Dylan and Blake Tuomy-Wilhoit – Alex and Nicky Katsopolis were played by Dylan and Blake Tuomy-Wilhoit, respectively, from 1992 until the series finale. Ready to feel old? The adorable twins are legal. Jesse and Becky's boys were played by Kevin and Daniel Renteria during the show's fifth season.
Hide Caption
10 of 12
12 photos: 'Full House': Where are they now?
Andrea Barber – Andrea Barber retired from acting shortly after playing DJ's best friend, Kimmy Gibbler. But she came out of retirement to reprise the role in sketch with Dave Coulier , and now she's set to co-star in the Netflix revival.
Hide Caption
11 of 12
12 photos: 'Full House': Where are they now?
Scott Weinger – Since playing DJ's boyfriend Steve, Scott Weinger has continued voicing Aladdin in films such as "Aladdin and the King of Thieves." Weinger appeared on "Scrubs" and "What I Like About You"; he was also a writer on the WB series. He has worked as a writer-producer on The CW's "90210" as well.
Hide Caption
12 of 12
(The Hollywood Reporter)
Nostalgia's taint has deluded viewers of a certain generation into believing that, with its hammy child performances, overplayed catchphrases and perfunctory hugs, "Full House" was a good TV show, rather than a show that pandered to the absolute basest of family-friendly instincts.
"They don't make shows like this anymore," fans often claim.
But how does Netflix's rebooted "Fuller House" look in a world in which shows such as "Fresh Off the Boat," "The Goldbergs," "The Middle," "Black-ish" and "Modern Family" all deliver family values, cute kids and life lessons along with quality and diversity of perspective?
To me, it looks even more egregious, but people likely to disagree really ought not to bother reading reviews anyway. What? You're reading a review to see if "Fuller House" recaptures the magic of the original? It absolutely does, if you remember that Voldemort practiced magic, too.
Think of "Fuller House" as a perverse play on Gus Van Sant's "Psycho," only with "Full House" creator Jeff Franklin Xeroxing his own sitcom. Where high aspirations left Van Sant doomed to the perception of failure, Franklin and company are likely to succeed, because "Fuller House" is a mawkish, grating, broadly played chip off the "Full House" block.
Read More
It's doubtful that there will be a more painful 2016 TV episode than the "Fuller House" pilot, which takes an inexcusable 35 minutes to establish a plot that is just an inversion of the original "Full House" premise. Candace Cameron's D.J. is a newly widowed mother of a 13-year-old son (Michael Campion's Jackson), a 7-year-old son (Elias Harger's Max) and a baby (Dashiell and Fox Messitt as Tommy). Worried about how to cope, she enlists the help of prodigal sister Stephanie (Jodie Sweetin) and best bud Kimmy Gibbler (Andrea Barber), a newly divorced mother of a 13-year-old girl (Soni Nicole Bringas' Ramona).
'Full House' stars pass the torch at Netflix sequel series premiere
It's such a clean flip of the "Full House" formula that it's amazing the amount of bending over backwards it takes to justify the plot, even if that's secondary to slavish celebration of the original. One after another, "Fuller House" cast members appear onscreen and are greeted by extensive howling, wailing, teeth-gnashing cheers from what sounds like a rabid audience. It doesn't feel entirely inappropriate that John Stamos, Bob Saget, David Coulier and Lori Loughlin would get to bask in episode-halting applause, but when Scott Weinger and Blake and Dylan Tuomy-Wilhoit get nearly equal treatment, there's a sense that either the creators or the audience are messing with us, or messing with any kind of narrative momentum.
Also, it's one thing for a studio audience to engage in this sort of worship, but the "Fuller House" editors are determined to let us experience this rapture in paint-drying real time. It's when the main characters make reference to the absent Michelle  (holdouts Mary-Kate and Ashley Olsen) and then turn and stare at the camera for no less than 13 seconds that you recognize how secondary storytelling is to fan service when it comes to "Fuller House."
The "Fuller House" premiere is almost non-stop references to the original series, filling-in-the-gaps exposition and then a climactic homage to the "Full House" pilot that includes both clips from that series and reenactment. It has no desire to live as its own thing and it's a trend that continues in the early episodes.
The second episode doesn't include any "Full House" clips, but it mentions and restages an allegedly classic scene. The third episode doesn't use clips or restage, but it features a retelling of the plot of an old episode and several nods and references. As part of a weaning process, those next episodes only include cameos by Stamos and Coulier, delivered with the exact level of subtlety that brought the Harlem Globetrotters to Gilligan's Island. At some point, D.J. needs a babysitter and Joey and Mr. Woodchuck fly in from Las Vegas and you realize how little effort has been put into making this anything less than ridiculous.
I've seen six "Fuller House" episodes and, to their credit, the last three are endeavoring to cut at least the most literal cords to "Full House," to be their own show. There are still references to "Full House" and in-jokes about the stars' outside projects, including multiple reminders that "Dancing With the Stars" veteran Cameron Bure is a terrific dancer, but the former castmembers aren't contriving reasons to drop in and the direct mimeographing of plotlines has either stopped or become soft enough that this sporadic viewer of "Full House" was no longer jarred by their obviousness.
It thus becomes possible to finally look at "Fuller House" as its own thing, and the point that's instantly noticeable is that there's an intellectual flaw behind the plot inversion that nobody thought to care about. "Full House" was, no matter its quality, about upsetting gender expectations. It premiered in 1987, the same year as "Three Men and a Baby" and "My Two Dads." There was something in the water. The idea of unmarried men thrust into paternal roles, specifically raising young women, was the next step beyond the 1960s, '70s and early-'80s comedies in which professional women or single women raised children hilariously, as TV looked to reflect society and get distance from the "Leave It To Beaver" nuclear family sitcom model. It wasn't revolutionary, but it was progressive and zeitgeist-y.
"Fuller House," then, is almost inherently regressive and follows no particular demographic or societal trend in dedicating episode after episode to teaching female characters who have or had careers and outside lives to re-concentrate on domesticity and motherhood. The forced male nurturing of "Full House" was about inclusiveness and stepping forward, but this is stepping back, even if you embrace the girl-power heart to this unholy Tanner-Gibbler trinity.
There's also something either unseemly or unsettling about copying and calling back so consciously to "Full House," while also sexualizing the main female characters of "Fuller House." This hasn't suddenly become an adult franchise, but it's apparently impossible not to make repeated references to Sweetin's chest and it will surely be up to "Full House" fans to decide if knowing that Kimmy is a demon in the sack is something that they're prepared for. [Eventually, if "Fuller House" lasts long enough, Kimmy is going to hook up with Jesse, Danny or Joey and that will be the end of the show. You've been warned. Brace yourself. That's where childhood ends.]
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
