<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2016 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 15:11:53 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 15:11:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<item>
<title>Kelly Clarkson brings everyone, including herself, to tears</title>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676982/s/4ddf77ae/sc/13/l/0L0Scnn0N0C20A160C0A20C260Centertainment0Ckelly0Eclarkson0Eamerican0Eidol0Ecry0Epiece0Eby0Epiece0Efeat0Cindex0Bhtml0Deref0Frss0Ishowbiz/story01.htm</link>
<description>Season 1 "American Idol" winner and breakout star Kelly Clarkson returned to the stage that made her famous Thursday night to mark the first live broadcast of "Idol's" final season.&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392882158/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4ddf77ae/sc/13/rc/1/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392882158/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4ddf77ae/sc/13/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392882158/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4ddf77ae/sc/13/rc/2/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392882158/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4ddf77ae/sc/13/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392882158/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4ddf77ae/sc/13/rc/3/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392882158/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4ddf77ae/sc/13/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392882158/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4ddf77ae/sc/13/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392882158/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4ddf77ae/sc/13/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392882158/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4ddf77ae/sc/13/ach.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392882158/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4ddf77ae/sc/13/ach.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/247392882158/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4ddf77ae/sc/13/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi2.feedsportal.com/r/247392882158/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4ddf77ae/sc/13/a2t2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676982/s/4ddf77ae/sc/13/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 12:53:03 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2016/02/26/entertainment/kelly-clarkson-american-idol-cry-piece-by-piece-feat/index.html</guid>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/150820042131-kelly-clarkson-2015-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" lang="" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/150820042131-kelly-clarkson-2015-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>1 of 15
15 photos: 'American Idol' stars: Where are they now?
Seacrest, left, named Nick Fradiani the winner of season 14 of "American Idol" in May 2015. Fradiani has yet to release an album, but his single "Beautiful Life" was the official theme for the seventh FIFA Women's World Cup.
Hide Caption
2 of 15
15 photos: 'American Idol' stars: Where are they now?
Caleb Johnson never landed in the bottom three last season, and now we know why. The Asheville, North Carolina, native went up against Jena Irene and was crowned the winner of season 13. His debut album, "Testify," was released in August 2014 and had the lowest first-week sales of any winner.
Hide Caption
3 of 15
15 photos: 'American Idol' stars: Where are they now?
Candice Glover won season 12, the first female contestant to win since 2007. Her debut album, "Music Speaks," was released in February 2014. She announced on her Facebook page that her sophomore album would contain songs written by her.
Hide Caption
4 of 15
15 photos: 'American Idol' stars: Where are they now?
"American Idol" started its new season in early January, but not all is well with past winner Phillip Phillips. In January 2015, the season 11 winner filed a claim against 19 Entertainment, the show's producers, saying he was "manipulated" into accepting jobs. The Hollywood Reporter wrote that he's trying to void various agreements.
Hide Caption
5 of 15
15 photos: 'American Idol' stars: Where are they now?
Since Scotty McCreery was crowned the winner of season 10 in 2011, the singer's debut album, "Clear As Day," has been certified platinum. He was named the Academy of Country Music's best new artist in 2012 and released his second studio album, "See You Tonight," in 2013. At the start of 2015, McCreery announced his next project would be classic country.
Hide Caption
6 of 15
15 photos: 'American Idol' stars: Where are they now?
Lee DeWyze had released two albums before auditioning for season 9 of "American Idol." After his win, he went on to release a third album, "Live It Up," with RCA Records in 2010. But a year later, the record label dropped DeWyze when the album sold just over 146,000 copies. He has since married model Jonna Walsh, signed with a new label and returned to "Idol" to perform his song "Silver Lining." In 2014, he also wrote a song for "The Walking Dead" soundtrack.
Hide Caption
7 of 15
15 photos: 'American Idol' stars: Where are they now?
Like DeWyze, Kris Allen had released an album before he got on "American Idol." After a very heated battle with Adam Lambert, Allen won season 8 in 2009. After a car accident in which he broke his wrist on New Year's Day 2013, Allen told the Chicago Tribune he was "more driven since 'Idol' " and released his third album, "Horizons," in August 2014. In December 2015 he announced his 2016 "Letting You In Tour" in support of an album scheduled for spring 2016.
Hide Caption
8 of 15
15 photos: 'American Idol' stars: Where are they now?
David Cook rocked a win in a close competition with David Archuleta on season 7. The same year, he released "David Cook," which has been certified platinum. Cook parted ways with RCA Records in 2012. In 2013, he performed a new single on "Idol," "Laying Me Low," which debuted on the charts with 14,000 sales, USA Today reported . He released his fourth studio album, "Digital Vein" in September 2015.
Hide Caption
9 of 15
15 photos: 'American Idol' stars: Where are they now?
Jordin Sparks made history by becoming the youngest winner of "American Idol" at age 17. After she won season 6 in 2007, her eponymous debut album that year went platinum and featured the hit single "No Air." Sparks' second album, "Battlefield," was released in 2009, and its namesake single peaked on the charts. In 2012, she starred in "Sparkle," Whitney Houston's last movie. Her album, "Right Here, Right Now," debuted in August 2015.
Hide Caption
10 of 15
15 photos: 'American Idol' stars: Where are they now?
Taylor Hicks' blues-meets-rock style earned him a following that led to his win on season 5, beating favorite (and now actress) Katharine McPhee. His self-titled debut album was certified platinum, and his single "Do I Make You Proud" debuted at No. 1 on Billboard's Hot 100 Singles. Hicks released "The Distance" in 2008 on his independent record label, Modern Whomp. In 2014 he played a residency in Las Vegas.
Hide Caption
11 of 15
15 photos: 'American Idol' stars: Where are they now?
Carrie Underwood went from college student to winner of season 4 in 2005. Her debut album, "Some Hearts," was certified seven times platinum, and she has gone on to win multiple Grammy Awards. In 2013, she starred in a live television version of "The Sound of Music." Married to hockey player Mike Fisher, Underwood gave birth to their first child, son Isaiah Michael Fisher, in February 2015.
Hide Caption
12 of 15
15 photos: 'American Idol' stars: Where are they now?
Fantasia Barrino defeated Diana DeGarmo on season 3 of "American Idol" in 2004. She then released her debut album, "Free Yourself," which was certified platinum that same year. Barrino won her first Grammy Award in 2011 for the single "Bittersweet," from her third album, "Back to Me." She has appeared on Broadway in "The Color Purple," been the subject of her own reality show and in April 2013 released an album, "Side Effects of You." These days fans get most of their news about her via the singer's Instagram account . She revealed in July 2015 that she and boyfriend Kendall Lamar had wed.
Hide Caption
13 of 15
15 photos: 'American Idol' stars: Where are they now?
Ruben Studdard was crowned the winner of "American Idol" on season 2, beating Clay Aiken in 2003. His first album, "Soulful," debuted at No. 1 on the Billboard 200 that year. Studdard has since released four more studio albums, gotten divorced and shed weight on "The Biggest Loser." In December 2015, Studdard received an honorary master's degree from Alabama A&amp;M University.
Hide Caption
14 of 15
15 photos: 'American Idol' stars: Where are they now?
The moment Kelly Clarkson became the first winner of "American Idol," she became a household name. Since her debut, "Thankful," she has released five additional studio albums and hit singles like "Because of You" and "Stronger (What Doesn't Kill You)." In 2013, she married talent manager Brandon Blackstock, and the couple welcomed a daughter in June 2014. She announced in October 2015 that she was pregnant with her second child.
Hide Caption
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
