<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2016 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 18:00:28 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 18:00:28 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<item>
<title>Live, from Cairo, it's Saturday night!</title>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676982/s/4db5f42e/sc/13/l/0L0Scnn0N0C20A160C0A20C190Cmiddleeast0Csaturday0Enight0Elive0Earabic0Epremiere0Cindex0Bhtml0Deref0Frss0Ishowbiz/story01.htm</link>
<description>Nervous cigarette smoke fills the lounge, wafting through the night's preparatory chaos. The crinkling of scripts mixes with the hum of crew members ironing costumes and makeup artists adding final touches.&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392116868/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4db5f42e/sc/13/rc/1/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392116868/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4db5f42e/sc/13/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392116868/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4db5f42e/sc/13/rc/2/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392116868/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4db5f42e/sc/13/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392116868/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4db5f42e/sc/13/rc/3/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392116868/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4db5f42e/sc/13/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392116868/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4db5f42e/sc/13/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392116868/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4db5f42e/sc/13/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392116868/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4db5f42e/sc/13/ach.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392116868/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4db5f42e/sc/13/ach.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/247392116868/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4db5f42e/sc/13/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi2.feedsportal.com/r/247392116868/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4db5f42e/sc/13/a2t2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676982/s/4db5f42e/sc/13/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 18:00:08 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2016/02/19/middleeast/saturday-night-live-arabic-premiere/index.html</guid>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160218111415-08-cairo-snl-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" lang="" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160218111415-08-cairo-snl-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>15 of 15
Then they realize their skin color is darker so they think maybe Italy or Spain.
Listening to the conversation in the room, they hear Arabic and think they'll be rich in Dubai.
Finally, they hear a very Egyptian word and freak out, refusing to be born.
The show won't shy away from the region's mounting problems, but hopes to tackle them with a unique sense of humor.
"We are trying to do something original. We aren't trying to break taboos but like one the way we do but not intentionally," explains Mansour. "We are trying to make it suitable for a Middle East audience."
Even the terror group ISIS is fair game. "SNL in Arabic" is pointedly referring to them by the derogatory Arabic name, Daesh.
"They get pissed off from [being called] Daesh, so we say Daesh," Mansour adds. "It's quite different if you know that enemy and know all the inside information that could give you the upper hand to make people laugh."
'They are doomed'
It took two years of planning to get the show on air.
The Cairo version will follow the original "Saturday Night Live" satirical sketch comedy model, codified in the SNL bible for franchises around the world.
Last May, several members traveled to New York to meet the original show's cast.
"They had 40 years of figuring it out and to write it in one format book," says Alfons. "It's just a matter of finding the right content for our audience and tweaking the jokes so they are relevant and funny to the entire Middle East."
There will be weekly celebrity hosts. The premiere's guest is one of the region's biggest movie stars, Egyptian actress Donia Samir Ghanem.
They'll also have the other "SNL" mainstays of sketches, digital shorts, the news with "Weekend Update," and live performances.
Three members of the New York cast -- Pete Davidson, Taran Killam and Aidy Bryant -- posted a video wishing their Egyptian colleagues well.
"Welcome to the 'SNL' family and good luck!" they say. "Bye! Later!"
"We done? Yeah, good luck. ... They are doomed," adds Killam.
"It's going to be tough, it's a tough job," says Bryant.
It is a tough job. "SNL in Arabic" puts on two shows a week with a quarter of the staff of the parent show. While they do a one-take performance in front of a live studio audience, the show isn't broadcast live for technical reasons.
They hope that will change soon.
Newbie binge watching
"It is hell, (Davidson, Killam and Bryant) were right about that," says Yara Fahmy, one of the four female cast members. "It's an amazing kind of hell."
Fahmy worked a desk job before auditioning with hundreds of other Egyptians to make the final cut of 12 cast members.
She admits she didn't know about the original "Saturday Night Live" before her audition.
"I went online and looked it up then I started binge watching 'SNL.' I was totally in love," she says. "Kristen Wiig, she is amazing. Every character she does is different. She just appears and people start to laugh. So confident."
"SNL in Arabic" isn't the first satire show in the Middle East.
"'ElBernameg' set the tone for this kind of comedy. It was satire, political and social," says Mansour. "It kind of set a bar for everyone to try to meet. We are trying to live off that legacy."
"ElBernameg" rose out Egypt's 2011 revolution.
Host Bassem Youssef, was dubbed the Middle East's Jon Stewart. Alfons and Mansour both worked on the groundbreaking program that boasted a weekly audience of tens of millions of people across the Middle East.
But in July 2013, the military overthrew one of the main targets of Youssef's satire, Egyptian President Mohamed Morsy. When Youssef applied the same sharp wit to the country's new rulers, the show was quickly taken off air . Bassem Youssef now lives in self-imposed exile.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
