<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2016 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 15:11:53 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 15:11:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<item>
<title>Kanye West's latest feud features producer Bob Ezrin</title>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676982/s/4dd3b8cb/sc/28/l/0L0Scnn0N0C20A160C0A20C240Centertainment0Ckanye0Ewest0Ebob0Eezrin0Efeat0Cindex0Bhtml0Deref0Frss0Ishowbiz/story01.htm</link>
<description>Add another name to Kanye West's growing list of feuds: Bob Ezrin.&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392663773/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd3b8cb/sc/28/rc/1/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392663773/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd3b8cb/sc/28/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392663773/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd3b8cb/sc/28/rc/2/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392663773/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd3b8cb/sc/28/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392663773/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd3b8cb/sc/28/rc/3/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392663773/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd3b8cb/sc/28/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392663773/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd3b8cb/sc/28/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392663773/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd3b8cb/sc/28/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392663773/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd3b8cb/sc/28/ach.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392663773/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd3b8cb/sc/28/ach.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/247392663773/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd3b8cb/sc/28/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi2.feedsportal.com/r/247392663773/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd3b8cb/sc/28/a2t2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676982/s/4dd3b8cb/sc/28/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 12:52:28 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2016/02/24/entertainment/kanye-west-bob-ezrin-feat/index.html</guid>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160218055557-kanye-snl-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" lang="" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160218055557-kanye-snl-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>1 of 22
22 photos: Kanye West's controversial moments
February 2016: Kanye offended Taylor Swift and her fans (not for the first time) when he released a new song, "Famous," in which he croons, "I feel like me and Taylor might still have sex. / Why? I made that bitch famous."
Hide Caption
2 of 22
22 photos: Kanye West's controversial moments
September 2015: West, here with wife Kim Kardashian, asked that concertgoers get to their feet at a show in Sydney. No problem -- until he demanded that some disabled spectators do the same and made snide remarks about a person in a wheelchair.
Hide Caption
3 of 22
22 photos: Kanye West's controversial moments
February 2015: In 2009, West interrupted Taylor Swift's speech at the MTV Video Music Awards to say that her video didn't deserve an award. When he approached the stage at the Grammys in February to interrupt Album of the Year winner Beck, it seemed like a joke -- but no, Kanye wasn't joking. He later apologized .
Hide Caption
4 of 22
22 photos: Kanye West's controversial moments
November 2013: Kanye started yet another conversation when he began using a Confederate flag on some of his new merchandise . By way of explanation, West told Los Angeles radio station 97.1 AMP that observers can "react how you want. Any energy is good energy. You know the Confederate flag represented slavery in a way -- that's my abstract take on what I know about it. So I made the song 'New Slaves.' So I took the Confederate flag and made it my flag. It's my flag. Now what are you going to do?"
Hide Caption
5 of 22
22 photos: Kanye West's controversial moments
October 2013: It wouldn't be a 'Ye performance if it didn't have a few special guests. West made sure his "Yeezus" tour would be a topic of conversation when he had a look-alike Jesus appear on stage with him at Seattle's Key Arena on October 19.
Hide Caption
6 of 22
22 photos: Kanye West's controversial moments
May 2013: The month of May was one long 'Ye-headline fest, as the artist got into another yelling match with a paparazzo after hitting his head on a sign, announced during a show that he's no "mother*****g celebrity" and then revealed that his next album would be called "Yeezus."
Hide Caption
7 of 22
22 photos: Kanye West's controversial moments
February 2013: Soapboxing has been included in the price of admission to Kanye concerts, as the artist has taken various opportunities to get a few things off his chest mid-show. In February, he revealed that he's got "love for Hov but I ain't f*****g with that 'Suit &amp; Tie,' " his friend Jay Z's track with Justin Timberlake. ( The pop singer later hit back at the rapper, coyly rhyming on "Saturday Night Live," "hit's so sick got rappers acting dramatic.")
Hide Caption
8 of 22
22 photos: Kanye West's controversial moments
December 2012: Every expectant parent has their own way of breaking the news to loved ones that they're awaiting an addition to the family. Kanye opted to share the joyous news with concert attendees at his Atlantic City show on December 31, when he encouraged the crowd to "make some noise" for his "baby mama."
Hide Caption
9 of 22
22 photos: Kanye West's controversial moments
April 2012: With speculation raging, since he couldn't seem to keep his pants up while hanging out with Kim Kardashian, Kanye dropped a single in which he admitted he was in love with her. Time soon revealed that the two were indeed an item.
Hide Caption
10 of 22
22 photos: Kanye West's controversial moments
August 2011: Still struggling with a negative public perception, West told the audience gathered at the UK's Big Chill film festival, "I walk through the hotel and I walk down the street, and people look at me like I'm f****n' insane, like I'm Hitler." That comparison, for obvious reasons, made international headlines.
Hide Caption
11 of 22
22 photos: Kanye West's controversial moments
March 2011: The NSFW album cover for Kanye West's "My Beautiful Dark Twisted Fantasy" was just the beginning of trouble for the rapper. After fearing censorship over his cover art -- "Banned in the USA!!! They don't want me chilling on the couch with my phoenix!" he tweeted at the time -- there was debate over whether his music video for "Monster" should also be censored , thanks to its depiction of West in bed with two lifeless women, among other controversial images.
Hide Caption
12 of 22
22 photos: Kanye West's controversial moments
November 2010: While gearing up to release "My Beautiful Dark Twisted Fantasy," West did a promotional appearance on "Today" with Matt Lauer -- one that quickly turned sour and led to him canceling his performance on the show.
Hide Caption
13 of 22
22 photos: Kanye West's controversial moments
July 2010: Before Amanda Bynes, Kanye West had the Twitter account to watch . His posts, frequently in all caps, would go from random, humorous comments to epic rants, to an 80-plus-tweet business plan for "DONDA."
Hide Caption
14 of 22
22 photos: Kanye West's controversial moments
September 2009: Even with his noted troublemaking at past awards shows, no one -- including West -- had figured out by September 2009 that they weren't the best places for him to hang out. What transpired at the MTV event is one of the most infamous moments in live TV, as he interrupted Taylor Swift during her acceptance speech for the best female music video.
Hide Caption
15 of 22
22 photos: Kanye West's controversial moments
September 2008: Yeezy's beef with paparazzi goes way back. For example, in September 2008, West was arrested on felony vandalism charges at Los Angeles International Airport after he got into a skirmish with two paps and allegedly damaged their cameras.
Hide Caption
16 of 22
22 photos: Kanye West's controversial moments
June 2008: Like most with an overwhelming number of strong opinions, Kanye was a natural at blogging on his site, Kanyeunivercity.com. So when he was booed at 2008's Bonnaroo music festival after showing up late for his set, the rapper let loose on the fest's organizers via his blog -- in caps lock, of course. "I HAVE A F****** LIGHT SHOW DUMB A**," he said. "IT'S NOT CALLED GLOW IN THE DARK FOR NO REASON SQUID BRAINS!"
Hide Caption
17 of 22
22 photos: Kanye West's controversial moments
September 2007: Awards shows are such a sticking point for Mr. West. When he lost out on all five of his MTV VMAs and wasn't scheduled to perform on the main stage, which had boasted the likes of Justin Timberlake and Britney Spears, West threw a fit, threatening not to return to the awards ceremony.
Hide Caption
18 of 22
22 photos: Kanye West's controversial moments
November 2006: Kanye really doesn't like losing, and he reminded us of that at the MTV Europe Music Awards in November 2006, when he stage-crashed Justice vs. Simian's best video win for "We Are Your Friends." Clearly, his video "Touch the Sky" should've won because "it cost a million dollars, and Pamela Anderson was in it." Having a "sippy sippy" pre-awards show might convince one of such merits.
Hide Caption
19 of 22
22 photos: Kanye West's controversial moments
February 2006: A year after his theatrical performance of "Jesus Walks" at the Grammys, West posed as Jesus Christ on the cover of Rolling Stone magazine in February 2006. It was a move so controversial he later claimed, "I can't even get endorsements now. The ones that might have been open to me when I was just a cute kid in a Polo."
Hide Caption
20 of 22
22 photos: Kanye West's controversial moments
September 2005: If you didn't know by September 2005 that Kanye is not the type to stick to the script, he proved it during a relief telethon for Hurricane Katrina victims. Speaking alongside Mike Myers, 'Ye memorably started ad-libbing, leading to a phrase that still hasn't lived down its infamy: "George Bush doesn't care about black people."
Hide Caption
21 of 22
22 photos: Kanye West's controversial moments
November 2004: The loss of best new artist to Gretchen Wilson at the American Music Awards turned 'Ye into an outspokenly sore loser. The "College Dropout" artist not only walked out of the AMAs, he told the press , "I felt like I was definitely robbed. ... I was the best new artist this year."
Hide Caption
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
