<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2016 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 16:32:07 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 16:32:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<item>
<title>#OscarsSoWhite? It starts with the academy</title>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676982/s/4dcb2bf2/sc/13/l/0L0Scnn0N0C20A160C0A10C190Centertainment0Coscars0Eso0Ewhite0Eacademy0Efeat0Cindex0Bhtml0Deref0Frss0Ishowbiz/story01.htm</link>
<description>&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392451695/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dcb2bf2/sc/13/rc/1/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392451695/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dcb2bf2/sc/13/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392451695/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dcb2bf2/sc/13/rc/2/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392451695/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dcb2bf2/sc/13/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392451695/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dcb2bf2/sc/13/rc/3/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392451695/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dcb2bf2/sc/13/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392451695/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dcb2bf2/sc/13/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392451695/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dcb2bf2/sc/13/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392451695/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dcb2bf2/sc/13/ach.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392451695/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dcb2bf2/sc/13/ach.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/247392451695/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dcb2bf2/sc/13/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi2.feedsportal.com/r/247392451695/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dcb2bf2/sc/13/a2t2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676982/s/4dcb2bf2/sc/13/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 16:29:58 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2016/01/19/entertainment/oscars-so-white-academy-feat/index.html</guid>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160119111347-oscar-denzel-washington-2002-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" lang="" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160119111347-oscar-denzel-washington-2002-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>Facebook Twitter Instagram
&lt;div class="banner" id="cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0_banner"&gt;&lt;span id="cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" class="_fwph"&gt;&lt;form id="_fw_form_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" style="display:none"&gt;&lt;input type="hidden" name="_fw_input_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" id="_fw_input_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" value="ptgt=s&amp;envp=g_js&amp;w=300&amp;h=250&amp;slau=300x250_sync&amp;adUnit=300x250_sync"&gt;&lt;/form&gt;&lt;span id="_fw_container_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" class="cn-shingle__ad"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
#OscarsSoWhite? It starts with the academy
Updated 0609 GMT (1409 HKT) January 20, 2016
14 photos: Black Academy Award winners
Hattie McDaniel was the first African-American to win an Academy Award, snagging a best supporting actress Oscar in 1940 for her role as Mammy in "Gone With The Wind."
Hide Caption
14 photos: Black Academy Award winners
In 1964, Sidney Poitier won best actor for "Lilies of the Field."
Hide Caption
2 of 14
14 photos: Black Academy Award winners
Louis Gossett Jr. poses in 1983 with his best supporting actor award for his role in "An Officer and a Gentleman."
Hide Caption
14 photos: Black Academy Award winners
Denzel Washington accepts his best supporting actor Oscar for the film "Glory" in 1990.
Hide Caption
14 photos: Black Academy Award winners
Her role in "Ghost" won Whoopi Goldberg a best supporting actress trophy in 1991.
Hide Caption
5 of 14
14 photos: Black Academy Award winners
Cuba Gooding Jr. throws his Oscar into the air after being named best supporting actor for his role in "Jerry Maguire" in 1997.
Hide Caption
6 of 14
14 photos: Black Academy Award winners
Denzel Washington became the first African-American to win two Oscars in the acting categories when he won best actor in 2002 for "Training Day."
Hide Caption
14 photos: Black Academy Award winners
2002 also saw Halle Berry win the best actress Oscar for "Monster's Ball."
Hide Caption
14 photos: Black Academy Award winners
Jamie Foxx won best actor for "Ray" in 2005.
Hide Caption
9 of 14
14 photos: Black Academy Award winners
Morgan Freeman picked up the Oscar for best supporting actor for his role in "Million Dollar Baby" in 2005.
Hide Caption
14 photos: Black Academy Award winners
"The Last King of Scotland" star Forest Whitaker won best actor in 2007.
Hide Caption
14 photos: Black Academy Award winners
Jennifer Hudson won the best supporting actress Oscar for "Dreamgirls" in 2007.
Hide Caption
12 of 14
14 photos: Black Academy Award winners
In 2009, Mo'Nique was named best supporting actress for her role in "Precious: Based on the Novel 'Push' by Sapphire."
Hide Caption
13 of 14
14 photos: Black Academy Award winners
Lupita Nyong'o won the best supporting actress Oscar in 2014 for her role in "12 Years a Slave."
Hide Caption
The voters for the Academy Awards are overwhelmingly white
The academy's president says a review will bring more diversity
(CNN)
This year's debate over #OscarsSoWhite is once again highlighting Hollywood's race problem, sharpening the focus on just who is handing out the industry's biggest awards.
For the second year in a row, there were no people of color nominated for Academy Awards in any of the major categories, prompting social media to react with a continuation of last year's #OscarsSoWhite campaign: #OscarsStillSoWhite.
Others were outraged, too. Filmmaker Spike Lee and actress Jada Pinkett Smith have said they plan to boycott this year's Academy Awards.
Fans have rallied around their decision.
Jada Pinkett Smith Suggests All Black People Boycott The Oscars and I Agree pic.twitter.com/A3qHeLURxu
— Affinity Magazine (@TheAffinityMag) January 16, 2016
I agree with Mrs. Jada, boycott the Oscars, Grammys, golden globe. &amp; attend all black Award ceremony's
— Great Exalted (@Tor_West) January 16, 2016
Read More
I think Jada Pinkett was saying we minorities should stop bothering with the Oscars entirely of they can't recognize our contributions
Jada Pinkett Smith, Spike Lee to boycott Oscars ceremony
The demographics of the academy, which decides the nominees and winners, have long been a point of contention, as they don't reflect the diversity of moviegoers. According to a 2014 study (PDF), 25% of frequent moviegoers were Hispanic, 10% were African-American, and 9% were Asian or of another background.
JUST WATCHED
The weird way Oscar votes are counted 01:25
JUST WATCHED
MUST WATCH
Racism without racists? 01:18
The Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences is made up of more than 7,000 people who work in cinema.
According to its website , individuals cannot apply for membership but must be "sponsored by two Academy members from the branch to which the candidate seeks admission." Those who are nominated for Academy Awards don't have to be sponsored, as they are automatically considered for membership.
"Nominees and sponsored candidates are reviewed by branch committees and recommendations for membership are considered by the Academy's Board of Governors," the rules state. "The Board decides which individuals will receive invitations."
HLNtv.com: According to the Academy, these are not the top performances of 2015
In 2012, a Los Angeles Times study of the academy found that "Oscar voters are nearly 94% Caucasian and 77% male" while "Blacks are about 2% of the academy, and Latinos are less than 2%."
"Oscar voters have a median age of 62, the study showed," the story said. "People younger than 50 constitute just 14% of the membership."
That same year, a study from the UC Berkeley School of Law titled " Not Quite a Breakthrough: The Oscars and Actors of Color, 2002-2012" (PDF) examined the industry since 2002, considered a big year because of the best actress and best actor Oscar wins by Halle Berry and Denzel Washington.
The study found that while there had been expectations of more diversity following that watershed moment (there had never before been a year in which two African-Americans won in the acting category), the reality was far different. "Oscar winners and nominees of color make fewer movies per year after their nominations than their white peers do," the study found, and "Oscar winners and nominees of color are less likely than their white peers to receive subsequent nominations.
"The Academy should form a task force to examine its membership procedures and develop steps to make it more inclusive of people of color and women," the study authors wrote. "In light of its exclusionary membership, the Academy's passive stance toward diversity is inadequate."
Today, it appears that not much has changed.
A photo posted by Lupita Nyong'o (@lupitanyongo) on
Jan 19, 2016 at 8:40pm PST
Lee and Low Books' infographic on "The Diversity Gap in the Academy Awards" says that among the branches of the academy, 97% of the producers and writers were white, while 88% of the actors were white. Overall, 93% of academy voters were white and 76% were male in 2015.
I'm not quite sure what you expect when over 90% of The Academy is made up of old white men. #oscars
— Myla (@thatsmyla) January 14, 2016
"If you think back 10 years ago, the Academy was doing a better job," actor and filmmaker George Clooney told Variety . "Think about how many more African Americans were nominated. I would also make the argument, I don't think it's a problem of who you're picking as much as it is: How many options are available to minorities in film, particularly in quality films?"
Critics agree that the issue goes far beyond awards season.
The 2015 Hollywood Diversity Report (PDF) produced out of the Ralph J. Bunche Center for African American Studies at UCLA said that while minorities had made some gains in Hollywood, they still remained "underrepresented on every front," most notably in terms of wielding leadership power.
"White males continued to dominate the positions from which green-lighting decisions are made in the Hollywood industry," the study said.
In February, Dennis Romero wrote in L.A. Weekly ,  "The industry has a serious diversity problem, and it doesn't appear that the business can quell critics by greenlighting a handful of minority-driven TV shows (Empire, Fresh Off the Boat, Jane the Virgin) or by celebrating a globe-trotting Mexican director (Academy Award nominee Alejandro Gonzalez Iñárritu of Birdman) who has little in common with the American Latino experience.
"Because there's so much money on the line -- it can take $100 million (including marketing costs) to get a hit studio film off the ground -- there's an extreme reluctance to take chances when it comes to casting and choosing directors, experts say," Romero wrote. "A white man can seem like a safe choice, especially now that half a film's revenue can come from overseas markets, markets that often are paying to see a certain vision of American culture. Leads are by default taken to be white unless otherwise written, which is why it was big news when it was rumored that black British actor Idris Elba would be the next James Bond."
On Martin Luther King Day, the president of the Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences, Cheryl Boone Isaacs -- who is African-American -- said in a statement that she was "both heartbroken and frustrated about the lack of inclusion" among this year's nominees.
A statement from Academy President Cheryl Boone Isaacs pic.twitter.com/Nqhgc7sbqG
Oscars president 'heartbroken and frustrated' about lack of diversity
"In the coming days and weeks we will conduct a review of our membership recruitment in order to bring about much-needed diversity in our 2016 class and beyond," she said. "We have implemented changes to diversify our membership in the last four years. But the change is not coming as fast as we would like. We need to do more, and better and more quickly."
Viewers are eagerly waiting to see how Academy Awards host Chris Rock handles the controversy at the ceremony February 28. So far, he's only said via his Twitter account that the Oscars are "the white BET Awards."
The #Oscars . The White BET Awards. https://t.co/8qjLR0uysI
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
