<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2014 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 08:57:44 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_sport" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_sport"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Football: Legend Pele leaves hospital</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://edition.cnn.com/2014/12/09/sport/football/brazil-pele-released/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~3/RGs3gqv0aQA/index.html</link>
<description>Soccer legend Pele joked with reporters Tuesday after he was discharged Tuesday from a Sao Paolo, Brazil, hospital.&lt;img src="//feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~4/RGs3gqv0aQA" height="1" width="1" alt=""/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 18:04:17 EST</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/12/09/sport/football/brazil-pele-released/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Soccer legend Pele leaves hospital
By Steve Almasy, CNN
December 9, 2014 -- Updated 2112 GMT (0512 HKT)
Ask many Brazilians who is the greatest footballer of all time and their answer will be simple: "Pele." The striker, pictured here in 2014, won three World Cups with Brazil between 1958 and 1970.
Pele is his country's leading goalscorer with 77 goals from 92 caps.
The Brazil team of 1970, which beat Italy 4-1 in the World Cup final in Mexico, is widely regarded as the greatest of all time. Pele is seen here leaping on his teammates.
Pele told CNN that his most memorable moment as a player was winning the 1958 World Cup when he was just 17.
Brazil also won the title in 1962 in Chile, but Pele did not play in the final after being injured in Brazil's second game.
Ahead of the World Cup earlier this year, Pele told CNN that his ideal final for 2014 would feature Brazil and Uruguay -- so his country can win revenge for 1950's heartbreaking Maracana defeat in the deciding match between the two South American teams. But Brazil crashed out after being beaten by eventual winners Germany 7-1 in the semifinal.
Aerial view of the Christ the Redeemer statue atop Corcovado Hill, overlooking the Maracana stadium in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. The famous arena hosted the 2014 World Cup final in July.
HIDE CAPTION
Pele spent 15 days in the hospital
He jokes that he has three hearts so he was never in danger of dying
Pele is considered one of the top two soccer players of all time
He began his soccer career in the late 1950s
(CNN) -- Soccer legend Pele joked with reporters Tuesday after he was discharged Tuesday from a Sao Paolo, Brazil, hospital.
"I was worried, but I never feared I'd die. Because I am from Tres Coracoes, ("I have three hearts"), it will be difficult for me to die," the three-time World Cup winner said. "But my doctor warned me that I very nearly lost one of my hearts back there."
Pele, born Edson Arantes do Nascimento, was moved out of intensive care on Sunday, Albert Einstein Hospital said.
Pele, 74, had been hospitalized since November 24 and had kidney dialysis for several days.
He said he was surprised by the outpouring of love from his fans worldwide.
"I received messages from China, Pakistan, all over Europe," he said "I didn't know everyone was paying attention to my situation."
The athletic icon had one kidney removed during his days as a player, his aide, Jose Fornos Rodrigues, said last week.
"When I went to play at Cosmos, I wasn't feeling well, and the doctor told me I was playing for a while with just one kidney. He said I had both inside but only one working. That's why I had surgery in New York and nobody found out about it," Pele said Tuesday.
Known as "The Black Pearl" and simply "The King," Pele is one of the best known names in all of sports.
He burst onto the scene as a teenager, helping lead his native Brazil to the 1958 World Cup championship. Pele went on to star on two other World Cup title teams as well, in 1962 and 1970, in addition to a breakthrough career with the Brazilian club Santos and later with the New York Cosmos of the now-defunct North American Soccer League.
In 2000, he and Argentina's Diego Maradona were named co-Players of the Century by FIFA, the international soccer governing body.
Santos named him a lifetime ambassador for the club, Pele told fans this week.
"It is exciting to know that I will be wearing the shirt of my favorite team for the rest of my life," he wrote on Twitter. "I expect to keep bringing pride and joy to Santos fans all around the world."
Even after retiring from football, Pele has remained in the public eye as a product pitchman, ambassador for the sport of football and advocate for Brazil's poor, having grown up among them in Tres Coracoes.
CNN's Barbara Arvanitidis contributed to this report.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
