<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2013 20:08:10 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_entertainment" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_entertainment"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Fall TV scorecard: What's hot, what's not</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2013/10/17/showbiz/tv/fall-tv-shows-scorecard/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~3/D5tsl6HEQRo/index.html</link>
<description>Fall TV can be so hit ... or miss.&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~4/D5tsl6HEQRo" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 10:03:06 EDT</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.cnn.com/2013/10/17/showbiz/tv/fall-tv-shows-scorecard/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Fall TV scorecard: What's hot and what's not
By Henry Hanks and Lisa Respers France, CNN
October 18, 2013 -- Updated 2329 GMT (0729 HKT)
NBC appears to have a hit with "The Blacklist" starring James Spader, right, and Diego Klattenhoff.
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
"Sleepy Hollow" and "The Blacklist" are among the season's hits
Favorites Michael J. Fox and Sean Hayes are struggling with new shows
Two shows have already been canceled -- "Lucky 7" and "We Are Men"
(CNN) -- Fall TV can be so hit ... or miss.
And like it or not, it doesn't take long for both viewers and networks to make the call. There have already been some surprise hits such as "Sleepy Hollow" as well as some casualties: Both ABC's "Lucky 7" and CBS' "We Are Men" were canceled after only two episodes, and there are surely more shows to follow.
UPDATE: Since this story was first published, there have been some developments. According to Deadline , CBS has ordered full seasons of "The Crazy Ones," "The Millers," and "Mom." Meanwhile NBC has canceled "Ironside" and "Welcome to the Family," The Wrap reported.
Let's take a look at how some of the network shows are faring:
Hits
• "Sleepy Hollow" (Fox) -- This is one hit few saw coming. Fans appear to love it, and USA Today called it the "best new show."
• "The Blacklist" (NBC) -- James Spader is killing the game as a master criminal in this new drama. The show might also be benefiting from its lead-in, "The Voice." Either way, people are watching.
Controversy surrounds Fox's 'Dads'
• "Marvel's Agents of S.H.I.E.L.D." (ABC) -- This widely anticipated Joss Whedon production had a huge premiere but has slowed just a tad in recent weeks. It's still big though, especially with the DVR set.
• "The Goldbergs" (ABC) -- So far, so good. Ratings have been decent, and this comedy might just swing a second season. According to Deadline, more scripts have already been ordered.
• "The Crazy Ones" (CBS) -- Mork and Buffy make a killer ratings combo, it seems. This sitcom starring Robin Williams and Sarah Michelle Geller appears to be pretty solid. The Salt Lake Tribune says it looks like a winner. A full season has been ordered.
• "The Millers" (CBS) -- Lucky show. Its lead-in is the ratings juggernaut "The Big Bang Theory," so, yeah, it's doing well. Like "The Crazy Ones," CBS was pleased enough to order a full season.
• "The Originals" (CW) -- The "Vampire Diaries" spinoff is getting respectable ratings and has had additional scripts ordered.
CNN's Fall Entertainment Guide
Misses
• "The Michael J. Fox Show" and "Sean Saves the World" (NBC) -- These two are grouped together because they have much in common: the return of two beloved actors, Michael J. Fox and Sean Hayes, and the fact that both, surprisingly, appear to be struggling. Variety listed them on their "10 Coldest TV Shows of the Fall."
• "Hostages" (CBS) -- This one does not have the ratings tied up. Don't look for it to make a second season.
"Betrayal" (ABC) -- Proof that not every show built around a mistress will work. According to TV Guide, ratings are down, and some critics wonder if it will be the next series to be canceled.
• "Back in the Game" (ABC) -- Not every movie actor's foray into television is going so well. We are going to go ahead and list this one starring James Caan as "dead show walking."
• "Welcome to the Family" (NBC) -- If you didn't get to know the family it's too late, as NBC has announced its cancellation.
• "Mom" (Fox) -- All the elements are there. The comedy stars Anna Faris and Allison Janney and was created by Chuck Lorre, the mind behind hits such as "Two and a Half Men." So why is it not working? Still, CBS has ordered a full season.
• "Ironside"(NBC) -- The reboot of this classic series with Blair Underwood starring as a paraplegic was called the "worst new drama" by one critic. Viewers seem to agree. NBC recently decided to cancel the show.
So-So
• "Brooklyn Nine-Nine" (Fox) -- This one feels very "Parks and Recreation." It's a critical darling, but ratings have not been overwhelming. We are rooting for you, Andy Samberg.
• "Once Upon a Time in Wonderland" (ABC) -- This one has us a little worried. The big budget fairytale series occupies the Thursday 8 p.m. slot, which puts it opposite CBS' popular "The Big Bang Theory" and NBC's fan favorite "Parks and Recreation." That time slot could spell doom.
• "Super Fun Night" (ABC) -- It should have been a surefire hit, coming after "Modern Family." And while lots of viewers tried it out initially, declining ratings in week two indicate they weren't too impressed. No bueno for star and creator Rebel Wilson.
• "The Tomorrow People" (CW) -- The paranormal series is hanging on ... for now.
• "Trophy Wife" (ABC) -- Critics seem to love it, but ratings have not been overwhelming. ABC has said the show recently pulled in 1.3 million more viewers than Fox's "The Mindy Project" (2.8 million), and the network has ordered more scripts. That's good, as it probably needs more time.
• "Dads" (Fox) -- This live-action Seth MacFarlane comedy has been called racist and sexist, but the controversy has not stopped the network from ordering more scripts.
Tell us what your favorite -- and least favorite -- shows have been so far?
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
