<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2014 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 08:57:44 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_sport" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_sport"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Bianchi crash explained</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://edition.cnn.com/2014/12/03/sport/jules-bianchi-crash-fia-report/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~3/vMfv4ukqPyc/index.html</link>
<description>Jules Bianchi "did not slow sufficiently to avoid losing control" during his crash at the Japanese Grand Prix, according to an FIA report published Wednesday.&lt;img src="//feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~4/vMfv4ukqPyc" height="1" width="1" alt=""/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2014 11:10:24 EST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141005082310-bianchi-head-shot-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141005082310-bianchi-head-shot-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<feedburner:origLink>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/12/03/sport/jules-bianchi-crash-fia-report/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Jules Bianchi 'did not slow sufficiently' before crash, says FIA
December 3, 2014 -- Updated 1836 GMT (0236 HKT)
The world of Formula One has been shocked after popular French racer Jules Bianchi suffered a serious head injury during a crash at the Japanese Grand Prix on October 5.
Bianchi, who is in his second season with the Marussia team, received urgent medical treatment after crashing when rain fell towards the end of the race at the demanding Suzuka circuit.
A visibly distressed Adrian Sutil witnessed the crash. Bianchi collided with a recovery vehicle that was attempting to move the German's Sauber.
Marussia chose not to run another driver in Bianchi's car at the next race in Russia out of respect for the Frenchman who remains critical but stable in a Japanese hospital.
There were subdued scenes in Sochi as the F1 drivers hold a minute's silence before the race in respect for the stricken Bianchi.
Marussia staged its own emotional tribute on the grid with sole driver Max Chilton holding a pit board which reads "Racing for Jules."
HIDE CAPTION
Jules Bianchi crash stuns Formula One
Jules Bianchi crash stuns Formula One
Jules Bianchi crash stuns Formula One
Jules Bianchi crash stuns Formula One
Jules Bianchi crash stuns Formula One
Jules Bianchi crash stuns Formula One
&lt;&lt;
Jules Bianchi suffered head injuries after crash at Japanese Grand Prix
FIA published 396-page report into accident Wednesday
Bianchi currently in French hospital
French driver's Marussia team folded in November
Follow us at @WorldSportCNN and like us on Facebook
(CNN) -- Jules Bianchi "did not slow sufficiently to avoid losing control" during his crash at the Japanese Grand Prix, according to an FIA report published Wednesday .
The Marussia driver, who suffered life-threatening head injuries, crashed into a recovery vehicle at Suzuka in October and was immediately taken to hospital.
The 25-year-old remains unconscious at a French hospital in Nice but is breathing unaided and is no longer in an artificial coma .
The Frenchman suffered a diffuse axonal head injury after colliding with the Sauber of Adrian Sutil, which was being removed from the circuit.
F1 driver suffered serious brain injury
F1 driver Jules Bianchi injured in crash
Can Formula One come up with a formula to solve its financial problems? The sport is facing a long, winding road ahead as it attempts to work out how best to split the huge revenue it generates.
F1 generated an estimated $1.7 billion in 2013, but that hasn't stopped Marussia going out of business. The team folded on Friday, while Caterham has also entered administration this season. Here, Ferrari's Fernando Alonso is pictured driving during practice ahead of the Russian Grand Prix in Sochi.
Caterham finished bottom of the constructors' championship in 2013 and are struggling again this season. The team joined F1 in 2010, but has never won a point.
Caterham rookie Marcus Ericsson was unable to line up on the grid at the U.S. Grand Prix in Austin, Texas last weekend due to his team's financial circumstances. "It's a strange feeling," the Swede told CNN. "I was out racing with these guys a couple of weeks ago in Russia and now I'm here. It's a very difficult situation."
The 11 teams' share of the sport's $1.7 billion revenue is estimated to be $900 million. The existing commercial agreement binds the teams to this revenue split until 2020.
But the costs for an F1 team can be astronomical -- Lotus boss Gerard Lopez estimated the new engine packages for 2014 cost $50-$60 million alone.
"If you look at the budgets of Marussia and compare the highest spender, whoever it is, Ferrari or Red Bull, you are talking about a gap from $70 million to $250 million," Mercedes motorsport director Toto Wolff explained. Not that Mercedes driver Lewis Hamilton is complaining as he pops open the champagne to celebrate another grand prix victory.
Marussia's Max Chilton was another driver sidelined in Austin last weekend.
Marussia has not just been troubled by financial problems this season, with the team left devastated after French driver Jules Bianchi crashed and suffered critical head injuries at the Japanese Grand Prix. Here Chilton stands with his team next to a tribute to Bianchi and Marussia following his accident at Suzuka during the Russian Grand Prix at Sochi in October.
There are also wage disparities in F1. Star drivers like double world champion Fernando Alonso, who has yet to decide who he will drive for next season, commands a fee of $40 million a year.
F1 supremo Bernie Ecclestone has warned if the sport's cash crisis is not resolved as few as 14 cars could race in 2015.
Regardless of its current financial woes, F1 will continue this weekend in Sao Paulo with Mercedes duo Lewis Hamilton and Nico Rosberg battling for the title. The Brazilian Grand Prix is the penultimate race of the 2014 season. The Briton holds a 24-point advantage over his German teammate. But there could be a twist in the tale with double points on offer (50 points for a win) at the season finale in Abu Dhabi on November 23.
Formula One's financial crisis
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
