<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2014 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 09:49:44 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_entertainment" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_entertainment"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Cumberbatch takes on 'Dr. Strange'</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2014/12/04/showbiz/marvel-casting-cumberbatch-reynolds/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~3/60R3bycLX6g/index.html</link>
<description>Cumberbatch fans, rejoice! It's finally official.&lt;img src="//feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~4/60R3bycLX6g" height="1" width="1" alt=""/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2014 08:18:55 EST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141118200311-11-cnn-heroes-red-carpet-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141118200311-11-cnn-heroes-red-carpet-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.cnn.com/2014/12/04/showbiz/marvel-casting-cumberbatch-reynolds/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Cumberbatch takes on 'Dr. Strange,' Reynolds to reprise 'Deadpool'
By Henry Hanks and Todd Leopold, CNN
December 5, 2014 -- Updated 0124 GMT (0924 HKT)
Benedict Cumberbatch has finally been confirmed to play Marvel's Doctor Strange on the big screen, come 2016. Here are some of our other favorite faces from the comic book world:
Ryan Reynolds was the Green Lantern in 2011, but his 2009 role as the motormouth assassin Deadpool in "X-Men Origins: Wolverine" has shown more staying power. "Deadpool" is set for release in 2016.
Krysten Ritter has reportedly landed the role of Marvel's "Jessica Jones" in an upcoming Netflix series.
Oscar winner Jared Leto was recently confirmed to play the Joker in the upcoming film "Suicide Squad," set for release August 5, 2016.
Fan favorite Harley Quinn will be portrayed by Margot Robbie in "Suicide Squad."
Will Smith will play the antihero, gun-toting Deadshot in "Suicide Squad."
Idris Elba let it slip in an interview that he'll appear in "Avengers: Age of Ultron" as his "Thor" character, Heimdall.
The first "Avengers" movie, released in 2012, is the third highest-grossing movie of all time -- and a new one, "Age of Ultron," is due out next summer. The trailer already has people buzzing . Two more will come out in 2018 and 2019.
Robert Downey Jr. brought Tony Stark's Iron Man to life in 2008. There have been two sequels, and Iron Man was a major star in "The Avengers."
Mark Ruffalo got to wear the Hulk's stretchy purple pants in "The Avengers," and he will be in the sequel as well. Eric Bana and Edward Norton played the character in two previous movies: "Hulk" (2003) and "The Incredible Hulk" (2008).
Halle Berry's Storm and Hugh Jackman's Wolverine became fan favorites when "X-Men" hit theaters in 2000. The pair have also appeared in the series' many sequels, including "X-Men: Days of Future Past" this year. (Wolverine has even had two movies of his own.)
The late Christopher Reeve, pictured, wore the red cape in 1978's "Superman" and its three sequels. Brandon Routh took over in 2006's "Superman Returns," and Henry Cavill starred in 2013's "Man of Steel."
Chris Evans, who first donned red, white and blue for 2011's "Captain America: The First Avenger," continued his fight against evil in "The Avengers." He reprised his role this year in "Captain America: The Winter Soldier," and he'll be in the second Avengers.
Following Michael Keaton in 1989 (and 1992), Val Kilmer in 1995 and George Clooney in 1997, Christian Bale drove the Batmobile for all three of the Batman movies directed by Christopher Nolan.
Chris Hemsworth played Thor in the 2011 film of the same name. There was also a sequel in 2013, and Thor, of course, is one of the Avengers.
Ron Perlman went red for Guillermo del Toro's "Hellboy" in 2004 and "Hellboy II: The Golden Army" in 2008.
"Captain America" wasn't Chris Evans' first time battling evil in a form-fitting blue suit. Evans, Ioan Gruffudd, Jessica Alba and Michael Chiklis were the "Fantastic Four" in 2005. They teamed up again in a 2007 sequel.
Mikey Kelley, James Arnold Taylor, Nolan North and Mitchell Whitfield voiced the Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles in 2007's "TMNT." Everyone's favorite pizza-eating reptiles returned this year in a live-action reboot.
HIDE CAPTION
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
