<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2014 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 09:49:44 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_entertainment" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_entertainment"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Lady Gaga's most revealing interview yet</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2014/12/03/showbiz/celebrity-news-gossip/lady-gaga-howard-stern-interview/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~3/b9U9M5t2-24/index.html</link>
<description>When Lady Gaga speaks of young women being abused in the music industry, she speaks from experience.&lt;img src="//feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~4/b9U9M5t2-24" height="1" width="1" alt=""/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2014 12:03:18 EST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141203135646-lady-gaga-march-2014-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141203135646-lady-gaga-march-2014-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.cnn.com/2014/12/03/showbiz/celebrity-news-gossip/lady-gaga-howard-stern-interview/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Lady Gaga's most revealing interview yet
By Breeanna Hare, CNN
December 3, 2014 -- Updated 2213 GMT (0613 HKT)
Lady Gaga gave a performance at the 2014 SXSW festival that included "vomit art," which she later explained at a keynote address was all about promoting the freedom of artistic expression. "Things that are really, really strange and feel really wrong can really change the world," she said. "I'm not saying vomit's going to change the world. ... It's truly just what we wanted to create and do." How does the singer's SXSW appearance hold up against her other spectacular looks?
On November 10, Lady Gaga took one small step for fashion-kind and debuted a "flying dress," essentially a hovercraft-like device, called Volantis.
Some observers might've cried fowl when they spotted Lady Gaga's outfit in Berlin on October 24.
Lady Gaga rocks a mustache at the pre-listening fan event for her album "ARTPOP" in Berlin on October 24.
Lady Gaga arrives at the Ritz Carlton hotel in Berlin on October 23, 2013.
Gaga stays under cover with a mask while in New York on September 7.
On October 24, Lady Gaga went with an all-white look -- sans footwear -- while in Berlin on October 24.
If Mary Poppins were also a mermaid, we imagine she'd look something like Lady Gaga did while in London on August 28.
Lady Gaga rocks an eye-catching outfit as she lands in London on August 27.
Lady Gaga performs at the 2013 MTV Video Music Awards.
Lady Gaga leaves Chateau Marmont.
After suffering a hip injury earlier this year, musician Lady Gaga underwent a process called The Abramovic Method under the instruction of performance artist Marina Abramovic. In a Vimeo video of her experience, Lady Gaga hums, meditates in water, and then walks through woods wearing nothing but a pair of boots.
Lady Gaga speaks at The Rally during NYC Pride 2013 on June 28.
Lady Gaga drapes herself in pink on the catwalk at the Philip Treacy fashion show in 2012.
Lady Gaga performing at the Prudential Center in Newark, New Jersey, in 2012.
Lady Gaga surprised many at the 2011 MTV Video Music Awards as she channeled her foul-mouthed, whisky-drinking, chain-smoking male alter-ago, Jo Calderone.
Lady Gaga performing in Toronto in 2010.
Lady Gaga dons her infamous meat dress at the 2010 MTV Video Music Awards.
Lady Gaga performs on NBC News Today show.
Lady Gaga poses in the press room at the 52nd Annual Grammy Awards in 2010.
Lady Gaga onstage during the 52nd Annual Grammy Awards in 2010.
Lady Gaga performs on stage in 2010 at Palais Omnisports de Paris-Bercy in Paris.
Lady Gaga at Lollapalooza 2010 in Chicago, Illinois.
Lady Gaga performs at The GRAMMY Celebration Concert Tour in 2009.
Musical guest Lady Gaga performs on Saturday Night Live in 2009.
Lady Gaga accepts the award for "Best New Artist" from Eminem during the 2009 MTV Video Music Awards at Radio City Music Hall.
Lady Gaga performs at the 2009 launch of music video website VEVO in New York City.
Lady Gaga at The Dame Ball Tour in Los Angeles, California.
Lady Gaga arrives for the 2009 MTV Video Music Awards.
Lady Gaga performs at the launch of V61 hosted by V Magazine, Marc Jacobs and Belvedere Vodka in 2009 in New York City.
Lady Gaga poses in the press room at the Z100 Jingle Ball concert at Madison Square Garden in New York City in 2008.
Lady Gaga performs at Lollapalooza 2007.
HIDE CAPTION
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
