<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Sports: Sports News, Scores, Analysis, Schedules &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/2010/07/08/AB582vC_page.html?wprss=rss_sports</link>
<description>The Washington Post Sports section provides sports news, video, scores, analysis and updates about high school, college, and pro sports teams, including the Capitals, Nationals, Redskins, United and Wizards. Post Sports also offers blogs and discussions about the latest sports news.</description>
<language>en</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2012 Washington Post Company</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 15:57:11 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 15:57:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>Sports: Sports News, Scores, Analysis, Schedules &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<url>http://media3.washingtonpost.com/wp-srv/hp/image/wp_web.gif</url>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/2010/07/08/AB582vC_page.html?wprss=rss_sports</link>
</image>
<item>
<title>Buying a striker during January transfer window is not always a quick-fix for Premier League teams</title>
<link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636679/s/414dfe5d/sc/13/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cbuying0Ea0Estriker0Eduring0Ejanuary0Etransfer0Ewindow0Eis0Enot0Ealways0Ea0Equick0Efix0Efor0Epremier0Eleague0Eteams0C20A140C120C10A0C5fbbe9a70E682d0E4d250Ea93c0E7c8446bd90A8c0Istory0Bhtml0Dwprss0Frss0Isports/story01.htm</link>
<description>&lt;p/&gt; &lt;p&gt;It’s the time of year when Premier League teams are assessing potential requirements ahead of the January transfer window. Teams with poor defenses will need to improve their back line, clubs struggling to score goals will need to acquire a striker and Arsenal will need to add a defensive midfielder.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/buying-a-striker-during-january-transfer-window-is-not-always-a-quick-fix-for-premier-league-teams/2014/12/10/5fbbe9a7-682d-4d25-a93c-7c8446bd908c_story.html?wprss=rss_sports"&gt;Read full article &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636679/s/414dfe5d/sc/13/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 15:39:36 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.washingtonpost.com/buying-a-striker-during-january-transfer-window-is-not-always-a-quick-fix-for-premier-league-teams/2014/12/10/5fbbe9a7-682d-4d25-a93c-7c8446bd908c_story.html?wprss=rss_sports</guid>
<dc:creator>Jimmy Coverdale</dc:creator>
<ExtractedText>By Jimmy Coverdale December 10 at 10:39 AM
(Photo by Clive Mason/Getty Images)
It’s the time of year when Premier League teams are assessing potential requirements ahead of the January transfer window. Teams with poor defenses will need to improve their back line, clubs struggling to score goals will need to acquire a striker and Arsenal will need to add a defensive midfielder.
I’m going to focus on strikers, because there are many examples of clubs buying forwards during the January transfer window without fixing the problems they had elsewhere, with two primary examples occurring over the last two years. Many claimed that Sunderland needed a striker in January 2013 and Danny Graham was signed for £5 million; zero goals over 13 appearances later, Graham is onto his third loan move away from the club. Last January, it was Hull’s turn: Steve Bruce signed two – Nikica Jelavic and Shane Long — for a combined £13.5 million. While they combined for nine goals over the second half of the season, Hull averaged fewer goals and shots per match after their arrival, from 1.05 goals and 11.6 shots on a per-match basis before the signings to 0.95 goals and 10.9 shots per match after (although Jelavic has scored four times this season and Hull turned an immediate, albeit questionable, profit on Long when he was sold to Southampton).
The January transfer window gives clubs the opportunity to make key improvements that could propel them into the Premier League title/European qualification race or potentially save them from relegation, and there’s likely to be a lot of focus on adding goal scorers. Premier League teams are averaging 1.32 goals per game (down from last season’s 1.38), with 12 clubs below this average and six scoring one goal or less per match (and this is after a strong start in terms of goals ). However, a club’s failure to score is usually attributed to poor striking options. A lack of creativity is often overlooked.
There will, nonetheless, be many claims that clubs need to buy a striker, and some need to do so. However, as the below scatter plot demonstrates, the more creative a side is, the more goals it is likely to score (with non-penalty, direct free kick and own goals removed from the total shown).
There is a big creative gap between Chelsea, Manchester City and Arsenal and the rest of the league. While this treats all shot assists (and, in turn, shots) as equal, the intention is to provide an overview, simply displaying that clubs may not necessarily need a striker like is often claimed.
Unsurprisingly, the four least-creative clubs have the lowest shot assists per 90 minutes (SA/90) averages from the player who leads their club in this metric. Hull’s Ahmed Elmohamady has a team-leading 17 shot assists, averaging 1.13 per 90 – ahead of Burnley’s Scott Arfield (1.10 SA/90), Sunderland’s Sebastian Larsson and Aston Villa’s much-maligned Tom Cleverley (both 1.03 SA/90). Each of these clubs have strikers who could potentially have greater production with better supply, so if money is limited it will likely prove to be better for that club to address the creative issue rather than acquiring a striker, even though none of these clubs has a striker who has scored more than four goals.
Conversely, teams like Tottenham, Liverpool and Queens Park Rangers have created more chances than most but have struggled to score, so signing a striker could prove to be worthwhile. Liverpool and Queens Park Rangers are prime examples of teams with forward issues, although Liverpool should improve once Daniel Sturridge returns, and the latter could acquire someone to play alongside Charlie Austin, who is the Premier League’s No. 4 goal-scorer.
It’s natural for teams to seek upgrades in January, but many clubs cannot afford to buy impact players for multiple positions, and few players provide the scoring and creative threat that could help fix both problems (and those players, such as Luis Suarez and Alexis Sanchez, are usually extremely costly). While each club has different levels of attacking requirements, a new striker may not prove to be the quick fix a club sought. Furthermore, proven goal scorers are often overvalued, so clubs with limited resources should look to add players who could upgrade their creative options, rather than signing a striker who could struggle without additional creativity in the side.
Data provided by Opta unless otherwise noted
Jimmy Coverdale is an analyst and writer at  BSports , focusing on fancy stats in soccer. You can follow him on twitter at  @JimmyCoverdale
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
