<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Sports: Sports News, Scores, Analysis, Schedules &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/2010/07/08/AB582vC_page.html?wprss=rss_sports</link>
<description>The Washington Post Sports section provides sports news, video, scores, analysis and updates about high school, college, and pro sports teams, including the Capitals, Nationals, Redskins, United and Wizards. Post Sports also offers blogs and discussions about the latest sports news.</description>
<language>en</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2012 Washington Post Company</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 15:57:11 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 15:57:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>Sports: Sports News, Scores, Analysis, Schedules &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<url>http://media3.washingtonpost.com/wp-srv/hp/image/wp_web.gif</url>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/2010/07/08/AB582vC_page.html?wprss=rss_sports</link>
</image>
<item>
<title>Chicago Cubs agree to terms with coveted free-agent starter Jon Lester for a reported six years, $155 million</title>
<link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636679/s/4149ccb9/sc/13/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Csports0Cchicago0Ecubs0Eagree0Eto0Eterms0Ewith0Ecoveted0Efree0Eagent0Estarter0Ejon0Elester0Efor0Ea0Ereported0Esix0Eyears0E1550Emillion0C20A140C120C10A0Cb542f9db0E43390E4c530E8cf80E35f35cb8f3f80Istory0Bhtml0Dwprss0Frss0Isports/story01.htm</link>
<description>&lt;p/&gt; &lt;p&gt;SAN DIEGO — The &lt;a data-xslt="_http" href="http://stats.washingtonpost.com/mlb/teamstats.asp?team=16&amp;#38;type=teamhome"&gt;Chicago Cubs&lt;/a&gt; have a long and languid history of losing, one that dates to their last World Series title, now 106 years ago. But on Tuesday night here, in the midst of baseball’s winter meetings that seemed stalled around a single decision, the legacy of curses and fires and fan interference slipped away, at least momentarily.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/chicago-cubs-agree-to-terms-with-coveted-free-agent-starter-jon-lester-for-a-reported-six-years-155-million/2014/12/10/b542f9db-4339-4c53-8cf8-35f35cb8f3f8_story.html?wprss=rss_sports"&gt;Read full article &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636679/s/4149ccb9/sc/13/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;</description>
<category domain="">Chicago Cubs</category>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 07:10:00 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/chicago-cubs-agree-to-terms-with-coveted-free-agent-starter-jon-lester-for-a-reported-six-years-155-million/2014/12/10/b542f9db-4339-4c53-8cf8-35f35cb8f3f8_story.html?wprss=rss_sports</guid>
<dc:creator>Barry Svrluga</dc:creator>
<ExtractedText>By Barry Svrluga December 10 at 2:10 AM Follow @barrysvrluga
The Chicago Cubs beat out offers from the Red Sox and Giants to land free agent starter Jon Lester, who started 11 games for Oakland after being dealt from the Red Sox during the 2014 season. (AP Photo/Ben Margot, file)
SAN DIEGO — The Chicago Cubs have a long and languid history of losing, one that dates to their last World Series title, now 106 years ago. But on Tuesday night here, in the midst of baseball’s winter meetings that seemed stalled around a single decision, the legacy of curses and fires and fan interference slipped away, at least momentarily.
The Cubs made the most franchise-defining move of this offseason, agreeing to terms with prized left-hander Jon Lester, immediately providing them with an ace to go with their heralded group of young position players – not to mention sending marquee franchises from coast to coast scrambling to fill holes in their rotation.
The deal – which Yahoo! Sports reported to be for six years and $155 million – beat out offers from the Boston Red Sox, with whom Lester won two World Series, and the San Francisco Giants, who have won three championships since 2010. It shapes the Cubs for 2015, because Lester will front a rotation that needed help after posting a 4.11 ERA last season, third worst in the National League.
But it also shapes them for the future, because Lester’s reputation and results are best in October, a month in which the Cubs don’t know success. As a rookie in 2007, he started the clinching game of Boston’s sweep of Colorado in the World Series – and then got better in future postseasons. In 14 playoff appearances, he has a 2.57 ERA. In the World Series, he has given up one run in 21 innings.
“This is a guy, when the game is really big, he was always at his best,” said new Cubs Manager Joe Maddon, who competed against Lester for years when he managed the Tampa Bay Rays.
Suddenly, it doesn’t seem ludicrous for Cubs fans to imagine Lester, who turns 31 next month, making one of those October starts wearing their blue hat. Last summer, they traded away their in-house ace, right-hander Jeff Samardzija, because they were headed to another last-place finish and they needed to further enhance their deep core of prospects – which they did with ballyhooed young shortstop Addison Russell.
But the acquisition of Lester indicates that Cubs management – led by former Boston executives Theo Epstein and Jed Hoyer – believes the club will compete for championships within the next two seasons because they have addressed their most glaring need.
“The thing that stands out to me are young players that swing the bat well,” Maddon said. “There’s athleticism, speed. Defense overall [is] pretty good. On the other side, you’re looking to augment the pitching.”
Now, the Cubs have done that. The $155-million total value matches the Yankees’ deal with Japanese star Masahiro Tanaka struck last year, tying for the fifth-highest ever granted a pitcher. But Tanaka’s contract is for seven years. Lester’s average annual pay of $25.8 million trails only Dodgers lefty Clayton Kershaw’s $30.15 million among pitchers.
Such deals are well-documented as fraught with peril. Lester became the 15th pitcher to agree to a deal worth at least $100 million, and there are far more flame-outs than championships among the predecessors. Only three pitchers with nine-figure deals have won World Series during the span of the contract – CC Sabathia with the New York Yankees in 2009, Barry Zito with the Giants in 2010 (when he was left off the playoff roster) and 2012, and Matt Cain with the Giants in 2012 and 2014 (when he was injured and didn’t pitch).
Yet since 2008, Lester has combined reliability with effectiveness, a rare combination among starting pitchers, which made him so marketable, so attractive. Never has he made fewer than 31 starts in a season. Only once has he failed to throw at least 200 innings. Only once, in the offensively dominant American League East, has he posted an ERA north of 3.75.
Over that seven-season span, among AL pitchers, only Felix Hernandez, Justin Verlander and James Shields have thrown more innings or made more starts, only Hernandez, David Price, Jered Weaver and Verlander have a lower ERA.
With Detroit’s Max Scherzer, the other premier pitcher on the free agent market, preferring to take his time in fielding offers and signing a deal, Lester became the one player holding the entire winter meetings hostage. Executives and scouts from the Cubs, Red Sox and Giants said throughout Tuesday they didn’t know where they stood. Other free agent pitchers – Kansas City’s James Shields, Brandon McCarthy of the Yankees, and on and on – couldn’t be matched up with potential suitors until some of those suitors were eliminated.
Then early Tuesday evening, San Francisco assistant general manager Bobby Evans told reporters that Lester had called the Giants, thanked them for their time and attention, and moved on. “We did not receive a rose,” Evans said.
Though the Los Angeles Dodgers had also been rumored to be in the chase, there was speculation that the team that already has the highest payroll in the game was merely driving up the price for the division rival Giants. So it appeared to come down to the Cubs and the Red Sox, who had soured their relationship with Lester when they offered him a deal well below market value in spring training – and then dealt him at the trade deadline.
Boston spent time trying to mend those fences over the past month, and  WEEI.com  reported that Red Sox owner John Henry was among a contingent that flew to meet Lester in person over the weekend. The ties to the franchise – from Manager John Farrell, who was once Lester’s pitching coach, to the city itself – were still deep. He made his debut with Boston, was diagnosed with lymphoma while with the Red Sox, overcame it, and grew from a prospect to a star.
“I think anytime you have a rapport or relationship with a guy that you’ve worked with, you’d love to see them evolve as a person and as a pitcher, in Jon’s case, in how they mature and how they get to this point in time to take care of their family from a financial standpoint, and certainly he has done that,” Farrell said. “Two World Series championships and a lot of positive things that have taken place.”
The next positive things will come in Chicago with the Cubs. Win a World Series there, and there’s no telling what your legacy might be. But that’s getting ahead of the game. For now, Lester’s decision changed only the franchise’s outlook going forward – and allowed the rest of the sport to move on to the remainder of an offseason that still promises a slew of intriguing decisions.
Barry Svrluga is the national baseball writer for The Washington Post.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
