<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Sports: Sports News, Scores, Analysis, Schedules &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/2010/07/08/AB582vC_page.html?wprss=rss_sports</link>
<description>The Washington Post Sports section provides sports news, video, scores, analysis and updates about high school, college, and pro sports teams, including the Capitals, Nationals, Redskins, United and Wizards. Post Sports also offers blogs and discussions about the latest sports news.</description>
<language>en</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2012 Washington Post Company</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 15:57:11 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 15:57:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>Sports: Sports News, Scores, Analysis, Schedules &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<url>http://media3.washingtonpost.com/wp-srv/hp/image/wp_web.gif</url>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/2010/07/08/AB582vC_page.html?wprss=rss_sports</link>
</image>
<item>
<title>Michigan loses to Eastern Michigan. Scowling Wolverines fan does not approve.</title>
<link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636679/s/414c7782/sc/13/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Csports0Cmichigan0Eloses0Eto0Eeastern0Emichigan0Escowling0Ewolverines0Efan0Edoes0Enot0Eapprove0C20A140C120C10A0C41bdbb640E227a0E45620Eb36e0E5aa2f0Ab8f0A7b0Istory0Bhtml0Dwprss0Frss0Isports/story01.htm</link>
<description>&lt;p/&gt; &lt;p&gt;Michigan was expected to right its ship against Eastern Michigan on Tuesday night, four days after&lt;a data-xslt="_http" href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/early-lead/wp/2014/12/09/big-ten-fans-are-ordering-njit-t-shirts-to-troll-michigan/"&gt; its baffling loss to the New Jersey Institute of Technology&lt;/a&gt;, a team that can’t even qualify for the NCAA tournament this year because it currently doesn’t have a conference.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/michigan-loses-to-eastern-michigan-scowling-wolverines-fan-does-not-approve/2014/12/10/41bdbb64-227a-4562-b36e-5aa2f0b8f07b_story.html?wprss=rss_sports"&gt;Read full article &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636679/s/414c7782/sc/13/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 12:45:17 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/michigan-loses-to-eastern-michigan-scowling-wolverines-fan-does-not-approve/2014/12/10/41bdbb64-227a-4562-b36e-5aa2f0b8f07b_story.html?wprss=rss_sports</guid>
<dc:creator>Matt Bonesteel</dc:creator>
<ExtractedText>By Matt Bonesteel December 10 at 7:45 AM Follow @MattBonesteel
(AP Photo/Tony Ding)
Michigan was expected to right its ship against Eastern Michigan on Tuesday night, four days after its baffling loss to the New Jersey Institute of Technology , a team that can’t even qualify for the NCAA tournament this year because it currently doesn’t have a conference.
The Wolverines entered the game 26-2 all-time against the Eagles, whose campus is only six miles down the road from Ann Arbor. And Michigan, which fell out of the national rankings after the NJIT loss, had gone 59 straight games without losing back-to-back games, the longest streak in the Big Ten.
And then Eastern Michigan zoned out its massive neighbor, holding the Wolverines to a season-low 32.6 percent shooting in a 45-42 win . And then one stunned Michigan student did a little zoning out of her own.
The student, Bryn Adams, seemed so happy earlier in the game!
— Bryn Adams (@bryn_adams) December 10, 2014
But now her blankly disgusted scowl has made her one of the young college basketball season’s newest celebrities. She’s fine with it, even if her team is letting her down on a nightly basis now.
I guess I'm famous now for zoning out so that's pretty cool
— Bryn Adams (@bryn_adams) December 10, 2014
After spending the first 17 years of his Post career writing and editing, Matt and the printed paper had an amicable divorce in 2014. He's now blogging and editing for the Early Lead and the Post's other Web-based products.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
