<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Sports: Sports News, Scores, Analysis, Schedules &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/2010/07/08/AB582vC_page.html?wprss=rss_sports</link>
<description>The Washington Post Sports section provides sports news, video, scores, analysis and updates about high school, college, and pro sports teams, including the Capitals, Nationals, Redskins, United and Wizards. Post Sports also offers blogs and discussions about the latest sports news.</description>
<language>en</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2012 Washington Post Company</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 17:01:11 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 17:01:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>Sports: Sports News, Scores, Analysis, Schedules &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<url>http://media3.washingtonpost.com/wp-srv/hp/image/wp_web.gif</url>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/2010/07/08/AB582vC_page.html?wprss=rss_sports</link>
</image>
<item>
<title>Jerry Jones wants to see NFL playoffs expanded by two teams. says it’s only a matter of ‘when’</title>
<link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636679/s/414ef8c6/sc/13/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Csports0Cjerry0Ejones0Ewants0Eto0Esee0Enfl0Eplayoffs0Eexpanded0Eby0Etwo0Eteams0Esays0Eits0Eonly0Ea0Ematter0Eof0Ewhen0C20A140C120C10A0C21fb638b0E0Ab880E430A10E8e580Ef419ad5cfba60Istory0Bhtml0Dwprss0Frss0Isports/story01.htm</link>
<description>&lt;p/&gt; &lt;p&gt;When it comes to the NFL playoffs, just about everyone wants a little bit more. Not too much, but just a bit.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;That includes NFL owners, especially Jerry Jones of the Dallas Cowboys. For one thing, another game would mean more money for Jones and the owners. For another thing, his Cowboys seem to juuuusssst miss the playoffs every year — and could do so again this year.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/jerry-jones-wants-to-see-nfl-playoffs-expanded-by-two-teams-says-its-only-a-matter-of-when/2014/12/10/21fb638b-0b88-4301-8e58-f419ad5cfba6_story.html?wprss=rss_sports"&gt;Read full article &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636679/s/414ef8c6/sc/13/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 16:58:11 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/jerry-jones-wants-to-see-nfl-playoffs-expanded-by-two-teams-says-its-only-a-matter-of-when/2014/12/10/21fb638b-0b88-4301-8e58-f419ad5cfba6_story.html?wprss=rss_sports</guid>
<dc:creator>Cindy Boren</dc:creator>
<ExtractedText>By Cindy Boren December 10 at 11:58 AM Follow @cindyboren
Who doesn’t want a little more playoff football? (Brandon Wade / AP)
When it comes to the NFL playoffs, just about everyone wants a little bit more. Not too much, but just a bit.
That includes NFL owners, especially Jerry Jones of the Dallas Cowboys. For one thing, another game would mean more money for Jones and the owners. For another thing, his Cowboys seem to juuuusssst miss the playoffs every year — and could do so again this year.
“Let me start off by saying I’m for two more playoff teams right now,” Jones said Tuesday morning on 105.3 FM The Fan . “I think we’ve got the number of people in the league that are for that, and it’s just a matter of when in my mind.”
A change from the 12-team format to 14 teams could come as soon as next season.
“I don’t want to discredit any team’s ability to mount an objection or any team’s ability to vote against it, but I think as it sits right now, it enjoys the favor of the staff,” he said. “I’ve seen the league office promote it, and I’ve certainly seen the teams are for it. I think it could come immediately.”
Expansion isn’t a new idea, but the current state of affairs doesn’t hurt. The NFC South will send a team with a team with a .500 or worse record to the playoffs — and it will host a playoff game. Meanwhile, a team with a winning record in a tougher division must hope to get a wild card. Jones doesn’t think the state of affairs merits taking a home game away from a division winner.
“This is an aberration — this is rare,” Jones said. “Because it’s such a rare thing — it does need to be structured so that if you win your division, you’ve done something.”
After spending most of her career in traditional print sports journalism, Cindy began blogging and tweeting, first as NFL/Redskins editor, and, since August 2010, at The Early Lead. She also is the social media editor for Sports.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
