<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Sports: Sports News, Scores, Analysis, Schedules &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/2010/07/08/AB582vC_page.html?wprss=rss_sports</link>
<description>The Washington Post Sports section provides sports news, video, scores, analysis and updates about high school, college, and pro sports teams, including the Capitals, Nationals, Redskins, United and Wizards. Post Sports also offers blogs and discussions about the latest sports news.</description>
<language>en</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2012 Washington Post Company</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 15:57:11 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 15:57:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>Sports: Sports News, Scores, Analysis, Schedules &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<url>http://media3.washingtonpost.com/wp-srv/hp/image/wp_web.gif</url>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/2010/07/08/AB582vC_page.html?wprss=rss_sports</link>
</image>
<item>
<title>After being jilted by free agent and former Boston starter Jon Lester, the Red Sox regroup</title>
<link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636679/s/4149e42a/sc/13/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Csports0Cafter0Ebeing0Ejilted0Eby0Efree0Eagent0Eand0Eformer0Eboston0Estarter0Ejon0Elester0Ethe0Ered0Esox0Eregroup0C20A140C120C10A0C66dff4440E437d0E4d40A0E98470E6cf6c1ad2d1d0Istory0Bhtml0Dwprss0Frss0Isports/story01.htm</link>
<description>&lt;p/&gt; &lt;p&gt;SAN DIEGO — Jon Lester signed with the Boston Red Sox on Aug. 13, 2002, as an 18-year-old who had graduated a couple months earlier from Bellarmine High in Tacoma, Wash. He would remain a Red Sox, only a Red Sox, until the middle of this past season. He became a husband, a father and a man in Boston. He won two World Series. He beat cancer.  He earned more wins  — 110 — wearing a Red Sox uniform than all but eight men in the franchise’s 114-year history.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/after-being-jilted-by-free-agent-and-former-boston-starter-jon-lester-the-red-sox-regroup/2014/12/10/66dff444-437d-4d40-9847-6cf6c1ad2d1d_story.html?wprss=rss_sports"&gt;Read full article &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636679/s/4149e42a/sc/13/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;</description>
<category domain="">Boston Red Sox</category>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 07:57:18 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/after-being-jilted-by-free-agent-and-former-boston-starter-jon-lester-the-red-sox-regroup/2014/12/10/66dff444-437d-4d40-9847-6cf6c1ad2d1d_story.html?wprss=rss_sports</guid>
<dc:creator>Dan Hargett</dc:creator>
<ExtractedText>By Adam Kilgore December 10 at 2:57 AM Follow @adamkilgorewp
Jon Lester spent the first eight-plus seasons of his major league career with the Boston Red Sox, winning World Series titles in 2007 and 2013. Boston dealt Lester to the Oakland A’s at the trade deadline last summer. (Photo by Jared Wickerham/Getty Images)
SAN DIEGO — Jon Lester signed with the Boston Red Sox on Aug. 13, 2002, as an 18-year-old who had graduated a couple months earlier from Bellarmine High in Tacoma, Wash. He would remain a Red Sox, only a Red Sox, until the middle of this past season. He became a husband, a father and a man in Boston. He won two World Series. He beat cancer.  He earned more wins  – 110 – wearing a Red Sox uniform than all but eight men in the franchise’s 114-year history.
And now the Red Sox, after Lester gave them more than they could have imagined, feel the anguish of Lester slipping through their fingers. He is not a Boston Red Sox anymore. He is a Chicago Cub after accepting their six-year, $155 million offer, ending a free agent saga that pulled at Lester’s emotions and kept three cities on edge until Tuesday night. The Cubs could celebrate. The Giants, buoyed by three World Series in five years, could shrug and move on. The Red Sox could only lament their failed, awkward pursuit and plan to replace the massive hole at the top of their rotation.
The lamentation will spread first throughout Boston, a city that regards its baseball team with sacred reverence. In spring training, the Red Sox offered Lester a lowball, $70 million contract. Discussions never picked up once the season began. The Red Sox, fresh off the 2013 World Series, spiraled to the bottom of the American League East. At the deadline, with no hope to contend and no chance to sign Lester, they shipped him to the Oakland A’s.
They still held out hope that it would be a temporary parting, not a final goodbye. Lester loved Boston, felt the pull of everything that had happened to him and everything he had done there. The Red Sox loved him back, but with a caveat. Owner John Henry had publicly stated his aversion to long, pricey contracts for pitchers over 30. He would bend for Lester. Ultimately, he would not break. The only offers the Red Sox made were ones Lester had no choice but to turn down. There are hometown discounts and there are insults, and the Red Sox positioned themselves on the wrong side.
And so he is a Cub, and the Red Sox face a mandate to replace him. They signaled their intention to vault back into contention with the Pablo Sandoval-Hanley Ramirez splash. They do not rebuild in Boston.
Lester’s decision became the first domino to fall in a row that could stretch down the vast lobby of the Manchester Grand Hyatt. Lester had created a blockade in the free agent and trade market for pitchers, and as he heads for Chicago, other deals could soon follow. The teams that missed out on Lester will move on to other plans. The teams who had hoped to acquire those clubs’ Plan Bs will need to move on to their own Plan Bs. The pond has started to ripple.
The loudest reverberations will come from the Red Sox. The options are plentiful, in both the free agent and trade market. Red Sox General Manager Ben Cherington told Boston reporters Monday evening that the Red Sox would work through “15 to 20 starting pitching scenarios” if they missed out on Lester. The wide net reflects the glut of pitchers who remain free agents and the cadre of starters eligible to become free agents after 2016, and therefore logical subjects of trade talks.
Have money to burn? James Shields and Max Scherzer are ready to listen, and behind them sit Ervin Santana, Brandon McCarthy, Justin Masterson, Jake Peavy and a host of others. Willing to unload prospects? David Price, Jordan Zimmermann, Doug Fister, Yovani Gallardo, Mat Latos, Ian Kennedy, Rick Porcello and Johnny Cueto all have one year remaining before free agency.
The Red Sox, as Cherington indicated, may have the most wide-ranging search. Though they have zero desire to move second base/outfield prospect Mookie Betts, they own a phalanx of top prospects on the cusp of the majors, including left-handed starter Henry Owens and catcher Blake Swihart. They’re also willing to exceed the luxury tax in 2015, which may make it palatable to take on a large one-year salary – like the $16.5 million owed to Zimmermann. Their ability to spend also makes them players for Shields, but not Scherzer. Henry may have broken his opposition to contracts longer than five years for Lester. But for an outsider? Unlikely.
Boston’s top target may be a pitcher from outside the group of free agents from this year and next year. Cole Hamels, who has four years and $96 million left on his contract, cannot replace what Lester meant to the franchise. But he can replace Lester’s production on the mound, and the Red Sox are enticed. One Phillies source said the team is “open to anything” as they start an overdue rebuild. Hamels has limited no-trade protection, but indications are he would prefer to leave Philadelphia as they drift further from contention and deeper into overhauling.
The Giants could attempt to lure Jake Peavy back into the rotation after he helped win a World Series and had a rousing effect inside their clubhouse. Their pursuit of Lester suggests that they’re willing to redistribute the money intended for Sandoval toward their rotation. Is the extra revenue generated by winning three world titles in five years enough to give them the flexibility to chase Scherzer? They probably don’t have the pieces to trade for a starter who could make a similar impact.
With Lester in place, the responses and backup plans could unfold fast. Will a flurry of deals and signings follow in the starting pitching market? Who knows? But when David Robertson signed with the White Sox on Monday night, Nationals General Manager Mike Rizzo’s phone buzzed with interest in his relievers.
“When certain dominoes do fall, it does change the landscape of it,” Rizzo said.
The landscape of baseball’s offseason changed when Lester reached his final decision. It changed in Chicago, where the Cubs accelerated their own rebuild with a brainy manager and an October hero. It changed more in Boston, where, in some ways, he will always be a Red Sox.
With the 56th pick of the 2002 Major League Baseball draft, the Chicago Cubs drafted a 6-foot-4 first baseman from Dunedin, Fla., named Brian Dopirak.  He would play six seasons in their minor league system, hitting 89 home runs and reaching Class AA. Dopirak would play four more seasons, never cracking the big leagues, before he washed out of baseball in 2011. With the 57th pick, the Boston Red Sox chose Jon Lester.
The Cubs may have looked back upon their choice with anguish in the 10 years since, as Lester became one of the most dominating left-handed pitchers in the sport, a flint-eyed ace who wore cowboy boots and snap-button shirts and never missed a start. The Cubs got nothing. The Red Sox got a franchise pillar.
Tuesday night, they bid farewell. Lester will always have the 10 years in which he helped the Red Sox cultivate a new identity and ascend to the top of the sport. But the Red Sox, now in search of something new, no longer have him.​
Adam Kilgore covers national sports for the Washington Post. Previously he served as the Post's Washington Nationals beat writer from 2010 to 2014.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
