<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Sports: Sports News, Scores, Analysis, Schedules &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/2010/07/08/AB582vC_page.html?wprss=rss_sports</link>
<description>The Washington Post Sports section provides sports news, video, scores, analysis and updates about high school, college, and pro sports teams, including the Capitals, Nationals, Redskins, United and Wizards. Post Sports also offers blogs and discussions about the latest sports news.</description>
<language>en</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2012 Washington Post Company</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 15:57:11 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 15:57:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>Sports: Sports News, Scores, Analysis, Schedules &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<url>http://media3.washingtonpost.com/wp-srv/hp/image/wp_web.gif</url>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/2010/07/08/AB582vC_page.html?wprss=rss_sports</link>
</image>
<item>
<title>After Jon Lester signing, Jeff Samardzija trade, Cubs and White Sox bringing back optimism to Chicago</title>
<link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636679/s/414d6623/sc/13/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Csports0Cafter0Ejon0Elester0Esigning0Ejeff0Esamardzija0Etrade0Ecubs0Eand0Ewhite0Esox0Ebringing0Eback0Eoptimism0Eto0Echicago0C20A140C120C10A0Cf170Ad720A0E5afd0E40Ac10E9c4c0Ec212cceff730A0Istory0Bhtml0Dwprss0Frss0Isports/story01.htm</link>
<description>&lt;p/&gt; &lt;p&gt;SAN DIEGO — For five years straight, the Chicago Cubs have played the role of — and even embraced being — the Chicago Cubs. Lovable? Maybe. If you love losing. Since 2010, they have finished fifth in the National League Central each season. No NL team has lost more games over that period.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/after-jon-lester-signing-jeff-samardzija-trade-cubs-and-white-sox-bringing-back-optimism-to-chicago/2014/12/10/f170d720-5afd-40c1-9c4c-c212cceff730_story.html?wprss=rss_sports"&gt;Read full article &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636679/s/414d6623/sc/13/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;</description>
<category domain="">Jeff Samardzija</category>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 14:30:39 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/after-jon-lester-signing-jeff-samardzija-trade-cubs-and-white-sox-bringing-back-optimism-to-chicago/2014/12/10/f170d720-5afd-40c1-9c4c-c212cceff730_story.html?wprss=rss_sports</guid>
<dc:creator>Barry Svrluga</dc:creator>
<ExtractedText>By Barry Svrluga December 10 at 9:30 AM Follow @barrysvrluga
Chicago Cubs Manager Joe Maddon aims to lead his new franchise back to the postseason.
SAN DIEGO – For five years straight, the Chicago Cubs have played the role of — and even embraced being — the Chicago Cubs. Lovable? Maybe. If you love losing. Since 2010, they have finished fifth in the National League Central each season. No NL team has lost more games over that period.
And then the Cubs heard the decision that had all of baseball hand-cuffed: left-hander Jon Lester would sign with them for the gaudy sum of $155 million over six years . And what was this wafting in on the cold breezes through the Windy City but optimism.
“The fact that the World Series has not been there for a long time,” new Manager Joe Maddon said, “I think that’s intriguing.”
Drive 10 miles down Lakeshore Drive, and the second team in the second city is as intriguing as any team here at baseball’s annual winter meetings, sending ripples through the Manchester Grand Hyatt — not to mention the American League Central — by trading for right-hander Jeff Samardzija, by signing free agent closer David Robertson, by their earlier free agent deals for lefty reliever Zach Duke and first baseman Adam LaRoche. It’s to the point where White Sox General Manager Rick Hahn can mention the word “championship” and talk about contending — even coming off two seasons that yielded 188 losses – and not sound crazy.
“I do believe you are not going to have a break when you come through Chicago and face that rotation,” Hahn said, wedging Samardzija between lefties Chris Sale and Jose Quintana.
It is December, when it’s easy to gather round the fire and grow warm feelings about a baseball season that is nearly four months off. But it’s not terribly difficult to imagine Wrigley Field absolutely jumping over the second weekend of July when the White Sox drive across town and play the Cubs, meaningful games in the standings and in the city.
What might that be like?
Jon Lester picked the Cubs Tuesday. (Jeff Chiu/AP Photo)
“It’s a great baseball town, one of the best in the country,” said Nationals General Manager Mike Rizzo, who grew up in Chicago as a Cubs fan, had his first scouting job for the White Sox, and still has a Bears helmet on a table in his office at Nationals Park. “There’s two different fan bases in Chicago, and any Chicagoan that says they like both teams is not a true Chicagoan, so you’re drawing the lines and you’re making a decision of who you’re rooting for. To have both of those teams good and competitive at the same time would be great.”
To be sure, these are two franchises in development, but those developments have helped shape the offseason. Since late 2011, when Theo Epstein moved from his job running the baseball operations with the Boston Red Sox to a job overseeing the same — and more — for the Cubs, there has been a classic slow-build on the North Side. Scouting and player development. Veterans out the door and prospects in. Losses on the field and at the gate, where one of baseball’s most resilient and reliable fan bases stopped coming, from 3.3 million fans in 2008 to 2.65 million in 2014.
Now, though, the Cubs have more prospects than they can possibly play. In an environment in which offense is at a premium, Kris Bryant might be the most promising hitter in the game, coming off a season in which he hit 43 homers and delivered a 1.098 on-base-plus-slugging percentage in time split between Classes AA and AAA. Dealing Samardzija — an Indiana product and former Notre Dame wide receiver who considers Chicago his home city — last summer to Oakland yielded shortstop Addison Russell, which gives them flexibility behind starter Starlin Castro, a three-time all-star who’s still just 24. First baseman Anthony Rizzo hit 32 bombs in just 140 major league games last year and is just 25. And there’s more on the way.
And to that mix, the Cubs bring a unique leader in Maddon, who left Tampa Bay following the season and was so attractive as a free agent that the Cubs fired their sitting manager, Rick Renteria, to make room. By now, Maddon has studied his roster and his system, and the strengths are obvious.
“Youth and athleticism,” Maddon said Tuesday. “Unique hitting abilities for young players. … I think the thing that jumps out the most is youth here, youth on the way, more offensive than the average young group of players that I’ve seen over the last couple of years.”
The White Sox don’t have that same young core, but they do have Sale, one of the American League’s best pitchers, and now Samardzija, whose 16-start entrée into the AL with Oakland last summer yielded a 3.14 ERA and a .224 opponents’ batting average. It’s why the White Sox, suddenly so aggressive, parted with four players for him rather than just signing a free agent.
“This was the guy we wanted,” Hahn said. “This was the guy who fit for us. This was the guy we felt was a perfect complement to [Sale and Quintana]. … It might be a little bit of a gamble, but we’re optimistic we [will be] able to extend his stay as well.”
That stay could be in a division that can be had. Detroit, for the first time in years, appears to have more questions than answers, with all the innings wearing on Justin Verlander, all the at-bats wearing on Miguel Cabrera, a bullpen still in shambles and Max Scherzer maybe walking out the door. Kansas City won the pennant but still boasts an offense that was last in baseball in homers and can’t afford to re-sign workhorse right-hander James Shields. Yes, Cleveland is modestly improved after adding first baseman-outfielder Brandon Moss in a trade with Oakland, but the rotation still needs Danny Salazar and Trevor Bauer to develop behind Cy Young winner Corey Kluber, and Minnesota is still at least a year away.
So maybe the time is coming in Chicago. In 1906, the White Sox beat the Cubs in the World Series. Since then, they have appeared in the postseason in the same year just once — 2008, when the Cubs were swept out of the division series and the White Sox lasted just four games. Rarely, in that time, have the two teams created a simultaneous murmur that filtered through the game.
Last month, Maddon was in New York on a short holiday, and he walked through Times Square. From the sidewalk, he heard people banging on the windows of a restaurant, trying to get his attention. Cubs fans, pointing to Cubs gear, ecstatic and excited about what might be to come. What an unusual position for Chicago to find itself.
“I’m eager to see how all this plays out,” Maddon said. “I’ve never been in this kind of market before, but I think it’s a great exercise, and I’m really looking forward to it.”
More from the Winter Meetings
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
