<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Sports: Sports News, Scores, Analysis, Schedules &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/2010/07/08/AB582vC_page.html?wprss=rss_sports</link>
<description>The Washington Post Sports section provides sports news, video, scores, analysis and updates about high school, college, and pro sports teams, including the Capitals, Nationals, Redskins, United and Wizards. Post Sports also offers blogs and discussions about the latest sports news.</description>
<language>en</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2012 Washington Post Company</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 16:03:12 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 16:03:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>Sports: Sports News, Scores, Analysis, Schedules &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<url>http://media3.washingtonpost.com/wp-srv/hp/image/wp_web.gif</url>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/2010/07/08/AB582vC_page.html?wprss=rss_sports</link>
</image>
<item>
<title>Top performances of the year: Single-game passing</title>
<link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636679/s/414e277f/sc/13/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Csports0Chighschools0Ctop0Eperformances0Eof0Ethe0Eyear0Esingle0Egame0Epassing0C20A140C120C10A0Cc63efdfd0E45c80E4c5d0Eae9c0E7d6ac20A3c2360Istory0Bhtml0Dwprss0Frss0Isports/story01.htm</link>
<description>&lt;p/&gt; &lt;p&gt;With the Virginia state championship games looming as the end-all, be-all Saturday, we’re taking a look back at some of the most stellar individual performances of the 2014 high school football season this week. Yesterday, we looked at the &lt;a data-xslt="_http" href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/recruiting-insider/wp/2014/12/09/top-individual-performances-of-the-year-single-game-rushing/"&gt;top single-game rushing showings&lt;/a&gt; of the year. Today, we’ll look at passing. Tomorrow, receiving.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/highschools/top-performances-of-the-year-single-game-passing/2014/12/10/c63efdfd-45c8-4c5d-ae9c-7d6ac203c236_story.html?wprss=rss_sports"&gt;Read full article &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636679/s/414e277f/sc/13/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;</description>
<category domain="">Eastern</category>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 16:02:58 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/highschools/top-performances-of-the-year-single-game-passing/2014/12/10/c63efdfd-45c8-4c5d-ae9c-7d6ac203c236_story.html?wprss=rss_sports</guid>
<dc:creator>Chelsea Janes</dc:creator>
<ExtractedText>By Chelsea Janes December 10 at 11:02 AM Follow @chelsea_janes
Brandon Battle’s 416-yard explosion against Westlake was one of the top passing performances in the area this season. (Doug Kapustin/For The Washington Post)
With the Virginia state championship games looming as the end-all, be-all Saturday, we’re taking a look back at some of the most stellar individual performances of the 2014 high school football season this week. Yesterday, we looked at the top single-game rushing showings of the year. Today, we’ll look at passing. Tomorrow, receiving.
SINGLE-GAME PASSING
1. Chuck Reese, Rockville: 483, 472, 465 yards
According to stats submitted to AllMetSports, the top three passing performances of the season by yardage all belonged to Rockville’s Chuck Reese . That’s no surprise: the Rams utilize a high-flying, perpetually passing offense that set Reese up to finish with more than 3,200 passing yards this season. Still, Reese had to complete the passes, find his receivers, and pick apart defenses that knew exactly what was coming. He did so, for the three most prolific passing performances of the season, including a 483-yard explosion against Wootton which came a week after a 472-yard showing against Magruder.
2. Jerome Johnson, Eastern, 464 and 433 yards
Reese holds the top three passing showings of the season, and Eastern’s Jerome Johnson holds the fourth and fifth biggest passing games. The mobile sophomore grew up in Eastern’s pass-heavy offense — the DCSAA Class A champions threw about 75 percent of the time — and should be a force to watch in years to come. Tellingly, given he’s often the youngest player on the field, Johnson showed big-game prowess: his most massive passing performance came against eventual DCIAA Stripes champion Bell, and his 433-yard showing came in the Class A title game against Sidwell Friends . He threw for six touchdowns in both of those games.
3. Jason Clingman, Northwood, 428 yards
Northwood  experienced a tough season, playing to a 2-8 record and struggling against the best teams in Montgomery 3A/2A/1A. But one bright spot was quarterback  Jason Clingman’s  game against Walter Johnson. Though Northwood lost the game, Clingman completed 26 of 42 passes for 428 yards — the best single-game showing for a Montgomery County quarterback not named Chuck Reese this season.
4. Brandon Battle, North Point, 416 yards
North Point was one of Southern Maryland’s most imposing teams this season, playing its way into the 4A East semifinal before falling to a solid passing attack from Arundel. At the center of the Eagles’ offense was quarterback Brandon Battle , who compiled nearly 2,500 yards in the air. His best game came in the regular-season finale against Westlake, a 416-yard passing performance in which he completed 20 of 35 passes for five touchdowns.
5. Brian Maffei, McLean, 415 yards
McLean fell to Langley in a win-and-get-in season finale this year, a loss that ended a strong season from senior quarterback Brian Maffei . In a performance as impressive because his arm didn’t fall off as it was because of the numbers it yielded, Maffei completed 42 of 71 passes in a mid-season loss to Herndon, tossing for 415 yards and four touchdowns in that game. His 42 completions set a state record.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
