<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Sports: Sports News, Scores, Analysis, Schedules &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/2010/07/08/AB582vC_page.html?wprss=rss_sports</link>
<description>The Washington Post Sports section provides sports news, video, scores, analysis and updates about high school, college, and pro sports teams, including the Capitals, Nationals, Redskins, United and Wizards. Post Sports also offers blogs and discussions about the latest sports news.</description>
<language>en</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2012 Washington Post Company</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 15:57:11 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 15:57:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>Sports: Sports News, Scores, Analysis, Schedules &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<url>http://media3.washingtonpost.com/wp-srv/hp/image/wp_web.gif</url>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/2010/07/08/AB582vC_page.html?wprss=rss_sports</link>
</image>
<item>
<title>Caps Insider: In Tampa, Troy Brouwer ended 5-on-5 drought with key goal</title>
<link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636679/s/414d4b8e/sc/13/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Csports0Cin0Etampa0Etroy0Ebrouwer0Eended0E50Eon0E50Edrought0Ewith0Ekey0Egoal0C20A140C120C10A0C430Afaaf40E34c70E4db70Eb9c0A0Efcb8351f73680Istory0Bhtml0Dwprss0Frss0Isports/story01.htm</link>
<description>&lt;p/&gt; &lt;p&gt;TAMPA — As the veteran on a line with youngsters, Washington Capitals forward Troy Brouwer understood his role, and &lt;a data-xslt="_http" href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/capitals-insider/wp/2014/12/09/the-older-guy-on-his-line-troy-brouwer-seeks-more-personal-consistency/"&gt;lately he felt he had set a poor example&lt;/a&gt;. He wanted opponents to fear him, left winger Marcus Johansson and whichever rookie center skated between them. Maybe now, after Brouwer freed his stick just long enough to elevate the puck into the top shelf for &lt;a data-xslt="_http" href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/capitals/alex-ovechkin-troy-brouwer-lead-capitals-past-lightning-for-third-straight-win/2014/12/09/74723256-7fee-11e4-8882-03cf08410beb_story.html"&gt;a key goal in a 5-3 win over powerful Tampa Bay,&lt;/a&gt; someone finally would.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/in-tampa-troy-brouwer-ended-5-on-5-drought-with-key-goal/2014/12/10/430faaf4-34c7-4db7-b9c0-fcb8351f7368_story.html?wprss=rss_sports"&gt;Read full article &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636679/s/414d4b8e/sc/13/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;</description>
<category domain="">Troy Brouwer</category>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 13:41:07 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/in-tampa-troy-brouwer-ended-5-on-5-drought-with-key-goal/2014/12/10/430faaf4-34c7-4db7-b9c0-fcb8351f7368_story.html?wprss=rss_sports</guid>
<dc:creator>Alex Prewitt</dc:creator>
<ExtractedText>By Alex Prewitt December 10 at 8:41 AM Follow @alex_prewitt
(Kim Klement/USA TODAY Sports)
TAMPA — As the veteran on a line with youngsters, Washington Capitals forward Troy Brouwer understood his role, and lately he felt he had set a poor example . He wanted opponents to fear him, left winger Marcus Johansson and whichever rookie center skated between them. Maybe now, after Brouwer freed his stick just long enough to elevate the puck into the top shelf for a key goal in a 5-3 win over powerful Tampa Bay, someone finally would.
“I thought he really deserved to get one today,” Coach Barry Trotz said. “I thought he deserved a goal tonight just based on his detail and his work ethic tonight.”
A nifty pass from Johansson on the rush and Brouwer’s ensuing tight-wire finish ended the latter’s five-on-five scoring drought at 17 games and made good on his demands Monday to anchor a group that had not scored an even-strength goal since Nov. 28 against the Islanders, which also happened to be Washington’s frontrunner for “best victory of the season so far” until Tuesday night in Tampa.
“We had a lot of good opportunities tonight. Still in the same boat, is we’re not finishing the majority of our opportunities and we have to continue to progress and find the back of the net,” Brouwer said. “But as far as our line, we got one sustained shift in our own zone, which we’ve been working hard in our D-zone and trying to break out quickly and not give them a whole lot. But all in all I thought we were a pretty effective tonight.”
At Amalie Arena, Brouwer finished second among Capitals forwards with a 63.16 percent Corsi-for, according to War On Ice , meaning more than three-fifths of total shot attempts went in Washington’s favor whenever he skated. Center Evgeny Kuznetsov, again tabbed instead of Andre Burakovsky, clocked in at 61.11 percent, while Johansson recorded a tidy 55 percent. Washington’s top group of Alex Ovechkin, Nicklas Backstrom and Tom Wilson also finished at 55 percent or higher.
“Our big guys showed up tonight and scored some goals for us,” Trotz said. “There wasn’t any passengers tonight.”
Trotz talks often about “passengers,” part of his lexicon that refers to each player knowing his role, or “seat on the bus.” For Brouwer, that meant crashing the net and battling behind the wall, while his skilled linemates handled the puck. Kuznetsov, Johansson and Brouwer were all unable to convert breakaway attempts, and Brouwer missing a close-range rebound on defenseman Nate Schmidt’s on-the-rush attempt, but as Washington sought comfort with a 3-2 lead, the line at last found the net.
The play started when Brouwer dug the puck out from along the boards in the defensive zone, a heavy point of emphasis in recent weeks for their group. Carrying the puck, Johansson surged up the far wall, past the benches, and slowed as he reached the right faceoff circle. Kuznetsov occupied the backdoor, but Brouwer used a late speed burst to get past captain Steven Stamkos. Johansson’s past wasn’t perfect, but Brouwer jiggled his stick free of Stamkos and flicked the puck across the crease, high-blocker on goaltender Ben Bishop.
“He had a breakaway, he did a really good job defensively, had a good chance, but his wall play was really, really strong,” Trotz said. “It opened up a lot of things for that line and I just thought at the end of the day, he was skating he was doing all the details in the game. He got rewarded just by using that big body and fending off people and getting it over Bishop.”
Later, in the visiting locker room, while the cameras swarmed goaltender Braden Holtby, Brouwer stood off to the side and allowed himself a slight smile. After talking about greater production the day before, was this, a reporter asked, the type of game he meant? Brouwer nodded.
“It is,” he said.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
