<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Sports: Sports News, Scores, Analysis, Schedules &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/2010/07/08/AB582vC_page.html?wprss=rss_sports</link>
<description>The Washington Post Sports section provides sports news, video, scores, analysis and updates about high school, college, and pro sports teams, including the Capitals, Nationals, Redskins, United and Wizards. Post Sports also offers blogs and discussions about the latest sports news.</description>
<language>en</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2012 Washington Post Company</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 15:57:11 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 15:57:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>Sports: Sports News, Scores, Analysis, Schedules &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<url>http://media3.washingtonpost.com/wp-srv/hp/image/wp_web.gif</url>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/2010/07/08/AB582vC_page.html?wprss=rss_sports</link>
</image>
<item>
<title>With a pair of Division I recruits, McNamara girls’ basketball starts perfect</title>
<link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636679/s/414d64d5/sc/13/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Csports0Chighschools0Cwith0Ea0Epair0Eof0Edivision0Ei0Erecruits0Emcnamara0Egirls0Ebasketball0Estarts0Eperfect0C20A140C120C10A0Cd91b3b790E26f10E4530A0E95ec0E65a33e33df210Istory0Bhtml0Dwprss0Frss0Isports/story01.htm</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;When the final buzzer sounded on McNamara’s stunning comeback win against Riverdale Baptist last week, junior guard &lt;a data-xslt="_http" href="http://wiki.allmetsports.com/all-met/players/prince-georges/mcnamara/girls-basketball/419968/"&gt;Morgan Smith&lt;/a&gt; felt a mix of joy and pride, but not necessarily surprise. The Mustangs rallied from a 20-point deficit in the second half for a 46-45 win against the Crusaders, who were ranked in the top-five of multiple national girls’ basketball rankings.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/highschools/with-a-pair-of-division-i-recruits-mcnamara-girls-basketball-starts-perfect/2014/12/10/d91b3b79-26f1-4530-95ec-65a33e33df21_story.html?wprss=rss_sports"&gt;Read full article &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636679/s/414d64d5/sc/13/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;</description>
<category domain="">Bishop McNamara</category>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 14:21:38 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/highschools/with-a-pair-of-division-i-recruits-mcnamara-girls-basketball-starts-perfect/2014/12/10/d91b3b79-26f1-4530-95ec-65a33e33df21_story.html?wprss=rss_sports</guid>
<dc:creator>Isabelle Khurshudyan</dc:creator>
<ExtractedText>By Isabelle Khurshudyan December 10 at 9:21 AM Follow @ikhurshudyan
When the final buzzer sounded on McNamara’s stunning comeback win against Riverdale Baptist last week, junior guard Morgan Smith felt a mix of joy and pride, but not necessarily surprise. The Mustangs rallied from a 20-point deficit in the second half for a 46-45 win against the Crusaders, who were ranked in the top-five of multiple national girls’ basketball rankings.
The win, and those that have come since, have  McNamara looking like a legitimate Washington Catholic Athletic Conference contender this season, but that’s what the Mustangs always were in their mind. Led by Smith, who has piled up more than 20 offers, and senior guard Myka Johnson-Matthews, a Stetson recruit, McNamara has started undefeated, and the Mustangs have been boosted by a roster that did not lose a single senior to graduation.
Since beating the Crusaders, McNamara has vaulted onto the national scene, attracting a top-10 ranking from the USAToday national girls’ basketball rankings .
“It shows us what we’re capable of and what we can do in the future,”  Smith said of the Riverdale Baptist win. “It was like a test for us. It’s given us a little bit of a boost. You’re only as good as what you do on the court, so we’re keeping that in mind and working hard for every game.”
Smith is the leading scorer for the Mustangs through the start of this season, averaging 16 points per game, and Johnson-Matthews and senior Kholby Oliver are right behind her with both averaging around 11 points. Though Smith has taken on a bigger role in her junior season, the scoring has been balanced for McNamara to date. Smith scored 20 points against Friendship Collegiate, but then Oliver was the leading scorer against Riverdale Baptist. Against Holy Cross on Tuesday night, Johnson-Matthews led her team with 17 points.
Since Smith has attracted offers from schools like Rutgers, Temple, Mississippi State and more, teams will inevitably have a plan to defend her. The Mustangs’ ability to develop scoring threats around her this early in the season bodes well going forward.
“It’s very good to know that no matter what, your teammates always have your back,” Smith said. “You don’t have to make every shot.”
Smith is also receiving interest from several ACC programs and has taken visits to Georgia Tech, Virginia and George Washington, but with the season in full swing, she said her focus is singular. If she takes any more visits in the near future, they will be to nearby schools.
With McNamara now in the national spotlight, Smith and the rest of the Mustangs will also receive more attention if the Mustangs’ run continues in WCAC play, which features an grueling slate, as usual. McNamara will play No. 1 Paul VI, also nationally ranked, on Jan. 9.
“We feel like we have a great team,” Coach Frank Oliver said. “They know they can compete with anybody in the country, and you have to have that mentality in our league. The ultimate goal is to be the best team that we can be, and we know that every single night presents a different challenge or a different obstacle.”
NUMBER CRUNCH: 95
Through three games, National Cathedral senior and Stanford recruit Marta Sniezek has scored 95 points. In the Eagles win over St. Stephen’s/St. Agnes on Tuesday night, she was the leading scorer with 25.
BREAKFAST LINKS:
Kentucky recruit Taylor Murray’s 36 points boosted Annapolis Area Christian to a 63-48 win over Meade.
Good Counsel girls’ basketball beat St. John’s, 67-49 , in the Falcons first Washington Catholic Athletic Association game of the season thanks to 25 points from senior forward Nicole Enabosi, a Delaware recruit.
Football and the military often compete for students’ allegiances in the South.
PHOTOS OF THE DAY:
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
