<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Sports: Sports News, Scores, Analysis, Schedules &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/2010/07/08/AB582vC_page.html?wprss=rss_sports</link>
<description>The Washington Post Sports section provides sports news, video, scores, analysis and updates about high school, college, and pro sports teams, including the Capitals, Nationals, Redskins, United and Wizards. Post Sports also offers blogs and discussions about the latest sports news.</description>
<language>en</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2012 Washington Post Company</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 15:57:11 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 15:57:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>Sports: Sports News, Scores, Analysis, Schedules &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<url>http://media3.washingtonpost.com/wp-srv/hp/image/wp_web.gif</url>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/2010/07/08/AB582vC_page.html?wprss=rss_sports</link>
</image>
<item>
<title>Fantasy football Week 15 start/sit: Start Eli Manning against Redskins, bench Frank Gore against Seahawks</title>
<link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636679/s/414e17a4/sc/13/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cfantasy0Efootball0Eweek0E150Estartsit0Estart0Eeli0Emanning0Eagainst0Eredskins0Ebench0Efrank0Egore0Eagainst0Eseahawks0C20A140C120C10A0C92fec4390Efbee0E46bf0E98aa0E28e60A0A5347630Istory0Bhtml0Dwprss0Frss0Isports/story01.htm</link>
<description>&lt;p/&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;em&gt;Each week, Neil Greenberg will give you three players to start and three to sit in your fantasy football league. &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Start&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Eli Manning, QB, New York Giants&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/fantasy-football-week-15-startsit-start-eli-manning-against-redskins-bench-frank-gore-against-seahawks/2014/12/10/92fec439-fbee-46bf-98aa-28e600534763_story.html?wprss=rss_sports"&gt;Read full article &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636679/s/414e17a4/sc/13/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 14:43:37 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.washingtonpost.com/fantasy-football-week-15-startsit-start-eli-manning-against-redskins-bench-frank-gore-against-seahawks/2014/12/10/92fec439-fbee-46bf-98aa-28e600534763_story.html?wprss=rss_sports</guid>
<dc:creator>Neil Greenberg</dc:creator>
<ExtractedText>By Neil Greenberg December 10 at 9:43 AM Follow @ngreenberg
(Don McPeak/USA Today Sports)
Each week, Neil Greenberg will give you three players to start and three to sit in your fantasy football league. 
Start
Eli Manning, QB, New York Giants
Manning and the Giants had 449 total yards when they faced the Redskins in Week 4, and this Washington team has only gotten worse since then.
The Redskins have allowed the most fantasy points to opposing quarterbacks this season (20.5 per game) and are a bottom five team in net yards allowed per pass (7.1).
Daniel Herron, RB, Indianapolis Colts
It is time for the Trent Richardson experiment in Indianapolis to end. Herron is averaging more yards per carry (5.1 vs. 3.3) and has two runs of 15 or more yards on 50 attempts compared with Richardson’s three on 141 carries. With Herron running the ball, the Colts’ offense moves the chains 24 percent of the time. When it is Richardson, that drops down to 17.9 percent.
Plus, their opponent this week, the Houston Texans, is much better at rushing the passer than stopping the run.
Keenan Allen, WR, San Diego Chargers
Don’t let last week’s production fool you: when Allen isn’t on Revis Island, he is a must start.
Plus, the last time he faced the Broncos defense he made nine catches on 13 targets for 73 yards and a touchdown.
Sit
Johnny Manziel, QB, Cleveland Browns
It’s tempting to start Johnny Football against the Bengals , who are one of the poorest pass-rushing teams in the league, but their secondary has held opposing quarterbacks to the ninth-fewest net yards per pass (6.2). That could mean an inconsistent game for the rookie quarterback.
Plus, Manziel wilted under the pressure in his limited action against Buffalo a few weeks ago.
Washington Redskins’ wide receivers
It is possible Colt McCoy’s neck injury is severe enough that Robert Griffin III might once again start at quarterback. If that’s the case, all Redskins’ receivers are too risky to be in your lineup.
RGIII has a Total Quarterback Rating — which values quarterback on all play types on a 0-to-100 scale — of 26.5 and is averaging just 5.3 net yards per pass, which is 20 percent below league average.
Frank Gore, RB, San Fransisco 49ers
Gore has just two rushing touchdowns this season and faces Seattle this week, who limited him to 28 yards on 10 carries in Week 13. The Seahawks, whose defense is on the upswing, are allowing the third-fewest yards per carry (3.5) and the sixth-fewest fantasy points to running backs (14.7).
Neil Greenberg analyzes advanced sports statistics for the Fancy Stats blog and prefers to be called a geek rather than a nerd.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
