<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Sports: Sports News, Scores, Analysis, Schedules &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/2010/07/08/AB582vC_page.html?wprss=rss_sports</link>
<description>The Washington Post Sports section provides sports news, video, scores, analysis and updates about high school, college, and pro sports teams, including the Capitals, Nationals, Redskins, United and Wizards. Post Sports also offers blogs and discussions about the latest sports news.</description>
<language>en</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2012 Washington Post Company</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 16:39:23 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 16:39:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>Sports: Sports News, Scores, Analysis, Schedules &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<url>http://media3.washingtonpost.com/wp-srv/hp/image/wp_web.gif</url>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/2010/07/08/AB582vC_page.html?wprss=rss_sports</link>
</image>
<item>
<title>DC Sports Bog: Larry Michael won’t apologize for picking the Redskins to win every week</title>
<link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636679/s/414ef19f/sc/13/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Csports0Clarry0Emichael0Ewont0Eapologize0Efor0Epicking0Ethe0Eredskins0Eto0Ewin0Eevery0Eweek0C20A140C120C10A0Cad1b8aaf0Ea1860E41a50Eb63f0Ed24eed80Abef50Istory0Bhtml0Dwprss0Frss0Isports/story01.htm</link>
<description>&lt;p/&gt; &lt;p&gt;Perhaps I was a bit hyperbolic in writing earlier this week that Larry Michael’s prediction of a double-digit Redskins win over the Rams &lt;a data-xslt="_http" href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/dc-sports-bog/wp/2014/12/08/larry-michaels-preview-of-the-rams-game-was-everything-thats-wrong-with-the-redskins/"&gt;demonstrated everything that’s been wrong with the franchise&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;My point was that a senior vice president for the franchise giving the Redskins the edge in offense, special teams and intangibles before a 24-0 home loss was emblematic of a greater problem: A refusal to acknowledge the often-wretched reality of where the team is, and an optimistic insistence that good times are nigh.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/larry-michael-wont-apologize-for-picking-the-redskins-to-win-every-week/2014/12/10/ad1b8aaf-a186-41a5-b63f-d24eed80bef5_story.html?wprss=rss_sports"&gt;Read full article &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636679/s/414ef19f/sc/13/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;</description>
<category domain="">Redskins</category>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 16:37:51 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/larry-michael-wont-apologize-for-picking-the-redskins-to-win-every-week/2014/12/10/ad1b8aaf-a186-41a5-b63f-d24eed80bef5_story.html?wprss=rss_sports</guid>
<dc:creator>Dan Steinberg</dc:creator>
<ExtractedText>By Dan Steinberg December 10 at 11:37 AM Follow @dcsportsbog
(By Toni L. Sandys/The Washington Post)
Perhaps I was a bit hyperbolic in writing earlier this week that Larry Michael’s prediction of a double-digit Redskins win over the Rams demonstrated everything that’s been wrong with the franchise .
My point was that a senior vice president for the franchise giving the Redskins the edge in offense, special teams and intangibles before a 24-0 home loss was emblematic of a greater problem: A refusal to acknowledge the often-wretched reality of where the team is, and an optimistic insistence that good times are nigh.
Clearly, though, Michael is not making personnel decisions, or coaching up the players, or covering kickoffs. At least not to my knowledge.
In any case, if you were wondering whether Michael was chastened by his optimistic prediction before a 24-0 home loss, the answer is nah. But Michael did address that prediction on the team-produced “Redskins Nation” program this week.
“Before we hear from Jay Gruden, I have something I’d like to say,” Michael began. “I’m not going to apologize, ever, for picking the Redskins here, every week, on Redskins Nation. Everybody knows what I do for a living, I work for the Redskins.
“Maybe you you shouldn’t be as surprised that over the course of the week, here on ‘Redskins Nation’ and while I’m at Redskins Park, I see how hard this team works, I see how much time they put into it,” he said. “And by the end of the week, I believe the Redskins are going to win. And I’m not going to apologize for the way I believe and the way I feel. And I appreciate everyone watching and complimenting me on the way I pick the games each week.”
Which is fine. I’m overly defensive and optimistic about The Washington Post, too. And a “Redskins Nation” episode that was pessimistic about the future of the Redskins would hardly be a “Redskins Nation” episode, anyhow. You don’t go to the arrival and departure monitors at an airport for updates on air safety.
— Dan Steinberg (@dcsportsbog) December 10, 2014
Dan Steinberg writes about all things D.C. sports at the D.C. Sports Bog.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
