<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Sports: Sports News, Scores, Analysis, Schedules &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/2010/07/08/AB582vC_page.html?wprss=rss_sports</link>
<description>The Washington Post Sports section provides sports news, video, scores, analysis and updates about high school, college, and pro sports teams, including the Capitals, Nationals, Redskins, United and Wizards. Post Sports also offers blogs and discussions about the latest sports news.</description>
<language>en</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2012 Washington Post Company</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 17:11:12 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 17:11:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>Sports: Sports News, Scores, Analysis, Schedules &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<url>http://media3.washingtonpost.com/wp-srv/hp/image/wp_web.gif</url>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/2010/07/08/AB582vC_page.html?wprss=rss_sports</link>
</image>
<item>
<title>NBA power rankings: Warriors remain at No. 1, Thunder on the move</title>
<link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636679/s/414eafd3/sc/13/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cnba0Epower0Erankings0Ewarriors0Eremain0Eat0Eno0E10Ethunder0Eon0Ethe0Emove0C20A140C120C10A0C0A6178ae90E942d0E44be0E94930E8b1165e80A3120Istory0Bhtml0Dwprss0Frss0Isports/story01.htm</link>
<description>&lt;p/&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;em&gt;Each week, Neil Greenberg will give his &lt;a data-xslt="_http" href="http://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/objective" target="_blank"&gt;objective&lt;/a&gt; NBA power rankings based on a team’s ability to win games (via the &lt;a data-xslt="_http" href="http://www.baseball-reference.com/bullpen/Pythagorean_Theorem_of_Baseball" target="_blank"&gt;Pythagorean win expectation&lt;/a&gt;, modified for the NBA) and Dean Oliver’s “&lt;a data-xslt="_http" href="http://www.basketball-reference.com/about/factors.html" target="_blank"&gt;Four Factors of Basketball Success&lt;/a&gt;,” which assesses the following:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/nba-power-rankings-warriors-remain-at-no-1-thunder-on-the-move/2014/12/10/06178ae9-942d-44be-9493-8b1165e80312_story.html?wprss=rss_sports"&gt;Read full article &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636679/s/414eafd3/sc/13/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 17:10:26 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.washingtonpost.com/nba-power-rankings-warriors-remain-at-no-1-thunder-on-the-move/2014/12/10/06178ae9-942d-44be-9493-8b1165e80312_story.html?wprss=rss_sports</guid>
<dc:creator>Neil Greenberg</dc:creator>
<ExtractedText>By Neil Greenberg December 10 at 12:10 PM Follow @ngreenberg
(AP Photo/Sue Ogrocki)
Each week, Neil Greenberg will give his  objective  NBA power rankings based on a team’s ability to win games (via the  Pythagorean win expectation , modified for the NBA) and Dean Oliver’s “ Four Factors of Basketball Success ,” which assesses the following:
Shooting, as measured by effective field goal percentage.
Rebounding, as measured by a team’s offensive and defensive rebounding percentages.
Free throw rate, calculated by taking a team’s free throws made divided by their field goals attempted.
Turnover rate on a per-possession basis.
Included with each team is its actual record plus its offensive and defensive rating, which is how many points scored/allowed per 100 possessions. The league has averaged  106.2 points scored per 100 possessions through Tuesday . The bigger the difference, the better the team is performing.
Here are this week’s power ratings along with each team’s points scored and allowed per 100 possessions. Agree or disagree? Let Neil know on Twitter  @ngreenberg .
1. Golden State Warriors (18-2), Last week’s ranking: 1
Offensive Rating: 109
Defensive Rating: 97.6
Defensively, the Warriors still lead the league in points allowed per 100 possessions and effective field goal percentage allowed and are in the top three offensively for effective field goal percentage. Point guard Stephen Curry is also making a case for MVP behind his 23.1 points, 5.1 rebounds, 7.7 assists and 2.0 steals per game.
2. Portland Trail Blazers (17-4), Last week’s ranking: 5
Offensive Rating: 109.5
Defensive Rating: 101.4
Portland may be higher here than in other rankings, but its play has been solid and LaMarcus Aldrige has been unstoppable from beyond the three-point arc.
LAMARCUS ALDRIDGE FGA DURING 2014-15 REGULAR SEASON (2014-15)
3. Dallas Mavericks (16-7), Last week’s ranking: 4
Offensive Rating: 116.1
Defensive Rating: 108.3
The Mavericks’ deficiencies on the defensive glass (71.2 defensive rebound percentage) are masked by their ability to put points on the board (league-leading 116.1 points scored per 100 possessions).
4. Los Angeles Clippers (15-5), Last week’s ranking: 7
Offensive Rating: 113.4
The Clippers lead the NBA in three-point shooting and are prolific from both corners.
LOS ANGELES CLIPPERS FGA DURING 2014-15 REGULAR SEASON (2014-15)
5. Toronto Raptors (16-6), Last week’s ranking: 2
Offensive Rating: 115.6
Defensive Rating: 107.0
The loss of DeMar DeRozan is mitigated by Kyle Lowry’s Eastern Conference player of the week performance .
6. Memphis Grizzlies (17-4), Last week’s ranking: 3
Offensive Rating: 110.2
Defensive Rating: 102.5
The Grizzlies’ only home loss is to the Spurs and they are in the top 10 for all but one of the Defensive Four Factors .
7. San Antonio Spurs (15-6), Last week’s ranking: 6
Offensive Rating: 107.0
Defensive Rating: 100.0
Losses to the Nets and Jazz don’t look great, but getting Tiago Splitter back should keep those to a minimum.
8. Houston Rockets (16-4), Last week’s ranking: 8
Offensive Rating: 105.0
Defensive Rating: 99.9
The Rockets have won seven of their last 10 and love to take the three-point shot.
9. Cleveland Cavaliers (13-7), Last week’s ranking: 9
Offensive Rating: 111.8
Defensive Rating: 106.1
Eight straight wins are impressive, but this team still struggles on defense: The Cavs rank 21st in effective field goal percentage allowed and 22nd in defensive rebound percentage.
10. Washington Wizards (14-6), Last week’s ranking: 11
Offensive Rating: 106.1
Defensive Rating: 102.2
The Wizards continue to be inconsistent. John Wall notches a double-double in four straight wins and then the team loses at 7-12 Boston.
(Source: inpredictable.com)
11. Atlanta Hawks (14-6), Last week’s ranking: 13
Offensive Rating: 109.5
Defensive Rating: 104.5
After adjusting margin of victory for strength of schedule, the Hawks have played the fifth-easiest slate of games so far , and Jeff Teague is taking advantage: He is setting career highs in true shooting percentage (60.7 percent), win shares per 48 minutes (0.188) and the rate at which he gets to the free throw line (42.4 percent).
12. Phoenix Suns (12-11), Last week’s ranking: 16
Offensive Rating: 107.9
Defensive Rating: 106.2
The Suns are fourth in the league at three-point attempt rate and fifth in three-point shooting, placing them in the top 10 for points scored per 100 possessions. However, they will have to sort out the shooting issues on the rest of the court if they want to make a serious move.
PHOENIX SUNS FGA DURING 2014-15 REGULAR SEASON (2014-15)
13. Chicago Bulls (12-8), Last week’s ranking: 10
Offensive Rating: 107.6
Defensive Rating: 105.4
Derrick Rose hasn’t given Chicago the offensive pop everyone was expecting upon his return. With him on the court, the Bulls are scoring 108.5 points per 100 possessions. That’s just 1.3 points more than when he is on the bench.
14. Sacramento Kings (11-11), Last week’s ranking: 14
Offensive Rating: 107.5
Defensive Rating: 107.5
The Kings are 2-5 without DeMarcus Cousins, who has viral meningitis and might miss a few more games.
15. New Orleans Pelicans (10-10), Last week’s ranking: 12
Offensive Rating: 108.7
Defensive Rating: 107.9
Anthony Davis leads the league in win shares (4.4) and would be the lock for MVP if not on a team projected to win 41 games.
16. Oklahoma City Thunder (8-13), Last week’s ranking: 21
Offensive Rating: 101.4
Defensive Rating: 102.4
Three games behind the Suns for the final playoff spot isn’t ideal, but the Thunder is 3-1 with both Russell Westbrook and Kevin Durant in the lineup, which, after adjusting for the small sample size, puts them on a 46-win pace.
17. Milwaukee Bucks (11-12), Last week’s ranking: 17
Offensive Rating: 103.6
Defensive Rating: 105.4
The Bucks have lost five of their last six, turn the ball over too much on offense (15.5 percent turnover percentage) and don’t grab defensive rebounds (72.1 percent).
18. Denver Nuggets (9-12), Last week’s ranking: 15
Offensive Rating: 106.7
Defensive Rating: 109.0
Denver has lost four straight and is falling apart defensively, allowing 109 points per 100 possessions and letting opponents get to the free throw line at the league’s third most frequent pace (0.261).
19. Boston Celtics (7-12), Last week’s ranking: 22
Offensive Rating: 106.0
Defensive Rating: 107.7
Rajon Rondo leads the league in assists per game (10.8) and was last seen having breakfast with the Lakers’ Kobe Bryant .
20. Miami Heat (10-11), Last week’s ranking: 18
Offensive Rating: 106.3
Defensive Rating: 109.8
Pat Riley’s teams have been defensively sound in the past, but this Heat team is giving up 109.8 points per 100 possessions,   fifth most in the league .
21. Indiana Pacers (7-14), Last week’s ranking: 20
Offensive Rating: 100.4
Defensive Rating: 104.1
It’s hard to tell which Pacers team is more representative of the season: The one that beat the Mavericks and Bulls on the road or the one that just lost five straight.
22. Brooklyn Nets (8-11), Last week’s ranking: 19
Offensive Rating: 102.8
Defensive Rating: 106.2
The Nets beat the Spurs in overtime and then lost two straight to the Hawks and Cavaliers, the latter beating them by 22 points.
23. Utah Jazz (6-16), Last week’s ranking: 23
Offensive Rating: 106.1
The Jazz lost nine straight before beating the Spurs, 100-96, at home.
24. Orlando Magic (9-14), Last week’s ranking: 25
Offensive Rating: 101.4
Defensive Rating: 106.9
Scoring points is a challenge ( 101.4 points per 100 possessions , 26th in the league)  but the Magic did go 3-3 on its most recent West Coast road trip.
25. New York Knicks (4-19), Last week’s ranking: 24
Offensive Rating: 104.3
The Knicks are struggling to win despite playing against the fourth-easiest schedule .
26. Los Angeles Lakers (6-16), Last week’s ranking: 27
Offensive Rating: 106.5
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
