<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Sports: Sports News, Scores, Analysis, Schedules &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/2010/07/08/AB582vC_page.html?wprss=rss_sports</link>
<description>The Washington Post Sports section provides sports news, video, scores, analysis and updates about high school, college, and pro sports teams, including the Capitals, Nationals, Redskins, United and Wizards. Post Sports also offers blogs and discussions about the latest sports news.</description>
<language>en</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2012 Washington Post Company</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 15:57:11 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 15:57:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>Sports: Sports News, Scores, Analysis, Schedules &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<url>http://media3.washingtonpost.com/wp-srv/hp/image/wp_web.gif</url>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/2010/07/08/AB582vC_page.html?wprss=rss_sports</link>
</image>
<item>
<title>Roger Goodell to unveil new personal conduct policy for players at NFL owners’ meetings</title>
<link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636679/s/414d5ef7/sc/13/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Csports0Croger0Egoodell0Eto0Eunveil0Enew0Epersonal0Econduct0Epolicy0Efor0Eplayers0Eat0Enfl0Eowners0Emeetings0C20A140C120C10A0C80Ad8156a0E0Ae620E49250Ea8e30E660Abb9ae0A8460Istory0Bhtml0Dwprss0Frss0Isports/story01.htm</link>
<description>&lt;p/&gt; &lt;p&gt;Commissioner Roger Goodell is expected to &lt;a data-xslt="_http" href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/sports/wp/2014/12/09/nfl-owners-to-have-extensive-discussions-wednesday-of-new-personal-conduct-policy/" target="_blank"&gt;outline a clearer, tougher personal conduct policy&lt;/a&gt; for players at a meeting of NFL owners Wednesday, expressing a willingness to remove himself, at least initially, from the discipline process.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/roger-goodell-to-unveil-new-personal-conduct-policy-for-players-at-nfl-owners-meetings/2014/12/10/80d8156a-0e62-4925-a8e3-660bb9ae0846_story.html?wprss=rss_sports"&gt;Read full article &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636679/s/414d5ef7/sc/13/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 13:53:50 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/roger-goodell-to-unveil-new-personal-conduct-policy-for-players-at-nfl-owners-meetings/2014/12/10/80d8156a-0e62-4925-a8e3-660bb9ae0846_story.html?wprss=rss_sports</guid>
<dc:creator>Cindy Boren</dc:creator>
<ExtractedText>By Cindy Boren December 10 at 8:53 AM Follow @cindyboren
(John Minchillo / AP)
Commissioner Roger Goodell is expected to outline a clearer, tougher personal conduct policy for players at a meeting of NFL owners Wednesday, expressing a willingness to remove himself, at least initially, from the discipline process.
The new policy proposal for owners, Goodell told the Wall Street Journal , is modeled on that used by the New York Police Department. Under it, an accused player would immediately be placed on paid leave after formal charges were filed or after an independent investigation under the proposal that would also apply to all NFL personnel, including owners. Discipline would be handled by a newly created special counsel for investigations and conduct, the NFL Network’s Ian Rapoport reports.
Goodell’s decision comes after a summer in which uneven, belated punishment handed down for domestic violence incidents created a firestorm of criticism, especially of the commissioner, and debate.
“I blew it,” Goodell told the Journal, echoing his earlier comments about a performance that had prompted calls for his removal by owners. “Our penalties didn’t fit the crimes.”
This began, of course, with the bungling of the Ray Rice case. The Baltimore Ravens running back was suspended only two games in July for knocking out his then-fiancee in an elevator. In September, when video of the knockout punch was published by TMZ, the outcry prompted Goodell to increase the penalty to an indefinite suspension and the Ravens released Rice. Rice appealed and an arbitrator overturned his suspension Nov. 28.
There were other cases, handled unevenly, that first month as well and the arrest of Adrian Peterson on a charge of injuring his child while spanking him caused Goodell to come up with another way of handling players accused of domestic incidents: he placed them on the commissioner’s exempt list, essentially putting them on paid leave while their cases were being legally resolved.
All of which leads us to the new policy. Goodell also conferred with NBA Commissioner Adam Silver, as well as with NYPD Commissioner William Bratton, on the policy. The NFL Player Association has had extremely limited input. From the Journal:
National Basketball Association Commissioner Adam Silver and Mr. Goodell compared notes over lunch at 21 Club in Manhattan. “You can learn from what we’re going through,” Mr. Goodell told him. A few weeks later, Mr. Silver, noting the “evolving social consensus” on domestic violence, issued a 24-game suspension of the Charlotte Hornets’ Jeff Taylor, the league’s harshest penalty yet for domestic violence. Mr. Taylor pleaded guilty to misdemeanor domestic-violence assault involving his then-girlfriend.
Mr. Goodell has also turned stricter. He has increased the minimum penalty for domestic violence to a six-game suspension. Last month, he issued a season-long suspension without pay to Mr. Peterson, the Vikings running back, who pleaded no contest to a misdemeanor charge of reckless assault. The players union is appealing the suspension to an arbitrator.
On Nov. 25, Mr. Goodell invited union representatives to his office to discuss his proposed revisions to the personal-conduct policy. The union argued that the NFL and owners should include off-field conduct in the collective-bargaining agreement.
After an hour, “We walked out,” said DeMaurice Smith, NFL Players Association executive director. He complained that the league’s process wasn’t “fair, transparent and consistent.”
The policy isn’t set in stone, though. The issue of paid leave is still up for discussion with the union, according to Rapoport, with the NFLPA wanted it to kick in when a player is charged with a felony and with player consent. Goodell told the Journal that he intends to propose adoption of the new plan at the meetings Wednesday in Dallas. Cowboys owner Jerry Jones told the Journal that owners would likely accept the plan and approve the use of “league assets to take actions as needed against domestic violence and to help victims.”
The owners will meet for only one day, so it’s possible there will be no action on the proposal, The Post’s Mark Maske writes .
According to one person familiar with the league’s deliberations on the policy, a “long discussion” among the owners is expected Wednesday. Another person with knowledge of the league’s planning called the NFL “far along” in its discussions and added a potential Wednesday vote by the owners on a new policy can’t be ruled out.
It is unclear how the league would proceed after a potential vote on the policy. It is also unclear how the NFL Players Association would protest.
After spending most of her career in traditional print sports journalism, Cindy began blogging and tweeting, first as NFL/Redskins editor, and, since August 2010, at The Early Lead. She also is the social media editor for Sports.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
