<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Sports: Sports News, Scores, Analysis, Schedules &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/2010/07/08/AB582vC_page.html?wprss=rss_sports</link>
<description>The Washington Post Sports section provides sports news, video, scores, analysis and updates about high school, college, and pro sports teams, including the Capitals, Nationals, Redskins, United and Wizards. Post Sports also offers blogs and discussions about the latest sports news.</description>
<language>en</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2012 Washington Post Company</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 17:24:13 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 17:24:13 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>Sports: Sports News, Scores, Analysis, Schedules &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<url>http://media3.washingtonpost.com/wp-srv/hp/image/wp_web.gif</url>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/2010/07/08/AB582vC_page.html?wprss=rss_sports</link>
</image>
<item>
<title>Redskins Blog: Colt McCoy takes opening snap in Wednesday’s practice; Robert Griffin III second</title>
<link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636679/s/414efc76/sc/13/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Csports0Credskins0Ccolt0Emccoy0Etakes0Eopening0Esnap0Ein0Ewednesdays0Epractice0Erobert0Egriffin0Eiii0Esecond0C20A140C120C10A0C5cf0Ad270A0E34f30E4e240E90A1f0E1a82475d8b10A0Istory0Bhtml0Dwprss0Frss0Isports/story01.htm</link>
<description>&lt;p/&gt; &lt;p&gt;Three days after injuring his neck on a savage sack, &lt;a data-xslt="_http" href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/football-insider/wp/tag/colt-mccoy/" target="_blank"&gt;Colt McCoy&lt;/a&gt; took the first snap during practice Wednesday at Redskins Park, with Robert Griffin III and Kirk Cousins following.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Only the first 20 minutes of practice is typically open to media during the season, so it’s unclear how first-team duties were split between McCoy, the presumptive starter, and Griffin as work got under way in earnest for Sunday’s game at the New York Giants.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/redskins/colt-mccoy-takes-opening-snap-in-wednesdays-practice-robert-griffin-iii-second/2014/12/10/5cf0d270-34f3-4e24-901f-1a82475d8b10_story.html?wprss=rss_sports"&gt;Read full article &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636679/s/414efc76/sc/13/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;</description>
<category domain="">Colt McCoy</category>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 17:20:19 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/redskins/colt-mccoy-takes-opening-snap-in-wednesdays-practice-robert-griffin-iii-second/2014/12/10/5cf0d270-34f3-4e24-901f-1a82475d8b10_story.html?wprss=rss_sports</guid>
<dc:creator>Liz Clarke</dc:creator>
<ExtractedText>By Liz Clarke December 10 at 12:20 PM Follow @lizclarketweet
Washington Redskins quarterback Colt McCoy (16) is sacked by St. Louis Rams middle linebacker James Laurinaitis (55) and defensive end Robert Quinn (94) during the second half of an NFL football game in Landover, Md., Sunday, Dec. 7, 2014. The Rams defeated the Redskins 24-0. (AP Photo/Nick Wass)
Three days after injuring his neck on a savage sack, Colt McCoy took the first snap during practice Wednesday at Redskins Park, with Robert Griffin III and Kirk Cousins following.
Only the first 20 minutes of practice is typically open to media during the season, so it’s unclear how first-team duties were split between McCoy, the presumptive starter, and Griffin as work got under way in earnest for Sunday’s game at the New York Giants.
Practice was abruptly closed to reporters when a fight erupted between wide receiver Andre Roberts and rookie Bashaud Breeland, who were going against each other on a pass play.
On Monday, McCoy was clearly uncomfortable moving his head to either side when speaking to reporters in the locker room after being blindsided by St. Louis defensive end Robert Quinn with 6 minutes 54 seconds remaining in the previous day’s 24-0 loss to the Rams at FedEx Field. McCoy played on until the two-minute mark, when he was relieved by Griffin.
Neither quarterback distinguished himself in the shutout.
McCoy finished 20 of 32 for 199 yards, with no touchdowns, two interceptions and six sacks, which equated to a passer rating of 54.0. Griffin was sacked once on his lone series, in which he completed 3 of 4 throws.
Coach Jay Gruden said Monday he wouldn’t name a starter for Sunday’s game at the Giants until after having a chance to review medical tests on McCoy. A battery of tests conducted Sunday night and Monday revealed no structural damage , according to a person with knowledge of the situation.
Gruden benched Griffin for lack of production following Washington’s third consecutive loss upon Griffin’s return from dislocated ankle. But McCoy, 28, the only Redskins quarterback to have led the team to a victory this season in a complete game, lost both of his starts since.
When making the change from Griffin to McCoy, Gruden said that McCoy would be the presumptive starter for the balance of the season. But Washington’s front office isn’t ready to pull the plug on Griffin’s development or part ways with the 2011 Heisman Trophy winner, who has not led the Redskins to a win in more than a year.
More from The Post:
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
