<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Technology</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/TECH/index.html?eref=rss_tech</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2016 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 20:40:10 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 20:40:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Technology</title>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/TECH/index.html?eref=rss_tech</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<item>
<title>Mozilla chief: The danger of FBI snooping</title>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676977/s/4db0c7b2/sc/21/l/0L0Scnn0N0C20A160C0A20C180Copinions0Capple0Eencryption0Ebackdoor0Efbi0Esurman0Cindex0Bhtml0Deref0Frss0Itech/story01.htm</link>
<description>&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392038895/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4db0c7b2/sc/21/rc/1/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392038895/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4db0c7b2/sc/21/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392038895/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4db0c7b2/sc/21/rc/2/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392038895/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4db0c7b2/sc/21/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392038895/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4db0c7b2/sc/21/rc/3/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392038895/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4db0c7b2/sc/21/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392038895/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4db0c7b2/sc/21/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392038895/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4db0c7b2/sc/21/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392038895/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4db0c7b2/sc/21/ach.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392038895/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4db0c7b2/sc/21/ach.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/247392038895/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4db0c7b2/sc/21/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi2.feedsportal.com/r/247392038895/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4db0c7b2/sc/21/a2t2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676977/s/4db0c7b2/sc/21/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 20:37:53 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2016/02/18/opinions/apple-encryption-backdoor-fbi-surman/index.html</guid>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160217164637-apple-fbi-san-bernardino-shooters-segall-dnt-lead-00004215-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" lang="" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160217164637-apple-fbi-san-bernardino-shooters-segall-dnt-lead-00004215-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>MUST WATCH
Feinstein: Apple should unlock terrorist's iPhone 05:08
For example, beyond the FBI's current overreach, in the United Kingdom, the draft Investigatory Powers Bill -- dubbed the "snoopers' charter" -- would allow government agencies to access users' Internet and email data.
The justification offered? Encryption without back doors helps bad actors and unsavory behavior. But even if back doors are initially designed for trusted actors, it's possible that they will get exploited by the bad guys. At which point we all become less secure.
In truth, we can respect the concerns of law enforcement officials while respectfully disagreeing with proposed policies. Sapping the effectiveness of encryption protections threatens the entire Internet.
Fortunately, marquee names in tech have emerged as champions of encryption . Apple's Tim Cook has been unwavering in his support, defending encryption fiercely and frequently, often clashing with public officials. Apple's willingness to defend encryption and its customers has been a tremendous boon.
This high-level support from leaders across the tech industry is crucial. But it won't be enough.
We also need a movement: a push by Internet users of all stripes. We need a grassroots movement with the same magnitude and passion as those that have formed around issues like the environment or civil rights.
We've seen the seed of this open Internet movement sprout in the last few years over issues like the Stop Online Piracy Act (SOPA) and Protect IP Act (PIPA) , and net neutrality.  Around this time last year, millions of Internet users banded together on net neutrality, aiming to protect the Internet as a public resource free of fast lanes, slow lanes and corporate control.
It began with education and awareness: Technologists, activists and passionate everyday Internet users took the time to make a complex but crucial Internet issue straightforward. In doing so, millions of users stood up to the cable Goliaths via protests, petitions and other grassroots methods.
Now it's time to look at how that movement can grow and take on its next challenge: laws that weaken encryption.
JUST WATCHED
MUST WATCH
Why Apple is fighting FBI court order 02:14
Everyday Internet users can make a difference. By learning about encryption and starting conversations around the kitchen table, even the casual Web user can contribute to making encryption discussion more mainstream. Too often, encryption is perceived as a baffling subject best left to policymakers. But it shouldn't be — "ciphertext," "cipher" and "plaintext" can become part of the public lexicon .
This worked for net neutrality. So, tell your friends and family: encryption is worth defending. Then we can begin to have a public dialogue about why weakening encryption is a bad idea.
Mozilla is eager to work with others across the open Internet movement to hasten this process. We're starting with a campaign to articulate encryption's indispensable role. This campaign will complement Mozilla's ongoing work to champion encryption. We continue to push the envelope with projects like Let's Encrypt, a free, automated and open Web certificate authority that helps ensure all Internet browsing is encrypted.
Online, security must be protected. Let's work together to make 2016 the year Internet security wins and encryption remains safe.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
