<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Technology</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/TECH/index.html?eref=rss_tech</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2016 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 20:40:10 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 20:40:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Technology</title>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/TECH/index.html?eref=rss_tech</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<item>
<title>Vetting drivers in age of Uber</title>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676977/s/4dcab6f2/sc/3/l/0L0Scnn0N0C20A160C0A20C230Copinions0Cuber0Edriver0Ebackground0Echeck0Elandin0Cindex0Bhtml0Deref0Frss0Itech/story01.htm</link>
<description>&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392519930/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4dcab6f2/rc/1/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392519930/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4dcab6f2/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392519930/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4dcab6f2/rc/2/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392519930/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4dcab6f2/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392519930/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4dcab6f2/rc/3/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392519930/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4dcab6f2/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392519930/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4dcab6f2/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392519930/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4dcab6f2/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392519930/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4dcab6f2/ach.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392519930/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4dcab6f2/ach.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/247392519930/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4dcab6f2/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi2.feedsportal.com/r/247392519930/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4dcab6f2/a2t2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676977/s/4dcab6f2/sc/3/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 13:23:04 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2016/02/23/opinions/uber-driver-background-check-landin/index.html</guid>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160222150821-uber-kalamazoo-shooting-dalton-arraignment-nr-00002106-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" lang="" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160222150821-uber-kalamazoo-shooting-dalton-arraignment-nr-00002106-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>Facebook Twitter Instagram
&lt;div class="banner" id="cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0_banner"&gt;&lt;span id="cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" class="_fwph"&gt;&lt;form id="_fw_form_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" style="display:none"&gt;&lt;input type="hidden" name="_fw_input_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" id="_fw_input_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" value="ptgt=s&amp;envp=g_js&amp;w=300&amp;h=250&amp;slau=300x250_sync&amp;adUnit=300x250_sync"&gt;&lt;/form&gt;&lt;span id="_fw_container_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" class="cn-shingle__ad"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="ad_bnr_atf_01" class="ad-ad_bnr_atf_01 ad-refresh-adbanner"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Vetting drivers in the age of Uber
By Brad Landin
Updated 0539 GMT (1339 HKT) February 23, 2016
JUST WATCHED
Police: Uber driver admits to 'taking people's lives' 01:55
Story highlights
Brad Landin: Uber driver allegedly shot people in Michigan rampage between providing rides. Uber's vetting of drivers under new scrutiny
He says to work, background checks must use overlapping, complex, local searches. It's not clear how thorough Uber's searches are
Brad Landin is president and chief compliance officer of Employment Screening Resources, a background check company based in Novato, California. The opinions expressed in this commentary are solely those of the author.
(CNN)
The recent mass shooting in Kalamazoo, Michigan, in which the alleged gunman apparently provided rides as an Uber driver between shootings, has placed public attention squarely on the issue of the background checks performed on Uber drivers.
Jason Brian Dalton -- who is facing murder, assault and firearms charges -- apparently had no criminal record, so a background check would not have helped exclude him.  Yet, the case raises questions about personal safety in the so-called "gig economy," where total strangers are invited into your life through software applications to provide a host of services, ranging from transportation and housecleaning to babysitting and acting as a personal assistant.
Background checks are a complex issue.  Contrary to public belief, there is no comprehensive database or source of information that provides a perfect one-stop background check solution. Even the fingerprint database maintained by the Federal Bureau of Investigation is far from perfect.
JUST WATCHED
MUST WATCH
Uber driver charged with 6 counts of murder 03:11
Although the FBI check uses biometric matching, the shortcomings of FBI criminal searches have been well documented .  In 2006 the U.S. attorney general revealed that roughly 50% of the records are incomplete and fail to provide information on the final outcome of an arrest.
Employers using background screening firms can and do access millions of records through unofficial private sector databases as a source of possible information. However, these databases are incomplete and subject to both false negatives (meaning a criminal record is missed) and false positives (meaning the record is about the wrong person or that, by law, the criminal matter should not have been reported).  In our opinion, this type of database should not be relied upon as a standalone search.
Read More
With some 3,200 counties in America to scour, these private sector databases are by no means complete, accurate and up to date. For example, there are a number of states that provide no public access to statewide criminal record s, which usually leaves only a small number of county records that are included in the private sector databases for an entire state.
JUST WATCHED
MUST WATCH
Kalamazoo Uber rider: 'You're not the shooter are you?' 02:03
Within the screening industry, these databases are primarily used as a research tool that can lead to the discovery of information, which must be properly vetted as being reportable under the Fair Credit Reporting Act and corresponding state laws.  The standard screening industry recommendation is to check primary source courthouse records where a person has lived, worked, or studied for at least the past seven years.
Will Uber make your job obsolete? (Opinion)
A thorough search does not begin and end with a background check. Employers should utilize a series of overlapping tools to exercise proper due diligence.  Often, procedures followed before the background check may be the most important: a thorough review of the application, verification of past employment, accounting for gaps in employment and conducting an in-person or video interview before a making a final offer.
In the gig economy there are so many moving parts that it is hard to know just how much due diligence a company is using.  For example, if a service engages someone through an online application without ever meeting him or her, there is the question of whether the person being researched is actually the person who is applying for the job.
In a standard employment situation, the employer -- at some point -- meets the person and engages in some sort of identity verification. That may not always be the case in the gig economy, where people may sign up through a software application, sight unseen to provide ad hoc services.
8 photos: What does the future of consumer tech look like?
8 photos: What does the future of consumer tech look like?
What does the future of consumer tech look like? – Tech expert Shelly Palmer writes for CNN from consumer tech show CES, in Las Vegas. Pictured, the Toyota Mirai fuelcell car. At CES Toyota announced it will share almost 6,000 of its patents on hydrogen fuel cell technology.
Hide Caption
1 of 8
8 photos: What does the future of consumer tech look like?
Uber, on demand – One growing trend -- consumers increasingly want services to be available on demand, says Palmer. Apps like Uber put passengers instantly in touch with driver services.
Hide Caption
2 of 8
8 photos: What does the future of consumer tech look like?
Spotify – Palmer says consumers are increasingly comfortable with "renting" content by paying for access to subscription services, such as music-streaming service Spotify.
Hide Caption
3 of 8
8 photos: What does the future of consumer tech look like?
Smart home, smartphone – Smart cars and smart homes still connect through smartphones. Lockitron, for example, is a service that lets you use your smartphone to unlock your doors.
Hide Caption
4 of 8
8 photos: What does the future of consumer tech look like?
Smart car, smartphone – From CES, this mockup of a car dashboard shows Facebook on a wirelessly connected smartphone displayed on a Mobi/us autonomous dashboard -- a concept for interacting with a self-driving car as well as with a smartphone. When the car is driving on autopilot mode the driver can watch movies or surf the web on their wirelessly connected smartphone.
Hide Caption
5 of 8
8 photos: What does the future of consumer tech look like?
Cyber hacks – Jennifer Lawrence was a victim of 2014's iCloud hack, where nude images of the actress were leaked online. In the future, "People will simply live in fear of having their private lives exposed, fear of losing their fortunes," says Palmer.
Hide Caption
6 of 8
8 photos: What does the future of consumer tech look like?
The Sony Hack – Palmer says: "The Sony hack was not about freedom of speech, but simply about freedom. For centuries, we have used monarchs, heads of state, religion, and political systems to control each other. Any or all of these methods of control seem feeble when compared to the ability of motivated hackers to do harm."
Hide Caption
7 of 8
8 photos: What does the future of consumer tech look like?
Apple iWatch – Wearable tech, such as Apple's iWatch, is growing fast and will gather data about our lives. "Remember, everything that can be connected, will be connected," says Palmer.
Hide Caption
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
