<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Technology</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/TECH/index.html?eref=rss_tech</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2016 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 20:40:10 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 20:40:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Technology</title>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/TECH/index.html?eref=rss_tech</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<item>
<title>Opinion: Cuba's Internet isolation beginning to lift</title>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676977/s/4d85076f/sc/13/l/0L0Scnn0N0C20A160C0A20C10A0Copinions0Ccuba0Einternet0Eisolation0Etummino0Cindex0Bhtml0Deref0Frss0Itech/story01.htm</link>
<description>Cuba's announcement of launching broadband Internet service in two pilot projects in Havana is historic.&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247391214084/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4d85076f/sc/13/rc/1/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247391214084/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4d85076f/sc/13/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247391214084/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4d85076f/sc/13/rc/2/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247391214084/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4d85076f/sc/13/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247391214084/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4d85076f/sc/13/rc/3/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247391214084/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4d85076f/sc/13/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247391214084/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4d85076f/sc/13/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247391214084/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4d85076f/sc/13/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247391214084/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4d85076f/sc/13/ach.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247391214084/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4d85076f/sc/13/ach.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/247391214084/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4d85076f/sc/13/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi2.feedsportal.com/r/247391214084/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4d85076f/sc/13/a2t2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676977/s/4d85076f/sc/13/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 13:24:05 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2016/02/10/opinions/cuba-internet-isolation-tummino/index.html</guid>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/150814064549-cuba-thumbs-up-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" lang="" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/150814064549-cuba-thumbs-up-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>Celebrate new day for U.S-Cuba relations
Cubans are thirsty for the ability to connect within their country and to the outside world, and they can currently access the Internet in a few different -- albeit limited and expensive -- ways. Empresa de Telecomunicaciones de Cuba S.A., the government-owned telecommunications service provider for Cuba that offers telephone, Internet and wireless services has continued to increase some access.
Dozens of new Internet access points have been created, WiFi hot spots continue to grow -- with 65 hot spots by the end of 2015 and the announcement to add 80 more in 2016 -- and state-run Internet cafes have tried to lower prices.  And while costs at Internet cafes dropped from $4.50 an hour to $2 an hour -- with WiFi hot spots at the same price point -- that is still a high price to pay given the average monthly salary of $20 or $25 a month.
So will we continue to see progress? Cubans themselves laid out their own national development strategy in June 2015 to allow for broadband Internet connection to citizens and businesses across the country. The more noteworthy objectives include replacing the current dial-up systems with broadband Internet connection and connecting 50% of households with this broadband Internet by 2020. Another goal details the plan to connect 90% of business organizations -- both state and nonstate enterprises -- by 2020, and increase mobile broadband connectivity. Last week's announcement seems like the first step in achieving these goals.
Public Wi-Fi comes to Cuba, at least in 35 spots
With Cuba in the spotlight since the December 17, 2014, rapprochement with the United States, pressure has only increased for the small island nation to expand its Internet access. The telecommunications sector has been an important part, or more precisely, a key pillar of President Barack Obama's opening to Cuba, dating back to executive actions for this sector in 2009. The President's commitment has grown exponentially since the December 17 announcement through a continuous relaxation of regulations in this sector. And it's clear why: Cubans' ability to connect, both with each other and to the outside world, is key to the goals of empowering and engaging more fully with the Cuban people.
To witness Cubans connecting in one of the new WiFi hot spots , video chatting with relatives abroad and sending photos to their friends in Miami is momentous.
Expanding this access is essential. The real measure of success of broadband rollout will be when the average Cuban can connect to affordable and accessible Internet -- reaching well beyond homesick business travelers and authorized government users. But the task ahead is a big one.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
