<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2014 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 08:57:44 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_sport" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_sport"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Cricket hit by new tragedy</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://edition.cnn.com/2014/11/30/sport/cricket-israeli-umpire-hughes/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~3/gj5b9QL97v8/index.html</link>
<description>Cricket has been hit by another tragedy in the same week Australian Test star Phillip Hughes died as result as a result of injuries he received after being struck by a ball in a match in Sydney.&lt;img src="//feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~4/gj5b9QL97v8" height="1" width="1" alt=""/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2014 15:33:53 EST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141130201526-dead-umpire-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141130201526-dead-umpire-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<feedburner:origLink>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/11/30/sport/cricket-israeli-umpire-hughes/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Cricket hit by fresh tragedy as umpire killed in freak accident
By Paul Gittings, CNN
November 30, 2014 -- Updated 2028 GMT (0428 HKT)
Oscar Hillel (center) was a highly respected figure in Israel cricket and was still playing as well as undertaking umpiring duties.
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
Cricket umpire dies after freak accident in game in Israel
Hillel Oscar, 60, hit by ball which ricocheted off the stumps
Oscar was former captain of Israeli national team
Australian Test star Phillip Hughes died earlier in week after being hit by a ball
Follow us at @WorldSportCNN and like us on Facebook
(CNN) -- Cricket has been hit by another tragedy in the same week Australian Test star Phillip Hughes died as result as a result of injuries he received after being struck by a ball in a match in Sydney.
Hillel Oscar, 60, a former captain of the Israeli national team, was umpiring a match Saturday in his home town of Ashdod when he received an apparently fatal blow in a freak accident.
Before the match between Young Ashdod and Super Lions Lod, the final game of the Israel domestic season, players and officials had held a minute's silence for Hughes, whose untimely death has led to a string of tributes across the world.
Cricketer Phil Hughes dies
CEO: No one loved cricket more than Phil
Expert: Hughes' death an expensive lesson
Australia shocked by cricketer's death
Super Lions Lod was also to be given the championship trophy at the end of the match, but as Steve Leigh, the Deputy Chairman of the Israeli Cricket Association told CNN, that celebration was never to happen.
Leigh was not at the match, but recounted what he had been told of the tragic incident.
"Midway through the first innings a ball was driven fiercely back towards the umpire (by the batsman).
"It hit the stumps and ricocheted but as Hillel tried to move out of the way the ball followed him and he was hit in the chest or just under the chin, it is still unclear exactly where.
Read: Worldwide bat tribute for tragic Hughes
"He collapsed immediately and according to witnesses who were there he may have had a heart attack."
Leigh said that the umpire was resuscitated by ambulance staff who were quickly on the scene, but he died later at a hospital in Ashdod.
Englishman Leigh, 51, said the Israeli cricketing community had been left stunned by the incident. "Hillel was much loved by everyone," he said
The Israel Cricket Association's CEO, Naor Gudker, paid his tribute on its official Facebook page.
"The entire Israel Cricket Association and players bow their heads in his memory. He was a wonderful man, cricketer, and umpire," Gudker said.
Oscar, who was born in Bombay, was married with two daughters and a grandchild. His funeral was being held in Ashdod Sunday.
Read: Hughes' death: How we crave danger
Meanwhile Leigh said the association would co-operate fully with any official investigation into the incident, liaising with world governing body, the ICC.
Unlike in sports such as baseball, cricket umpires are unprotected and do not wear helmets, despite the high speeds which the ball can be struck by batsman.
But fatal incidents involving either players or umpires are extremely rare.
An umpire at a match in Wales was killed five years ago after a ball thrown by a fielder hit him on the head.
In the light of the recent accident, Leigh said that "maybe there was need" for umpires to wear helmets.
Unlike Australia, Israel is not considered a major cricketing power, but there are several thousand active participants at all levels, with an 18-strong national league.
Most of the adult players were originally born, like Oscar, in traditional cricket playing countries such as India, where it is the national sport.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
