<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2016 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 12:26:56 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 12:26:56 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<item>
<title>Bubba keen to 'man up'</title>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676991/s/4dc9d0ad/sc/13/l/0Ledition0Bcnn0N0C20A160C0A20C230Cgolf0Cbubba0Ewatson0Ehead0Ecase0Cindex0Bhtml0Deref0Frss0Isport/story01.htm</link>
<description>&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392483242/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dc9d0ad/sc/13/rc/1/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392483242/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dc9d0ad/sc/13/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392483242/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dc9d0ad/sc/13/rc/2/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392483242/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dc9d0ad/sc/13/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392483242/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dc9d0ad/sc/13/rc/3/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392483242/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dc9d0ad/sc/13/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392483242/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dc9d0ad/sc/13/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392483242/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dc9d0ad/sc/13/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392483242/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dc9d0ad/sc/13/ach.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392483242/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dc9d0ad/sc/13/ach.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/247392483242/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dc9d0ad/sc/13/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi2.feedsportal.com/r/247392483242/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dc9d0ad/sc/13/a2t2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676991/s/4dc9d0ad/sc/13/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 12:57:26 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://edition.cnn.com/2016/02/23/golf/bubba-watson-head-case/index.html</guid>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160223102454-bubba-watson-9th-win-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" lang="" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160223102454-bubba-watson-9th-win-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>Rory McIlroy: 'I'd take Masters win over Olympic gold'
Read More
"Five years ago (the doctor) said there was one more in my system and obviously it decided this week," he told reporters. "My baby came out, I guess.
"Again, no pain. And I'm already a head case, so my thoughts of seeing red liquids coming out, I thought I was dying, basically, without pain."
On Wednesday, Bubba and Bieber met up when the musician offered his three-year-old son Caleb a drumming lesson, while Watson's TV debut came as a result of a previous meeting with the cast of "Boy Meets World."
"I've got 48 episodes of Boy Meets World on my phone," said Watson. "When I'm on the airplane, that's what I watch. It's a good quality show. You learn a lesson. They were not going to give me a line and then they gave me line. That was $900."
— bubba watson (@bubbawatson) February 16, 2016
On Saturday night, while holding the third-round lead, Watson attended the Los Angeles Clippers vs. Golden State Warriors basketball game at the Staples Center. And on Sunday he beat Adam Scott and Jason Kokrak by a shot for a second Riviera win in three years.
Watson's week encapsulates his world. One minute an open, engaging character, the next a prickly, controversial maverick.
Rickie Fowler: Golfer forms new 'Fab Four'
The self-taught swinger, who wields his pink driver with venom, admitted he was still struggling with the aftermath of comments he made at the recent Phoenix Open when he criticized the course redevelopments.
He claims the headlines said he didn't like the tournament or the community, which Watson calls a "lie." And he admits he struggles at times with his place in the world.
"I'm pretty mad about it, but I've got to get over it," said Watson, whose real name is Gerry. "I've got to man up and be a better man, and with those comments, I've got to figure out how to answer things better.
"You know, all the stuff going on in my head we've been working on in the last 11 years of PGA Tour life, I've got to get better at it, but the bad stuff is going to pop out every once in a while.
"I have a lot of fears in my life, which as I'm reading the Bible, I'm not supposed to have, but I do. I'm human.
"And a lot of those fears come out on the golf course: Big crowds, people touching me, people yelling at me. Just, I want to go and hide."
Watson's win, which suggests talk of a new Big Three in golf may be premature, takes him to within one victory of his stated goal of 10 PGA Tour titles.
The Floridian said earlier this year he would retire at 10 -- or reaching world No. 1 , whichever comes first -- but the two-time U.S. Masters champion continues to confound.
"Yes, I would definitely consider it," he repeated on Sunday. But he also added: "The goal setting is always there. When I get to 10 wins, then we'll bump it up a few. We won't go another 10.
"[But] they are going to have to kick me off Augusta."
6 photos: Bubba Watson: Masters career in pictures
Bubba Watson conjured a miraculous hook out of the trees on Augusta's 10th hole in the play-off against Louis Oosthuizen to set up his first Masters title in 2012.
Hide Caption
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
