<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2016 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 17:37:09 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 17:37:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<item>
<title>Tiger: Agent dismisses setback reports</title>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676991/s/4dca7db8/sc/13/l/0Ledition0Bcnn0N0C20A160C0A20C230Cgolf0Ctiger0Ewoods0Eagent0Edismisses0Einjury0Eclaims0Cindex0Bhtml0Deref0Frss0Isport/story01.htm</link>
<description>Tiger Woods' agent has rubbished speculation the 14-time major champion is struggling to move and is in pain sitting down as he recovers from his third back surgery.&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392515541/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dca7db8/sc/13/rc/1/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392515541/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dca7db8/sc/13/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392515541/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dca7db8/sc/13/rc/2/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392515541/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dca7db8/sc/13/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392515541/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dca7db8/sc/13/rc/3/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392515541/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dca7db8/sc/13/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392515541/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dca7db8/sc/13/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392515541/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dca7db8/sc/13/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392515541/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dca7db8/sc/13/ach.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392515541/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dca7db8/sc/13/ach.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/247392515541/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dca7db8/sc/13/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi2.feedsportal.com/r/247392515541/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dca7db8/sc/13/a2t2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676991/s/4dca7db8/sc/13/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 12:56:40 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://edition.cnn.com/2016/02/23/golf/tiger-woods-agent-dismisses-injury-claims/index.html</guid>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/151202133700-tiger-woods-sad-tease-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" lang="" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/151202133700-tiger-woods-sad-tease-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>Facebook Twitter Instagram
&lt;div class="banner" id="cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0_banner"&gt;&lt;span id="cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" class="_fwph"&gt;&lt;form id="_fw_form_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" style="display:none"&gt;&lt;input type="hidden" name="_fw_input_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" id="_fw_input_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" value="ptgt=s&amp;envp=g_js&amp;w=300&amp;h=250&amp;slau=300x250_sync&amp;adUnit=300x250_sync"&gt;&lt;/form&gt;&lt;span id="_fw_container_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" class="cn-shingle__ad"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Tiger Woods: Golfer is ...  'progressing nicely'
Updated 1451 GMT (2251 HKT) February 24, 2016
24 photos: Tiger Woods: From highs to lows
Tiger Woods had a third back operation in October 2015 in an attempt to alleviate nerve trouble, and says he has no idea when he will be returning to action.
Hide Caption
1 of 24
24 photos: Tiger Woods: From highs to lows
The 14-time major winner has a long history of injury problems. Here he has cream rubbed into his back by former caddy Steve Williams during the 2004 American Express Championship.
Hide Caption
2 of 24
24 photos: Tiger Woods: From highs to lows
Woods' best result of an injury-hit 2015 was a tie for 10th at August's Wyndham Championship -- his last appearance this season before having back surgery.
Hide Caption
3 of 24
24 photos: Tiger Woods: From highs to lows
In July 2015, Woods missed the cut at the British Open for just the second time in his illustrious career.
Hide Caption
4 of 24
24 photos: Tiger Woods: From highs to lows
Woods throws his club in disgust following a shot from the rough during the first round of the 2015 U.S. Open at Chambers Bay in June, when he missed the halfway cut after rounds of 80 and 76.
Hide Caption
5 of 24
24 photos: Tiger Woods: From highs to lows
Woods and Lindsey Vonn announced they were dating on Facebook in March 2013. In January that year, the champion skier had finalized her divorce from Thomas Vonn, after initializing proceedings in 2011. Woods split up with his wife, Elin Nordegren, in 2010 after admitting a series of infidelities.
Hide Caption
6 of 24
24 photos: Tiger Woods: From highs to lows
Woods and Vonn announced their breakup in May 2015, with the golfer claiming he "hadn't slept" in the days following.
Hide Caption
7 of 24
24 photos: Tiger Woods: From highs to lows
Woods winces in pain after striking a tree root with his club after a shot from the rough in the final round of the 2015 Masters Tournament in April. He finished tied for 17th.
Hide Caption
8 of 24
24 photos: Tiger Woods: From highs to lows
In 2013, Woods regained the No. 1 spot in world golf rankings with a win at the Arnold Palmer Invitational.
Hide Caption
9 of 24
24 photos: Tiger Woods: From highs to lows
In October 2010, Woods appears dejected after losing a match to Lee Westwood and Luke Donald in the Ryder Cup teams competition in Wales. Later that month he lost his No. 1 ranking to Westwood, a position he had held for 281 consecutive weeks. He had taken a break from golf earlier that year after reports of marital infidelities emerged in late 2009.
Hide Caption
10 of 24
24 photos: Tiger Woods: From highs to lows
Woods misses a putt at the Frys.com Open in October 2011. That month, he dropped out of golf's top 50 for the first time in almost 15 years. Woods reportedly lost millions in endorsements after sponsors ended their ties with him in the wake of his sex scandal.
Hide Caption
11 of 24
24 photos: Tiger Woods: From highs to lows
Woods missed the U.S. Open in July 2011, citing knee and Achilles tendon injuries . He won the tournament in 2008 -- his last major victory to date.
Hide Caption
12 of 24
24 photos: Tiger Woods: From highs to lows
Despite his problems, Woods remained a key attraction -- being invited to the 2011 Australian Open, where he finished third. That year he was the highest-paid American athlete on Sports Illustrated's "Fortunate 50" list .
Hide Caption
13 of 24
24 photos: Tiger Woods: From highs to lows
In July 2011, Woods dropped Williams, his caddy of 12 years. "I want to express my deepest gratitude to Stevie for all his help, but I think it's time for a change," Woods said . Here, the two share a laugh during a practice round two months before Williams was let go.
Hide Caption
14 of 24
24 photos: Tiger Woods: From highs to lows
After a nearly three-month break, Woods returned to golf at the Bridgestone Invitational in August 2011.
Hide Caption
15 of 24
24 photos: Tiger Woods: From highs to lows
In August 2011, Woods failed to make the cut at the PGA Championship for the first time in his career. He has won the season's closing major on four occasions, most recently in 2007.
Hide Caption
16 of 24
24 photos: Tiger Woods: From highs to lows
In October 2011, Woods landed Rolex as a sponsor despite not having won a major tournament in nearly two years. "Rolex is convinced that Tiger Woods still has a long career ahead of him," the high-end watchmaker said. The following month he played for the U.S. in the Presidents Cup in Melbourne, Australia.
Hide Caption
17 of 24
24 photos: Tiger Woods: From highs to lows
Woods lines up his putt at the Honda Classic in March 2012. He shot a 62, his lowest final round as a professional , but he tied for second in the PGA Tour event.
Hide Caption
18 of 24
24 photos: Tiger Woods: From highs to lows
In December 2011, Woods earned his first win in two years at the Chevron World Challenge , a charity tournament that he hosts which does not count on the PGA Tour money list.
Hide Caption
19 of 24
24 photos: Tiger Woods: From highs to lows
Woods signs autographs at the Arnold Palmer Invitational in March 2012. His win there marked his first PGA Tour victory since September 2009.
Hide Caption
20 of 24
24 photos: Tiger Woods: From highs to lows
Woods drops the ball on the 15th fairway during the final round of the AT&amp;T National in July 2012. He overtook Jack Nicklaus for second place on the all-time PGA Tour victory list and now has 79 overall -- three behind Sam Snead's record.
Hide Caption
21 of 24
24 photos: Tiger Woods: From highs to lows
Woods hits his tee shot on the 12th hole during the final round of the Farmers Insurance Open at Torrey Pines in January 2013. He lost his title the previous year as the world's top-paid athlete , dropping to third place on Sports Illustrated's "Fortunate 50" list .
Hide Caption
22 of 24
24 photos: Tiger Woods: From highs to lows
In 2012, Woods became the first PGA Tour player to earn $100 million when he finished third at the Deutsche Bank Championship, taking home more than $500,000 .
Hide Caption
23 of 24
24 photos: Tiger Woods: From highs to lows
Woods tosses his ball to his caddy at the Farmers Insurance Open at Torrey Pines in January 2013, when he won his 75th PGA Tour title.
Hide Caption
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
