<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2014 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 08:57:44 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_sport" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_sport"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Cricket: Abbott returns. With a bouncer</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://edition.cnn.com/2014/12/08/sport/cricket-sean-abbott-australia-hoggard/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~3/D0cG8rxiorw/index.html</link>
<description>Australia began its first match since the death of Phil Hughes. Also back in action in a different game, the man who bowled that fateful ball.&lt;img src="//feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~4/D0cG8rxiorw" height="1" width="1" alt=""/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 23:47:20 EST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141208214309-sean-abbott-bowling-hughes-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141208214309-sean-abbott-bowling-hughes-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<feedburner:origLink>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/12/08/sport/cricket-sean-abbott-australia-hoggard/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Family and friends mourn cricket star
CEO: No one loved cricket more than Phil
Phil Hughes laid to rest
And that's what happened when Australian Sean Abbott returned to action, bowling competitively for the first time since delivering the 'bouncer' that resulted in the death of Phillip Hughes late last month.
The New South Wales (NSW) player on Tuesday came on at the 12th over to applause from the small crowd at the Sydney Cricket Ground (SGC) -- the same venue as the November 25 incident -- in the first session of a domestic four-day match against Queensland.
The over included a bouncer, his fifth ball.
Abbot went on to take two wickets and NSW bowling coach Geoff Lawson praised the 22-year-old's resilience.
"He's practiced well, he's looked good but you never know what's underneath the surface with young guys," said Lawson.
"But the proof is in the pudding -- he got onto this field and he did the business. He's a young guy on the way up and he played like it today so I guess his mindset is a pretty good one."
New South Wales players had black armbands on, in memory of Hughes.
"Abbott is doing the right thing by getting back on the pitch as soon as possible," Matthew Hoggard, who played for England between 2000-2008, told CNN prior to the start of Tuesday's game.
"If, in his first over, he can bowl a bouncer -- just to get rid of the stigma -- then he should.
"It would help get the horrible memory out of his mind."
"The longer he goes on without bowling a bouncer, the worse it will get. He needs to get back to bowling like he did."
Australia and India pay tribute
The Australian Test team also took to the field competitively, as the postponed First Test against India also began on Tuesday in Adelaide.
Prior to the game, players and coaching staff from both sides assembled on the field to honor Phil Hughes. Hughes was named as the 13th man for the match. A tribute by former Australian cricket captain and legendary commentary Richie Benaud played out followed by 63 seconds of applause.
Hughes, who had been tipped to earn an international recall for the Test, had made 63 runs when he received the delivery that shocked and rocked the cricketing world.
The Australian players all wore Hughes' Test cap number, 408, on their shirts as well as black armbands.
#SeanAbbott embraces family at Lunch been sat next to them and by far the loudest in the crowd. #cricketunited pic.twitter.com/mnO2xwUMsG
— Charlie Gibson (@CharlieMooseGib) December 9, 2014
In the build up, one of Australia's lead bowlers has said he will not be changing his approach against India, following an incident that has been frequently been described as 'freak' by those within the game.
"I've been bowling very aggressive for the last 18 months and I'm not going to change that," Mitchell Johnson told reporters.
However, the paceman was left in a more quizzical mood when asked how he would react if one of his short-pitched deliveries were to hit an Indian batsman.
"I'm not sure," he replied. "It might be (a) different (reaction) this time."
Hughes' domestic team, South Australia, took on Tasmania in Hobart. It was the first time also his former teammates had taken to the field since his death. Both teams paused for 63 seconds before the start of play to remember Hughes. According to local ABC media, the South Australian playets had "PH 612" etched on their shirts , in reference to Hughes' South Australian cap number.
Read: Australia captain moves world to tears with eulogy
A bouncer is an aggressive delivery, pitched short and fast with a good ball rearing up at the batsman's upper torso and head. Abbott's ball to Hughes hit the batsman on the back of the head -- Hughes slumped to the floor and lost consciousness seconds after he was hit near his left ear. He was stretchered off the ground, put into an induced coma at hospital and and later died.
'Appalling incident'
'His best cricket was still ahead of him'
Australian Test cricket captain Michael Clarke reacts as he arrives for the funeral of Australian batsman Phil Hughes in his hometown of Macksville in northern New South Wales on December 3, 2014. Hughes died November 27, two days after being hit by a cricket ball during a match.
Australia Prime Minister Tony Abbott (right) arrives for the funeral of Australian cricket batsman Phil Hughes in Macksville, northern New South Wales on December 3.
Australian cricketer Mitchell Johnson arrives to Coffs Harbour ahead of today's funeral service for Phil Hughes on December 3.
Pallbearers carry the coffin of Australian batsman Phil Hughes ahead of his funeral in his home town of Macksville in northern New South Wales on December 3.
A schoolgirl walks past a tribute to Australian batsman Phil Hughes before his funeral to be held in his home town of Macksville.
Cricket bats and signs are placed outside St. Patrick's Primary School hours before the funeral of Australian batsman Phil Hughes.
Newcastle fans applaud in memory of Phil Hughes at the 63 minute mark during the an A-League soccer match between the Newcastle Jets and Central Coast Mariners on November 30 in Newcastle, Australia. Hughes' was injured while on 63 not out, charging the number with symbolism for mourners.
New Zealand cricket teams the Otago Volts and Wellington Firebirds place a bat, cap and black armband on the University Oval in Dunedin in memory of Australian cricketer Phil Hughes. Hughes was the 408th player to play Test cricket for Australia when he made his debut in 2009.
The Australian rugby team run onto the pitch beside a cricket bat and Australian mascot left in tribute to Australian cricketer Phil Hughes at Twickenham Stadium, southwest of London on November 29.
"Phil was the new young gun in Aussie cricket who had burst onto the scene," wrote Nick Compton of his friend Phil Hughes.
Hughes made 26 Test appearances for Australia, hitting 1535 runs at an average of 32.66.
In 2009, the 20-year-old became the youngest international cricketer to ever hit back-to-back centuries, achieving the feat against South Africa in Durban.
Hughes was named Australia's Domestic Player of the Year in 2013.
Remembering Phil Hughes
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
