<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2014 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 10:09:24 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>The greatest beards in history</title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/08/world/the-greatest-beards-in-history/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/08/world/the-greatest-beards-in-history/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>When it comes to facial hair, there are few more passionate advocates than Phil Olsen.</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 11:10:59 EDT</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/140929113407-beards-grey-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/140929113407-beards-grey-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>World Beard and Mustache Championships took place in Portland, Oregon
One analyst says a beard has always been a powerful social symbol
Will bearding continue to rise, or is it due for a fall? Opinions differ
(CNN) -- When it comes to facial hair, there are few more passionate advocates than Phil Olsen.
As the "founder and self-appointed captain" of Beard Team USA, he was responsible for bringing the sport of competitive bearding to the United States in 2003.
Since then, things have, well, grown.
"It really is quite amazing," Olsen said from his home in California. "Interest in bearding worldwide has taken off.
"You see more and more facial hair everywhere you look, and every time, it feels like a little victory for me. Men are finally liberating themselves."
The weird world of 'competitive bearding'
Olsen is one of the "bearders" behind the World Beard and Mustache Championships , which took place in Portland, Oregon, this weekend. Hundreds competed in categories including "full beard natural," "full beard styled mustache," "imperial" and "freestyle."
Interest in bearding worldwide has taken off.
Phil Olsen, Beard Team USA founder
"Men are competitive. It's in our very nature," Olsen said this month. "So why shouldn't we compete over our beards? It is our uniquely masculine quality, the one thing we can do that most women can't."
The scale of this event is emblematic of the huge resurgence in beard cultivation over recent years.
For Olsen -- who himself sports a 12-inch sculpted Wookiee of a thing -- this burgeoning masculine hairiness is driven by sexual politics.
"For centuries, men have been pressured by women to scrape their faces daily so that they would look more like women," he says.
"Finally, we have come around to realizing that we should express our masculinity in the natural way, by growing a beard."
So how does he feel about men who shave?
Long, short, tamed or wild - beards have taken a multitude of forms throughout the years. Despite their long and turbulent history, beards are more popular than at any other time in living memory. Xtopher Grey, pictured, is a prominent competitive beard grower.
Over 300 "bearders" are expected to attend the 2014 beard and mustache championships in Oregon, a testament to the rising popularity of competitive beard-cultivation. The competitor Nate Johnson, pictured, has developed a partitioned beard that cascades down to the middle of his chest, a style that requires high levels of maintenance and commitment.
A beard that defies gravity? Mike Johnson is a well-known competitor on the bearding circuit. His type of beard is slender and is arched upwards or is fixed straight up. Aids, in this category, are permitted.
Al Underwood competes in the Musketeer category. The Musketeer mustache is long and slim while the beard is kept small and pointed. Eyepatch optional.
Gentlemen sporting mustaches, as opposed to the full beard, are allowed to compete as well, though many full-bearders view them with suspicion. For Brooke Mahnen, one of the contestants in this category, quantities of wax play a key role in his success.
The Los Angeles-based photographer Jeffrey Moustache is mustache by name, mustache by nature. Well, by nurture actually. He has been rumored to spend a great deal of time sculpting his man-hair, ensuring that both beard and mustache exist in a state of perfect balance and harmony.
Some competitors, such as Ben Ratell, pursue the immaculate beard, which has been lovingly tamed and groomed over many years.
Others, like Big Joe Johnson, believe that their masculinity is better expressed by the no-holds-barred approach, in which the beard is allowed to grow freely as an expression of what it is to be a man.
Care must be taken over the context in which the beard is presented -- in other words, the style of hair worn on the head. Devin Cara chooses to shave his pate in order to lend his impressive auburn beard maximum impact.
Whenever Dennis Dickerson comes to town, comparisons with Colonel Sanders -- of Kentucky Fried Chicken fame -- are never far behind. Yet he is another well-known competitor, as he is able to impress with his elegant and relatively understated goatee style, which is enhanced by a naturally occurring, horizontal wave.
Many modern-day bearders derive inspiration from the glories of the past. Ambrose Burnside (1824-1881), the American industrialist and politician, was the grandfather of the sideburn and is an iconic figure in the bearded community.
Another important figure in the folklore of facial hair was a pirate called Captain Edward Teach (1680-1718), also known as Blackbeard. He plundered the coasts of the West Indies, North Carolina and Virginia, and was said to weave flaming fuses into his beard to intimidate his enemies.
Karl Marx (1818 - 1883), the radical German social, political and economic theorist, has become synonymous with the chest-length gray beard, complemented by a mane of salt-and-pepper hair.
There have been many examples over the years of famous men becoming indivisible from their facial hair in the public mind. Spanish surrealist artist Salvador Dali was famed for his slim mustache that twirled eccentrically upwards. It is said that at the height of his fame, a letter would be delivered to his home if it was posted simply with a picture of his mustache on the front.
The Russian mystic Grigory Yefimovich Rasputin used his unkempt beard and long hair to signify an otherworldly spirituality. In the context of Russian Orthodox Christianity, this was perceived as a mark of holiness. Russian Orthodox priests vow not to cut their hair or beards as a way of repelling the opposite sex. Their pledge states: "I promise to wear the clothing appropriate to my priestly rank, not to cut my hair nor my beard... for through such unseemly behavior I risk belittling my rank and tempting believers."
Maharishi Mahesh Yogi, founder of the Transcendental Meditation (TM) movement and a spiritual adviser to the Beatles, is pictured with his iconic long, gray, pointed beard. Indeed, in terms of his association with the style he is second only to Gandalf.
For the British musician John Lennon, the beard was a sign of an anti-establishment commitment to "peace and love". Here he is pictured with his Japanese wife, Yoko Ono. Lennon started growing his beard at the beginning of 1969, around the time that he got married, thus supporting the observation that men often grow beards to mark life changing events.
The shaving habits of movie stars and musicians are always in the public eye. Before his wedding to Amal Alamuddin, George Clooney broke hearts and enraged fans with his changeable facial hair. (Now they have bigger things to worry about.)
Even the renowned American actor and sex symbol Gregory Peck was not immune from the allures of facial hair. Here he is pictured in 1954 wearing a startling beard especially grown for the film 'Moby Dick'.
ZZ Top are the indisputable kings of the rock 'n' roll beard. Ironically, the drummer, who has rarely ventured beyond the mustache, has the pogonophiliac name Frank Beard.
Friedrich Nietzsche (1844-1900), the German philosopher, was famous for his walrus mustache, which became increasingly unruly in his later life as his mental health unraveled.
Another famous proponent of the walrus mustache was the American writer Mark Twain.
George V (1865-1936), king of the United Kingdom between 1910 and 1936, was synonymous with the lavish mustache supported by a pointed beard. To this day, beard enthusiasts believe that his achievement will never be equaled, let alone surpassed.
In Victorian England, large beards were often associated with the intelligentsia. And they don't come much more intellectual than Charles Darwin (1809-1882), the grandfather of evolution.
Archduke Franz Ferdinand, whose assassination sparked the First World War, was known for his statesmanlike, curled mustache.
The American gunslinger Wyatt Earp (1848-1929) favored a drooping mustache that made him a style icon long after his death.
Hubert Carter (1869-1934), the great English star of stage and screen, did much to build the link between unruly facial hair and the wild-eyed Thespian. He is pictured in 1910 with a long, curly, cascading beard.
A beard is often seen as expressive of a man's unique character. A promotional still for 'The Adventurer', written and directed by Charlie Chaplin in 1917, reveals two very different beard styles adorning two very different men. Chaplin (far right) is almost completely clean shaven, with his trademark patch of hair on his upper lip. Meanwhile, Eric Campbell (far left), an actor and close associate of Chaplain who invariably played the villain, showcases a sinister, Gothic-inspired beard with twirled eyebrows.
Something to tickle your fancy?
Something to tickle your fancy?
Something to tickle your fancy?
Something to tickle your fancy?
Something to tickle your fancy?
Something to tickle your fancy?
Something to tickle your fancy?
Something to tickle your fancy?
Something to tickle your fancy?
Something to tickle your fancy?
Something to tickle your fancy?
Something to tickle your fancy?
Something to tickle your fancy?
Something to tickle your fancy?
Something to tickle your fancy?
Something to tickle your fancy?
Something to tickle your fancy?
Something to tickle your fancy?
Something to tickle your fancy?
Something to tickle your fancy?
Something to tickle your fancy?
Something to tickle your fancy?
Something to tickle your fancy?
Something to tickle your fancy?
Something to tickle your fancy?
Something to tickle your fancy?
Something to tickle your fancy?
Something to tickle your fancy?
HIDE CAPTION
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
