<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2013 20:08:10 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_entertainment" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_entertainment"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Stars rock short hair</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2013/11/06/showbiz/celebrity-news-gossip/stars-short-haircuts/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~3/xroe6vwh2l4/index.html</link>
<description>&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~4/xroe6vwh2l4" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2013 13:13:10 EST</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.cnn.com/2013/11/06/showbiz/celebrity-news-gossip/stars-short-haircuts/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Cropping up: Stars rock short hair
By Breeanna Hare, CNN
November 6, 2013 -- Updated 2236 GMT (0636 HKT)
Jennifer Lawrence surprised fans on November 6 when she revealed that her long hair had been chopped off to a pixie style. She's not the only star who's stunned the public with nothing more than a haircut -- take a look at these other stars who've gone short.
Jennifer Aniston, who set trends when "Friends" was on the air with her character Rachel, is now following them. The actress didn't go quite as short as many others have, but she did trim her locks down to an "un-precious" bob.
The pixie cut has become so popular even Pamela Anderson, whose fame for long locks dates all the way back to her "Baywatch" days, has adopted the look.
In late October, Jennifer Hudson joined the short hair bandwagon as well.
We're used to seeing Beyoncé with long hair, so when the singer debuted a super-short pixie cut in August, the world paused to take notice.
Halle Berry's short hair has become so closely associated with her that she often likes to change it for movie roles. For "The Call," she chose to wear a curly wig that many observers didn't love, but it was part of the job. "It's becoming harder and harder for actors to escape who they really are and have people suspend belief," she said. "For me, the first thing that has to go is (my) hair."
Emma Watson spent 10 years playing Hermione Granger in the "Harry Potter" franchise, so when the series ended she also said good-bye to Hermione's long hair. The cut paid off for Watson, though -- it was named the most influential hairstyle of 2011.
Keira Knightley's has grazed past her shoulders, but in 2004 she chopped it off into a pixie for the movie "Domino."
If you walk into a salon and ask for the "Mia Farrow," the stylist will know exactly what you're talking about. Farrow's '60s pixie is iconic -- and it's also one she cut herself. The actress told the New York Times in a letter to the editor that she shaped her 'do with a pair of fingernail scissors while working on 1964's "Peyton Place," and then went shorter at the hands of Vidal Sassoon for "Rosemary's Baby."
Victoria Beckham is known for sharp lines, from her clothing to her poses, and her hair plays a part. Although she's been seen wearing it on the longer side occasionally, her short, precise cuts have set trends.
Natalie Portman buzzed off her brunette locks for 2005's "V for Vendetta," and she told USA Today that getting the scene right stressed her out more than losing her hair. The actress showed similar dedication to her gig in 2012, when she went blond for a movie role .
In her "Dawson's Creek" days, Michelle Williams kept her hair pretty long, but when she was dating Heath Ledger she began to prefer the pixie. "I feel like myself with short hair," she said in 2011 . "I cut it for the one straight man who has ever liked short hair and I wear it in memorial of somebody who really loved it."
Rihanna is a style chameleon, going from one hairstyle to the next like she's changing her shoes. But before THE haircut in 2007 -- the asymmetrical bob that signaled her darker, sexier side and inspired copycat cuts -- she wasn't quite as adventurous. It seems revealing herself to be a "Good Girl Gone Bad" began with her hair.
Hair can make or break a career, and a perfect example is British model Twiggy. The star-in-the-making rocked a crop that we still see today. Her 1966 cut was a risk -- but it paid off in a major way.
Without a doubt, Justin Bieber's popularity was boosted by his lush, eyelash-grazing bangs -- the kind that were soon found swooped across the foreheads of adolescent boys in nearly every middle school in America around 2010. But in February 2011, Bieber practically broke the Internet when he revealed a shorter, spikier -- and, to him at least -- "more mature" 'do.
Demi Moore, too, isn't afraid to lose her strands for her job. When she starred in 1997's "G.I. Jane," the actress parted ways with her lustrous locks in favor of a completely shaved -- and thereby, more believable -- head.
Lopping off her hair for 2012's "Les Miserables" made Anne Hathaway cry , as she told Kelly Ripa last year, but she now seems to be loving it. After all, she won an Oscar with that short cut.
Charlize Theron didn't have any tears when she had to go super-short for her role in "Mad Max." The actress said she actually found the new look "freeing," telling Ryan Seacrest at the Oscars in 2013 that she thinks "every woman should do it."
Miley Cyrus' haircut was the snip heard around the world. Although the star eased into the shorter look with a neat bob, her shorter, more daring cut left fans stunned .
Amber Rose's bald look has become her signature -- so much so that a playful photo of the celebrity model in a long blond wig rendered her nearly unrecognizable. But it turns out her cut is inspired by another short-hair standout: Sinead O'Conner. "I knew I wanted to look as beautiful as she did one day, so when I was old enough to make my own decisions, at 19, I cut it off," Rose told Inked magazine in 2011 .
Pink comes off as pretty fearless in general, and that also applies to her hair. The singer has never been afraid to change her cut -- or admit when she hates it -- and that brazen confidence can be inspiring. At the 2012 MTV Video Music Awards, Miley Cyrus clearly took her style guidance from her fellow star.
Carey Mulligan could give "An Education" in cultivating a signature style. While her hair has gone from brunette to blond, her adorable pixie cut has more or less stayed the same without becoming boring.
Ginnifer Goodwin is another actress who is known for wearing short hair with sophistication. Perhaps ironically, one of her top three tips for going short is to learn to embrace the bedhead.
Willow Smith became just as famous as her parents, Will and Jada Pinkett Smith, with her single "Whip My Hair." But the teen star was soon experimenting with a different -- and much shorter -- style. When she got a buzz cut in 2012, her mom was a supporter : "Willow cut her hair because her beauty, her value, her worth is not measured by the length of her hair."
HIDE CAPTION
Cropping up: Stars rock short hair
Cropping up: Stars rock short hair
Cropping up: Stars rock short hair
Cropping up: Stars rock short hair
Stars rock short hair
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
