<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Technology</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/TECH/index.html?eref=rss_tech</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2013 14:41:49 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Technology</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/TECH/index.html?eref=rss_tech</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_technology" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_technology"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Water-recycling shower cuts bills by over $1,000</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2013/11/11/tech/innovation/futuristic-water-recycling-shower-orbsys/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_technology/~3/SLKrhltL0Ck/index.html</link>
<description>New high-tech shower recycles 90% of water and 80% energy every time you wash&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_technology/~4/SLKrhltL0Ck" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2013 05:31:25 EST</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.cnn.com/2013/11/11/tech/innovation/futuristic-water-recycling-shower-orbsys/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Futuristic water-recycling shower cuts bills by over $1,000
By Stefanie Blendis and Monique Rivalland, for CNN
November 11, 2013 -- Updated 1951 GMT (0351 HKT) | Filed under: Innovations
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
Swedish designer Mehrdad Mahdjoubi has developed a shower that recycles water
OrbSys Shower saves more than 90% water and 80% energy while you wash
It could save users over $1000 a year and help people living in areas with a shortage of water
(CNN) -- In space, astronauts go for years without a fresh supply of water. Floating in a capsule in outer space they wash and drink from the same continuously recycled source. So why, asked Swedish industrial designer Mehrdad Mahdjoubi, do we not do the same on Earth?
This was the concept behind the OrbSys Shower -- a high-tech purification system that recycles water while you wash. In the eyes of Mahdjoubi, we should start doing it now, before it becomes a necessity.
So how does it work? Similar to space showers, it works on a "closed loop system:" hot water falls from the tap to the drain and is instantly purified to drinking water standard and then pumped back out of the showerhead. As the process is quick, the water remains hot and only needs to be reheated very slightly.
 OrbSys shower recycles water as you wash
OrbSys shower recycles water as you wash
 Inventor claims there is no compromise on water pressure
Inventor claims there is no compromise on water pressure
Exoskeleton gives you super strength
Origami-inspired kayak unfolds from box
This year, his showers were installed for the first time in Ribersborgs Kallbadhus, a coastal bathing house in Sweden. During the summer months more than 1000 bathers come and swim waters rich with plankton, algae and seaweed, before showering off.
"It's not just an exotic environment for application but it's an extreme field test because the showers are on pretty much constantly, for about 10 hours per day... and the feedback has been good."
Read: The smart streetlamps that save energy
At the bathing house, CNN introduced Mahdjoubi to Danish industrial designer Nille Juul- Sørensen, who recently designed Malmo's Triangeln train station. Juul- Sørensen was keen to talk about the wider potential of Mahdjoubi's design: "My interest is not in the objects but in the system. There will be so many applications for this."
If deployed on a bigger scale, the purification technology developed for OrbSys could be used in taps and drinking fountains in the world's developing countries, where water-related illness is rife. "Everybody should save as many resources as possible," says Mahdjoubi, "but obviously these showers would be even more beneficial for people living in areas with water shortages.
"I want to get it to as many people as possible. That's the next step. It's not just about saving water. The motivation is to be smart about how we use our planet's resources."
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
