<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2013 20:08:10 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_entertainment" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_entertainment"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Hollywood's sexy sex scenes</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2013/10/31/showbiz/movies/sex-scenes-movies-gallery/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~3/fYpsPBaIT8Q/index.html</link>
<description>&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~4/fYpsPBaIT8Q" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2013 16:49:26 EDT</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.cnn.com/2013/10/31/showbiz/movies/sex-scenes-movies-gallery/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Gallery: Hollywood's sexy sex scenes
By Lisa Respers France, CNN
October 31, 2013 -- Updated 1752 GMT (0152 HKT)
Adele Exarchopoulos, left, and Lea Seydoux star in "Blue is the Warmest Color," which is drawing lots of attention because of its graphic sex scenes, including one that is more than six minutes long. Here are some other films that fogged the windows.
Graphic sex scenes between Marlon Brando and Maria Schneider in "Last Tango in Paris" shocked the world at the time and initially earned the film an X rating as well as two Academy Award nominations.
The graphic sex scenes between Donald Sutherland and Julie Christie in "Don't Look Now" resulted in an X rating at first and has fans still wondering, did they or didn't they?
"Nine 1/2 Weeks," starring Mickey Rourke and Kim Basinger, wasn't a huge commercial success, and critics didn't love it -- except maybe Roger Ebert -- but had it couples acting out that food scene.
Daniel Day-Lewis and Lena Olin had some sexy scenes in "The Unbearable Lightness of Being."
Gay activists protested "Basic Instinct ," starring Michael Douglas and Sharon Stone, as they felt that the portrayal of her bisexual character was offensive.
Jane March and Tony Leung Ka Fai star as a young girl and her older lover in "The Lover."
Naomi Watts, left, and Laura Harring got hot and heavy in "Mulholland Drive."
Gina Gershon, left, and Jennifer Tilly play lovers in "Bound."
Matt Dillon and Denise Richards helped steam things up in the erotic thriller "Wild Things," which included a menage a trois scene with Neve Campbell.
Tom Cruise and Nicole Kidman were still married when they co-starred in "Eyes Wide Shut," in which iconic director Stanley Kubrick pushed the envelope. Years later, there is still talk about hidden messages.
Halle Berry and Billy Bob Thornton dealt with some heavy emotional issues in "Monsters Ball" while engaging in some passion.
Gael Garcia Bernal, Diego Luna and Maribel Verdu form a passionate trio in "Y Tu Mama Tambien."
"Secretary," starring Maggie Gyllenhaal and James Spader, explores the relationship between a submissive secretary and her boss.
The controversy surrounding a fellatio scene in "The Brown Bunny," starring Vincent Gallo and Chloe Sevigny, reportedly caused the actress some strife.
Heath Ledger, left, and Jake Gyllenhaal share a cowboy love that dare not speak its name in "Brokeback Mountain."
Viggo Mortensen and Maria Bello are a loving couple who face danger in "A History of Violence." But they also don't mind spicing it up with costumes and role play.
Raphael Barker and Sook-Yin Lee star in "Shortbus," about a female sex therapist and a group of sexually adventurous New Yorkers.
Kate Winslet and David Kross played out the heat between a younger man and an older woman in "The Reader."
Mila Kunis reportedly banned her father from watching her sex scene with Natalie Portman in "Black Swan."
HIDE CAPTION
'Last Tango in Paris' (1972)
'Don't Look Now' (1973)
'The Unbearable Lightness of Being' (1988)
'Basic Instinct' (1992)
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
