<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Technology</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/TECH/index.html?eref=rss_tech</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2016 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 20:40:10 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 20:40:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Technology</title>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/TECH/index.html?eref=rss_tech</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<item>
<title>How do you keep kids safe?</title>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676977/s/4d6329a9/sc/33/l/0L0Scnn0N0C20A160C0A20C0A40Chealth0Cinternet0Esafety0Ekids0Esocial0Emedia0Eparents0Cindex0Bhtml0Deref0Frss0Itech/story01.htm</link>
<description>The best Internet safety tip for parents, experts say, is to be involved with their children's digital lives.&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247390587433/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4d6329a9/sc/33/rc/1/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247390587433/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4d6329a9/sc/33/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247390587433/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4d6329a9/sc/33/rc/2/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247390587433/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4d6329a9/sc/33/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247390587433/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4d6329a9/sc/33/rc/3/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247390587433/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4d6329a9/sc/33/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247390587433/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4d6329a9/sc/33/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247390587433/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4d6329a9/sc/33/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247390587433/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4d6329a9/sc/33/ach.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247390587433/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4d6329a9/sc/33/ach.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/247390587433/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4d6329a9/sc/33/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi2.feedsportal.com/r/247390587433/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4d6329a9/sc/33/a2t2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676977/s/4d6329a9/sc/33/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 15:41:23 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2016/02/04/health/internet-safety-kids-social-media-parents/index.html</guid>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/150819135815-dangers-social-media-youtube-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" lang="" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/150819135815-dangers-social-media-youtube-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>Nicole Lovell, 13, may have met her alleged killer online
Best Internet safety tip for parents: Be involved with their children's digital lives, experts say
Kelly Wallace is CNN's digital correspondent and editor-at-large covering family, career and life. Read her other columns and follow her reports at CNN Parents and on Twitter.
(CNN)
There is still so much we don't know about how a 13-year-old Blacksburg, Virginia, girl got to know an 18-year-old Virginia Tech freshman before he allegedly stabbed her to death.
What we do know is a bit more about a possible motive in the death of Nicole Lovell, a middle school student. David Eisenhauer, a college track and field athlete, is thought to have had an inappropriate relationship with Lovell and stabbed her to death because she threatened to expose their relationship, according to a law enforcement official.
But how did they meet? How did the alleged relationship begin?
Signs are pointing toward an online network, after police arrested Eisenhauer based on tips and leads obtained from social media. We also know that Lovell was active on social media, including posting in a Facebook group called Teen Dating and Flirting, which has since been shut down.
Parenting lessons from Child Predator Social Experiment
On New Year's Day, Lovell reportedly posted a selfie in the group, with the comment "cute or nah," which garnered more than 300 responses, most of them in the vicious category. Lovell also was active on the anonymous instant messaging app Kik, according to a neighbor who told The New York Times that Lovell had showed one of her daughters texts she had exchanged with an 18-year-old that she planned to meet the night she disappeared.
Read More
I've reported on parents who just aren't aware of Kik and other social applications that their teens might be using, such as Ask.fm, and how the anonymity on these sites can lead to bullying and other dangerous behavior. So what can parents do to keep their kids safe on social media?
Know what your children are up to
On the one hand, especially after a tragedy like the death of Lovell, you can see how they might want to ban their children from all social media. No engaging, no trouble. But that's not a reality in today's world, when social media is a key way teens socialize and spend their time.
Instead of a ban, parents should show interest in their children's online lives, said Diana Graber, co-founder of CyberWise.org , a digital literacy site for parents, educators, teens and tweens. This is not a new piece of advice, but it bears repeating again and again: Be involved.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
