<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2016 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 12:26:56 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 12:26:56 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<item>
<title>What a shot! 31 amazing sports photos</title>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676991/s/4dca7db7/sc/28/l/0Ledition0Bcnn0N0C20A160C0A20C230Csport0Cgallery0Cwhat0Ea0Eshot0Esports0E0A2230Cindex0Bhtml0Deref0Frss0Isport/story01.htm</link>
<description>&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392515540/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dca7db7/sc/28/rc/1/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392515540/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dca7db7/sc/28/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392515540/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dca7db7/sc/28/rc/2/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392515540/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dca7db7/sc/28/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392515540/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dca7db7/sc/28/rc/3/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392515540/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dca7db7/sc/28/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392515540/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dca7db7/sc/28/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392515540/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dca7db7/sc/28/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392515540/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dca7db7/sc/28/ach.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392515540/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dca7db7/sc/28/ach.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/247392515540/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dca7db7/sc/28/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi2.feedsportal.com/r/247392515540/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dca7db7/sc/28/a2t2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676991/s/4dca7db7/sc/28/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 13:32:36 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://edition.cnn.com/2016/02/23/sport/gallery/what-a-shot-sports-0223/index.html</guid>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160222172310-01-what-a-shot-0223-restricted-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" lang="" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160222172310-01-what-a-shot-0223-restricted-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>What a shot! 31 amazing sports photos
Updated 1134 GMT (1934 HKT) February 23, 2016
31 photos: What a shot! 31 amazing sports photos
Denny Hamlin edges Martin Truex Jr. to win the Daytona 500 on Sunday, February 21. Hamlin won by 0.011 seconds in what was the closest finish in race history.
Hide Caption
1 of 31
31 photos: What a shot! 31 amazing sports photos
Anthony Davis shoots over Marcus Morris during an NBA game in Detroit on Sunday, February 21. Davis had 59 points and 20 rebounds for the New Orleans Pelicans, who won 111-106.
Hide Caption
2 of 31
31 photos: What a shot! 31 amazing sports photos
Sara Errani watches the ball Thursday, February 15, during the quarterfinals of the Dubai Tennis Championships. She would go on to win the tournament.
Hide Caption
3 of 31
31 photos: What a shot! 31 amazing sports photos
Cleveland's Richard Jefferson, left, is fouled by Randy Foye during an NBA game in Oklahoma City on Sunday, February 21.
Hide Caption
4 of 31
31 photos: What a shot! 31 amazing sports photos
American figure skater Alexa Scimeca goes airborne Saturday, February 20, during the Four Continents event in Taipei City, Taiwan. She and Chris Knierim finished second in the pairs competition, behind Sui Wenjing and Han Cong of China.
Hide Caption
5 of 31
31 photos: What a shot! 31 amazing sports photos
Players from the Boston Red Sox work out in Fort Myers, Florida, on Thursday, February 18. Spring training is officially underway for all major-league teams.
Hide Caption
6 of 31
31 photos: What a shot! 31 amazing sports photos
Israel's Adam Edelman completes a skeleton run Thursday, February 18, at the IBSF World Championships in Innsbruck, Austria.
Hide Caption
7 of 31
31 photos: What a shot! 31 amazing sports photos
Victoria Pendleton, left, and Carey Williamson fall off their horses during a steeplechase race in Fakenham, England, on Friday, February 19. Pendleton is a former Olympic cyclist who won the keirin at the 2012 Games.
Hide Caption
8 of 31
31 photos: What a shot! 31 amazing sports photos
Chris Carter competes in the triple jump at the Glasgow Indoor Grand Prix on Saturday, February 20. He finished second behind fellow American Omar Craddock.
Hide Caption
9 of 31
31 photos: What a shot! 31 amazing sports photos
C.J. Hancock, bottom, tries to hold off Ruben Esparza during their Bellator bout in Houston on Friday, February 19. Hancock would win the fight with a rear-naked choke in the third round.
Hide Caption
10 of 31
31 photos: What a shot! 31 amazing sports photos
Argentina's Francesca Baruzzi Farriol loses a ski Tuesday, February 16, during a giant-slalom race at the Winter Youth Olympics. The games were held in Lillehammer, Norway.
Hide Caption
11 of 31
31 photos: What a shot! 31 amazing sports photos
Kobe Bryant is swarmed by San Antonio's Kyle Anderson and Tony Parker during an NBA game in Los Angeles on Friday, February 19.
Hide Caption
12 of 31
31 photos: What a shot! 31 amazing sports photos
Baylor fans react to a foul called against their team during a college basketball game in Waco, Texas, on Tuesday, February 16.
Hide Caption
13 of 31
31 photos: What a shot! 31 amazing sports photos
Zemgus Girgensons falls awkwardly after colliding with a Pittsburgh player in Buffalo, New York, on Saturday, February 21.
Hide Caption
14 of 31
31 photos: What a shot! 31 amazing sports photos
Victor Minibaev, left, and Roman Izmailov perform synchronized dives at the Diving World Cup on Saturday, February 20. The Russians finished fifth in the 10-meter platform.
Hide Caption
15 of 31
31 photos: What a shot! 31 amazing sports photos
Hull City's Adama Diomande, left, competes for the ball with Arsenal's Laurent Koscielny during an FA Cup match in London on Saturday, February 20. The match ended scoreless.
Hide Caption
16 of 31
31 photos: What a shot! 31 amazing sports photos
Frank Halai scores Wasps' opening try during a Premiership match in Bath, England, on Saturday, February 20. Wasps defeated Bath 24-18.
Hide Caption
17 of 31
31 photos: What a shot! 31 amazing sports photos
The puck gets past Chicago goalie Corey Crawford during an NHL game in Minneapolis on Sunday, February 21. The game was played at the University of Minnesota's football stadium as part of the league's Stadium Series. The home team Wild won 6-1.
Hide Caption
18 of 31
31 photos: What a shot! 31 amazing sports photos
Texas Tech basketball player Toddrick Gotcher runs toward fans as they celebrate the team's home win over No. 3 Oklahoma on Wednesday, February 17.
Hide Caption
19 of 31
31 photos: What a shot! 31 amazing sports photos
Slovenian ski jumper Jurij Tepes competes at a World Cup event in Lahti, Finland, on Sunday, February 21.
Hide Caption
20 of 31
31 photos: What a shot! 31 amazing sports photos
Club America's Oribe Peralta falls down Saturday, February 20, during a league match against Cruz Azul in Mexico City.
Hide Caption
21 of 31
31 photos: What a shot! 31 amazing sports photos
George Hewett of the Sydney Swans is tackled during an Australian Football League match against the Port Adelaide Power on Saturday, February 20.
Hide Caption
22 of 31
31 photos: What a shot! 31 amazing sports photos
Sparks fly from the truck of Christopher Bell (No. 4) during a NASCAR race in Daytona Beach, Florida, on Friday, February 19.
Hide Caption
23 of 31
31 photos: What a shot! 31 amazing sports photos
U.S. soccer players Kelley O'Hara, top, and Lindsey Horan, right, congratulate Tobin Heath after Heath scored a second-half goal against Canada on Sunday, February 21. The United States defeated Canada 2-0 to win the final of the CONCACAF tournament in Houston.
Hide Caption
24 of 31
31 photos: What a shot! 31 amazing sports photos
Students from the University of Washington turn their backs to the court as Stanford's starters are introduced before a basketball game in Seattle on Saturday, February 20.
Hide Caption
31 photos: What a shot! 31 amazing sports photos
Pat Ngoho takes part in Bowl-A-Rama, Australia's biggest skateboarding competition, on Sunday, February 21.
Hide Caption
26 of 31
31 photos: What a shot! 31 amazing sports photos
Pro surfer Jarryd Foster competes in a big-wave event held in Praia do Norte, Portugal, on Friday, February 19.
Hide Caption
27 of 31
31 photos: What a shot! 31 amazing sports photos
USC's Nikola Jovanovic loses the ball after his shot was blocked by Utah's Brekkott Chapman, left, on Sunday, February 21.
Hide Caption
28 of 31
31 photos: What a shot! 31 amazing sports photos
Tampa Bay pitcher Danny Farquhar warms up during a spring-training workout in Port Charlotte, Florida, on Sunday, February 21.
Hide Caption
29 of 31
31 photos: What a shot! 31 amazing sports photos
Lydia Ko dumps water on Haru Nomura after Nomura won the Women's Australian Open on Sunday, February 21. It was the first LPGA victory for Nomura.
Hide Caption
30 of 31
31 photos: What a shot! 31 amazing sports photos
Horses race on a frozen lake in St. Moritz, Switzerland, on Sunday, February 21. See 38 amazing sports photos from last week
Hide Caption
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
