<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2016 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 17:37:09 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 17:37:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<item>
<title>Olympic effect transforms women's rugby</title>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676991/s/4daf19a7/sc/13/l/0Ledition0Bcnn0N0C20A160C0A20C180Csport0Cemily0Escarratt0Erugby0Eengland0Eolympics0Cindex0Bhtml0Deref0Frss0Isport/story01.htm</link>
<description>She was England's World Cup-winning hero as an amateur, and now Emily Scarratt is hoping to crown her professional rugby career by winning Olympic gold.&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247391938437/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4daf19a7/sc/13/rc/1/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247391938437/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4daf19a7/sc/13/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247391938437/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4daf19a7/sc/13/rc/2/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247391938437/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4daf19a7/sc/13/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247391938437/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4daf19a7/sc/13/rc/3/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247391938437/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4daf19a7/sc/13/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247391938437/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4daf19a7/sc/13/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247391938437/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4daf19a7/sc/13/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247391938437/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4daf19a7/sc/13/ach.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247391938437/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4daf19a7/sc/13/ach.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/247391938437/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4daf19a7/sc/13/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi2.feedsportal.com/r/247391938437/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4daf19a7/sc/13/a2t2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676991/s/4daf19a7/sc/13/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 09:53:24 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://edition.cnn.com/2016/02/18/sport/emily-scarratt-rugby-england-olympics/index.html</guid>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160118172736-emily-scarratt-2014-world-cup-final-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" lang="" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160118172736-emily-scarratt-2014-world-cup-final-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>"When I heard we could be going, there was a kind of disbelief. I started thinking, 'Could we do that then?'"
Olympic glory
Rugby sevens will feature at the OIympics for the first time in August.
Its popularity has grown rapidly -- countries that don't have a big history in the sport, such as Russia, are making an impact after investing in the game.
"It's a massively pivotal time for the sport," says Scarratt, who was the tournament's top points scorer when England won the 15-a-side World Cup in 2014.
"The inclusion of the game at the Olympics is huge, and nations which aren't traditionally well known can and will play sevens.
"It's a more accessible game because you need less players, and there is less contact. It's more of a game for athletes -- which we're trying to be."
Beating the boys
The birthplace of rugby sevens 02:50
Rugby's progression, particularly in the women's sphere, has been significant in recent years.
"Within the country, I think there's now 21,000 women and girls playing rugby -- that's huge," Scarratt says.
When she started playing, aged five, there were no junior girls teams in her area -- she had to play with the boys.
At 12 she was forced to join her local girls' club -- where she was thrown straight into the under-18s.
"I remember it was really a 'sink or swim' moment," Scarratt recalls.
"It was quite daunting knowing there was a six-year difference, which is probably even bigger at that age but I'd always been slightly larger than average so I didn't think it was as much of a big deal."
Brought up in the rugby heartland of Leicester, Scarratt excelled at every sport she tried -- even being offered a U.S. college basketball scholarship at the age of 16.
But it was always the oval-shaped ball which ruled her heart.
A photo posted by England Rugby (@englandrugby) on
Oct 3, 2015 at 3:51am PDT
"I don't know why I chose rugby," she says. "I was sports-mad all through school and played all of them, but rugby encompasses a lot of them.
"It has the contact element, the agility, the team ethic -- it's almost an amalgamation of lots of sports."
World Cup winner
After the 2014 World Cup success, it was announced that 20 central contracts would be handed out to female players for the first time in English rugby history.
It meant Scarratt could leave her job as a physical education teaching assistant and take up the sport full time.
"I never thought it would be possible to turn professional," she says.
"It's difficult trying to be a full-time athlete and a full-time employee. It's tricky to juggle.
"It's a lot more stress-free now because we only have to focus on the one thing because we get paid to do it."
Scarratt is now focused on the second round of the Women's Sevens Series in Sao Paulo this weekend, with 12 teams from across the world going for glory.
A photo posted by England Rugby (@englandrugby) on
Dec 3, 2015 at 10:06am PST
England, which came third in the opening round in Dubai in December, harbors aspirations of winning not only the Brazil tournament but the entire series -- thus ending New Zealand's dominance since its inception in 2012.
But with such a huge workload staggered over a couple of days, Scarratt is wary of expectations.
"It's a lot of rugby within a couple of days," she says.
"At the moment there are seven or eight teams that could genuinely win each tournament, which certainly hasn't been the case in the women's game before.
"That's really exciting as a neutral but you know you have to be properly on your game if you want the results to go the way you want."
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
