<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2013 18:54:09 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_sport" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_sport"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>'I had to stop breaking my body'</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://edition.cnn.com/2013/11/14/sport/amy-williams-wales-rally-gb-sochi-2014/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~3/Hu1kbWjoUSg/index.html</link>
<description>Pain, pain and more pain. Amy Williams is an expert in discomfort.&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~4/Hu1kbWjoUSg" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2013 10:07:23 EST</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/11/14/sport/amy-williams-wales-rally-gb-sochi-2014/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Amy Williams has swapped skeleton racing for rally driving
The Briton will co-driver at the final round of the World Rally Championship
Williams won Britain's first individual Winter Games gold medal at Vancouver 2010
The 31-year-old has set her sights on sailing around the world in inflatable vessel
(CNN) -- Pain, pain and more pain. Amy Williams is an expert in discomfort.
Plagued by a chronic knee complaint, the 31-year-old has had numerous epidural injections to soothe three swollen vertebrae and she suffers almost constant sciatica.
Not to mention the degenerative disc in her neck.
These injuries are legacy of a death-defying decade in skeleton racing -- 10 years of hurling herself headfirst down an icy track in pursuit of golden glory has come at a cost.
"I'm pretty much broken between my back and my knees," says the Briton, who won gold at the Vancouver 2010 Winter Games.
"I got to the point where I was so blinkered and obsessed by winning a medal that I put all of the physical pain to one side.
Sochi Olympic torch takes a spacewalk
The Olympic torch has left Earth as part of its 123-day journey across Russia, which will end at the Black Sea resort of Sochi -- host venue for the 2014 Winter Games. The rocket was launched at 8:14 a.m. local time Thursday November 7 at the Baikonur Cosmodrome in Kazakhstan, which is a Russian-leased facility.
"This feat underlines incredible human capabilities and will symbolize the aspirations of all athletes from around the world to reach new heights in sports," Sochi 2014 organizing committee president Dmitry Chernyshenko said in a statement.
Cosmonaut Mikhail Tyurin will hand the torch to Oleg Kotov and Sergey Ryazansky, who will take it on an historic spacewalk on November 9. The torch, along with the cosmonauts, will spend a total of four hours in outer space. Kotov and Ryazansky have already been in low Earth orbit for more than a month.
This NASA photo, a two-minute exposure, shows the early moments of the torch's journey into outer space. The Sochi 2014 torch is the third to do so, after the Atlanta 1996 and Sydney 2000 Summer Games, but is the first to go on a spacewalk.
Earlier Thursday, the Soyuz-FG rocket and Soyuz-TMA capsule sat in wait at the Baikonur Cosmodrome ahead of the torch's journey to the International Space Station (ISS).
Japanese astronaut Koichi Wakata bid farewell to his family prior to liftoff. Wakata, Russian commander Tyurin and U.S. astronaut Rick Mastracchio accompanied the torch on its journey.
Russian cosmonaut Tyurin holds the torch aloft before boarding the rocket. For safety reasons, the torch will stay unlit aboard the rocket and the ISS. If lit, the torch would burn up precious oxygen.
A view of the Soyuz rocket, which is emblazoned with the Olympic logo and Sochi 2014 livery.
A crowd of hundreds of people watched the launch in Tokyo, Japan. The country's astronaut Koichi Wakata became the first Japanese commander of the ISS on this trip.
Once it has completed its spacewalk, the torch will return to Earth and continue a journey which will end with the lighting of the Sochi 2014 Olympic cauldron on February 7. It is scheduled to return to Earth on November 11 before continuing its 65,000-kilometer trip, which will include a voyage underwater in Lake Baikal and a climb to the top of Europe's highest peak, Mount Eblrus. Last month, it went to the North Pole.
HIDE CAPTION
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
