<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2016 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 14:44:05 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 14:44:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<item>
<title>Remember this kid? His dream just came true</title>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676993/s/4dd84d1d/sc/13/l/0Ledition0Bcnn0N0C20A160C0A20C250Cfootball0Cmessi0Eboy0Emurtaza0Eahmadi0Ebarcelona0Eargentina0Eshirt0Cindex0Bhtml0Deref0Fedition/story01.htm</link>
<description>&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392775677/u/89/f/676993/c/35494/s/4dd84d1d/sc/13/rc/1/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392775677/u/89/f/676993/c/35494/s/4dd84d1d/sc/13/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392775677/u/89/f/676993/c/35494/s/4dd84d1d/sc/13/rc/2/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392775677/u/89/f/676993/c/35494/s/4dd84d1d/sc/13/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392775677/u/89/f/676993/c/35494/s/4dd84d1d/sc/13/rc/3/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392775677/u/89/f/676993/c/35494/s/4dd84d1d/sc/13/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392775677/u/89/f/676993/c/35494/s/4dd84d1d/sc/13/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392775677/u/89/f/676993/c/35494/s/4dd84d1d/sc/13/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392775677/u/89/f/676993/c/35494/s/4dd84d1d/sc/13/ach.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392775677/u/89/f/676993/c/35494/s/4dd84d1d/sc/13/ach.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/247392775677/u/89/f/676993/c/35494/s/4dd84d1d/sc/13/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi2.feedsportal.com/r/247392775677/u/89/f/676993/c/35494/s/4dd84d1d/sc/13/a2t2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676993/s/4dd84d1d/sc/13/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 10:58:10 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://edition.cnn.com/2016/02/25/football/messi-boy-murtaza-ahmadi-barcelona-argentina-shirt/index.html</guid>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160225113506-murtaza-ahmadi-lionel-messi-afghanistan-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" lang="" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160225113506-murtaza-ahmadi-lionel-messi-afghanistan-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>— UNICEF Afghanistan (@UNICEFAfg) 25 February 2016
Earlier this month, the Afghan Football Federation told CNN that Messi's charitable foundation was trying to set up a meeting between the five-time world player of the year and Murtaza.
Messi's club Barcelona informed CNN it would be willing to help, but stressed that any such meeting would be down to the player and his management.
Asked about becoming an internet sensation, Murtaza told CNN from the family's farm in Jaghori, southwest of Kabul: "The whole people in the world know me now."
An image posted to Hamayon's Facebook page shows his little brother dancing in his makeshift shirt.
His father, who said the impacts of reports about his son from around the globe had "inspired me," added that his dream was "to have a football stadium in our district."
He explained that the plastic bag jersey had come about when he told his son "that we were living in a poor village far from the city and it was impossible for me to get him the shirt."
Arif added: "He kept crying for days, asking for the shirt, until his brother Hamayon helped him make one from the plastic bag to make him happy. He stopped crying after wearing that plastic bag shirt."
Internet users began searching for the mystery boy in mid-January when a Messi fan account on Twitter posted an image of him wearing the plastic bag Messi shirt.
A kid in Iraq &#128148;.. pic.twitter.com/ZfOEpUCNvw
— Leo Messi (@messi10stats) January 16, 2016
The picture showed him only from the back -- a small boy with a buzz cut wearing a brown knitted sweater -- with a caption that read: "A kid in Iraq ..." and included an emoji of a breaking heart.
The Iraq reference turned out to be false, and a Twitter user who wrote that the boy was from the city of Dohuk in northern Iraq later admitted that he had made that up.
Claims by a television station in Kurdistan that they had found the boy in Dohuk were also false.
"I feel very happy that he is famous now," Arif said. "He is really excited that his pictures are everywhere now. He wants to become a football player in the future, and go to school."
Last month, Messi reclaimed his title as the world's best player when he won his fifth Ballon d'Or at a lavish ceremony in Zurich.
Today @FCBarcelona and UNICEF mark 10 years of partnership and renew commitment to children https://t.co/54aI9uHnFT pic.twitter.com/Aw004jBbfz
— UNICEF (@UNICEF) 25 February 2016
Meanwhile, UNICEF announced that it has renewed its partnership with Barcelona on a program to give some of the world's most vulnerable children the chance to participate in sports.
The program, in its 10th year, has helped more than one million children in Angola, Brazil, China, Ghana, Malawi, South Africa and Swaziland, and the new four-year agreement will see Barcelona increase its annual contribution from €1.5 million (£1.65 million) to €2 million.
"We are united in the fight for children's rights and the promotion of education through sport," Josep Maria Bartomeu, the Barcelona president, said.
Build your dream Champions League team and share it, challenging your friends to beat your Ultimate XI
Choose your team
Tap team shirts left or right
Tap a player to add them to your team
Tap to view player stats
Your formation will update as you add players
Tap on the trash can to clear your selections
Tap done to show and share your team results
Got it
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
