<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2016 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 14:44:05 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 14:44:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<item>
<title>Kansas shooting: 3 killed, 14 wounded</title>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676993/s/4ddffb38/sc/13/l/0Ledition0Bcnn0N0C20A160C0A20C260Cus0Ckansas0Eshooting0Cindex0Bhtml0Deref0Fedition/story01.htm</link>
<description>A Kansas sheriff's deputy served a man a "protection from abuse" order just 1½ hours before that man began opening fire -- a flurry of bullets that ended with at least 14 wounded and three dead before the shooter was shot and killed.&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392919138/u/89/f/676993/c/35494/s/4ddffb38/sc/13/rc/1/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392919138/u/89/f/676993/c/35494/s/4ddffb38/sc/13/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392919138/u/89/f/676993/c/35494/s/4ddffb38/sc/13/rc/2/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392919138/u/89/f/676993/c/35494/s/4ddffb38/sc/13/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392919138/u/89/f/676993/c/35494/s/4ddffb38/sc/13/rc/3/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392919138/u/89/f/676993/c/35494/s/4ddffb38/sc/13/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392919138/u/89/f/676993/c/35494/s/4ddffb38/sc/13/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392919138/u/89/f/676993/c/35494/s/4ddffb38/sc/13/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392919138/u/89/f/676993/c/35494/s/4ddffb38/sc/13/ach.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392919138/u/89/f/676993/c/35494/s/4ddffb38/sc/13/ach.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/247392919138/u/89/f/676993/c/35494/s/4ddffb38/sc/13/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi2.feedsportal.com/r/247392919138/u/89/f/676993/c/35494/s/4ddffb38/sc/13/a2t2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676993/s/4ddffb38/sc/13/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 14:20:23 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://edition.cnn.com/2016/02/26/us/kansas-shooting/index.html</guid>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160225185031-01-kansas-shooting-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" lang="" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160225185031-01-kansas-shooting-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>Story highlights
Two hospitals are treating 11 patients -- 1 critical, 5 serious and 5 in fair condition -- officials say
Sheriff: A deputy served the shooter a "protection from abuse" order 1½ hours before shots rang out
The worst of the carnage was at Excel Industries, a lawn care company where the gunman worked
Hesston, Kansas (CNN)
[Breaking news update, published at 10:03 a.m. ET]
The "protection from abuse" order that Cedric Ford received roughly 90 minutes before he went on Thursday's deadly shooting spree in Kansas was served to him at his workplace -- Excel Industries in Hesston, where most of the casualties would be -- Harvey County Sheriff T. Walton told reporters Friday.
Walton identified Cedric Ford as the man who killed three people and injured 14 others in the rampage that ended at Excel Industries, the lawn care equipment manufacturer where Ford worked.
A deputy went to Excel and served Ford with the protection order at about 3:30 p.m. (4:30 p.m. ET) Thursday, about 90 minutes before the shootings began, Walton said.
"They said he was upset (upon receiving the order), but nothing greater than anybody else who gets served a PFA," Walton said, citing witnesses.
Read More
The sheriff added that the person who filed the order did not work at Excel.
Walton detailed a timeline of the shootings. The first person Ford shot was a man driving with his two children, Walton said.
Walton said the gunman later shot and wounded a second person, stealing that person's car, before heading to back to Excel Industries. A 911 call came in at about 5 p.m. CT.
Ford was armed with an assault rifle and an automatic pistol, Walton said.
Excel Industries' CEO, Paul Mullet, said Friday that  his first priority is his employees' "safety and wellness."  Mullet added that his company is fully cooperating with law enforcement agencies and the Red Cross.
[Original story, published at 8:44 a.m. ET]
A Kansas sheriff's deputy served a man a "protection from abuse" order just 1½ hours before that man began opening fire -- a flurry of bullets that ended with at least 14 wounded and three dead before the shooter was shot and killed.
While it wasn't immediately clear what led to the protection order, Harvey County Sheriff T. Walton said, "I believe that probably is the trigger, and it went from there."
All of those killed and all but two of those wounded Thursday were struck in and around the building of the gunman's employer, a lawn care equipment manufacturer in Hesston, Kansas, authorities said.
The Harvey County Sheriff's Office indicated Thursday that 10 of the 14 wounded were critical.
Their conditions may have changed since, though. Via Christi St. Francis Hospital in Wichita, had one in critical, two in serious and four in fair condition Friday morning, spokeswoman Roz Hutchinson said. Three of the four being treated at Wesley Medical Center are serious and the other is fair, said Susan Burchill, the spokeswoman there. CNN is waiting to hear back from one other hospital were victims are believed to be.
The carnage left people grasping for answers in Hesston, a small city of about 3,700 people located about 35 miles north of Wichita. While authorities hunt for these, Harvey County's sheriff said that residents "are ready to start grieving."
"Everybody says it can't happen here," Walton said. "And here we are. It happened here."
5 photos: Kansas workplace shooting
Several officers stand at the front door of Excel Industries in Hesston, Kansas, where a series of shootings that left multiple dead ended on Thursday, February 25. The suspected shooter, an employee at Excel, was killed by authorities.
Hide Caption
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
