<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2014 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 10:09:24 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Sharing peace</title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/05/01/world/defining-moments/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/05/01/world/defining-moments/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description/>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 07:31:19 EST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141210115118-defining-moments-nobel-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141210115118-defining-moments-nobel-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>By Monica Sarkar and Ivana Kottasová , CNN
December 1, 2014 -- Updated 1225 GMT (2025 HKT)
DECEMBER 10 - OSLO, NORWAY: An image of joint Nobel Peace prize winner Malala Yousafzai, center, is displayed on a screen alongside previous winners in the Nobel Field exhibit at the Nobel Peace Center. The prize will be presented to and shared between the youngest recipient ever, 17-year-old Malala, and Indian children's rights activist Kailash Satyarthi today.
DECEMBER 9 - MANAGUA, NICARAGUA: A man runs with a "toro encuetado," a structure resembling a bull and covered with exploding fireworks, as part of celebrations in honor of the Virgin of the Immaculate Conception on her feast day. The Virgin of the Immaculate Conception is Nicaragua's patron saint.
DECEMBER 8 - IRBIL, IRAQ: A Christian prays during a visit by the Archbishop of Lyon, French Cardinal Philippe Barbarin, at the Saint Joseph church in the capital of the Kurdish region of northern Iraq.
Landon Donovan raises the MLS Cup for the sixth -- and last -- time following LA Galaxy's victory over New England Revolution.
DECEMBER 5 - PRETORIA, SOUTH AFRICA: Traditional worshipers burn herbs in prayer at dawn at Freedom Park for former South African President Nelson Mandela . Today marks the first anniversary of his death at the age of 95 and events will be held around the country.
DECEMBER 4 - CHIANG MAI, THAILAND: A Thai women prepares for a parade and ceremony in honor of King Bhumibol Adulyadej's birthday. The world's longest-reigning monarch is a deeply revered figure in Thailand, where his portrait hangs in government offices and many homes.
DECEMBER 3 - KULANGHAM, INDIAN-CONTROLLED KASHMIR: An election officer checks a Kashmiri woman's identity before letting her cast her vote in the second phase of five-phase state elections at a polling station 68km north of Srinagar.
DECEMBER 2 - BUCHAREST, ROMANIA: A soldier with a camouflaged face watches an honor guard pass by prior to a military parade to mark Romania's National Day. Romanians braved the cold weather to watch the traditional parade, held outside the Palace of Parliament, formerly the House of the People, built during the rule of communist dictator Nicolae Ceausescu.
DECEMBER 1 - OSAKA, JAPAN: Ksenia Monko and Kirill Khaliavin of Russia perform during the gala exhibition of the NHK Trophy figure skating competition.
NOVEMBER 28 - MACKSVILLE, AUSTRALIA: Cricket bats are placed at Donnelly Welsh Playing Fields in Macksville, New South Wales, in memory of Australian cricketer Phillip Hughes, who died this week after he was hit in the head by a ball during a match. Fans across Australia have paid tribute to the sportsman by leaving cricket bats outside their front doors and using the Twitter hashtag #putoutyourbats .
NOVEMBER 27 - PARIS: Sheep graze at the Champ de Mars near the Eiffel Tower in Paris during a protest by farmers demanding an effective plan to combat wolf attacks on flocks.
NOVEMBER 25 - HONG KONG: A pro-democracy activist holds a yellow umbrella in front of a police line on a street in Mong Kok district on November 25, 2014 in Hong Kong. Police and authorities have started clearing barricades and tents from the group's protest camp, almost two months after demonstrations began .
NOVEMBER 25 - SHADIPORA, INDIAN-CONTROLLED KASHMIR: Voters stand in a queue outside a polling station at Shadipora, on the outskirts of Srinagar, waiting to cast their ballots in the Jammu and Kashmir state assembly elections. Muslim separatist groups have called for a voting boycott.
NOVEMBER 23 - LILLE, FRANCE: Roger Federer, Stanislas Wawrinka, Marco Chiudinelli, Michael Lammer and Severin Luthi of Switzerland celebrate winning the Davis Cup against France. The win is the first Davis Cup title for Switzerland and for former World No. 1 Federer , who has notched up victory in almost every other major tournament.
NOVEMBER 21 - KATHMANDU, NEPAL: Nepalese Hindu devotees light oil lamps in memory of deceased family members during the Bala Chaturdashi festival at the Pashupatinath Temple. Devotees sow seven kinds of seeds around temple premises in the name of those who have passed away.
NOVEMBER 20 - KOBANI, SYRIA: Syrian Kurdish refugee children from Kobani, receive food rations in front of their living quarters separated by plastic sheets at a camp in Suruc, on the Turkey-Syria border. The area, also known as Ayn al-Arab, which has been under attack by the militant group ISIS, is being defended by Kurdish fighters.
NOVEMBER 19 - KUALA LUMPUR, MALAYSIA: A model wearing a creation by Calvin Thoo has make-up applied backstage at the Islamic Fashion Festival on November 18. The event seeks to raise awareness of Islamic expression and culture.
November 18 - GLASGOW, UK: Forensic archaeologists examine images salvaged from the Mackintosh Library at Glasgow School of Art . The library, one of the world's finest examples of Art Nouveau, was devastated by a fire in May; Hollywood star Brad Pitt and "Dr Who" actor Peter Capaldi have joined the appeal to help restore Charles Rennie Mackintosh's masterpiece .
NOVEMBER 17 - PRAGUE, CZECH REPUBLIC: People light candles at a memorial to students attacked by riot police during the Velvet Revolution in 1989. Czech citizens are commemorating the 25th anniversary of the revolution, in which hundreds of thousands of people took to the streets of Prague and other cities across what was then still communist Czechoslovakia to demand political reforms and greater freedoms.
NOVEMBER 14 - AMRITSAR, INDIA: Children dress up as key figures in Indian history for Children's Day celebrations at a school. The event coincides with the anniversary of the birth of India's first Prime Minister, Jawaharlal Nehru.
NOVEMBER 13 - COMET 67P: The surface of Comet 67P/Churyumov-Gerasimenko, as seen from the European Space Agency's Philae lander, the first spacecraft to make a controlled -- if bouncy -- landing on a comet . The lander, sent from its mothership Rosetta, lost contact with scientists on Earth overnight, but has since begun sending back images and data.
NOVEMBER 12 - KARACHI, PAKISTAN: Paramilitary soldiers perform during the 18th "passing out parade" at the Sindh Rangers Training Center.
NOVEMBER 11 - LONDON, ENGLAND: The ceramic poppy art installation by artist Paul Cummins and theater designer Tom Piper, entitled 'Blood Swept Lands and Seas of Red,' is seen lit up before sunrise in the dry moat of the Tower of London. The finished installation is made up of 888,246 ceramic poppies, with the final poppy placed today, Armistice Day. Each poppy represents a British and Commonwealth military life lost in World War I.
NOVEMBER 10 - BERLIN, GERMANY: Shadows of people and the light installation "Lichtgrenze" (border of lights) appear on the Berlin Wall memorial on Bernauer Strasse. Germany celebrated the 25th anniversary of the fall of the wall with a weekend of special events, including a candle vigil and an open-air concert.
NOVEMBER 7 - RIO DE JANEIRO, BRAZIL: Teenage girls from the Cerro-Cora favela (slum) pose before the start of their debutante ball at the Ilha Fiscal castle in Guanabara Bay, organized by the Pacifying Police Unit (UPP) from their community on November 6. The gala relied on volunteers who prepared makeup, styled hair and loaned dresses, in an effort to build goodwill between residents and the community's police force.
NOVEMBER 6 - BAD TÖLZ, GERMANY: Girls in traditional costume sit in a horse-drawn carriage during the annual Leonhardi pilgrimage. The event honors St. Leonhard, patron saint of the highland farmers for horses and livestock.
NOVEMBER 5 - GEORGIA, UNITED STATES: Poll manager Markeia White places an "I Voted" sticker on her sweatshirt after casting her ballot inside the old Hoggards Mill Courthouse, now a polling site for Baker County, on November 4. Republicans have gained full control of Congress and the power to pin down President Barack Obama during his last two years in office.
NOVEMBER 4 - MALKIYA, BAHRAIN: A baby lies in a decorated bassinet ready to be blessed ahead of the Shiite Muslim holiday of Ashura during the month of Muharram on November 3. The scene, representative of seventh-century Iraq, is part of events leading up to Ashura, which commemorates the death of Imam Hussein, grandson of the Muslim prophet Mohammed.
NOVEMBER 3 - MADRID, SPAIN: Shepherds guide a flock of 2,000 sheep through the center of Madrid on November 2, in defense of ancient grazing, droving and migration rights which are increasingly threatened by urban sprawl and modern agricultural practices. Traffic was held back while the bleating parade made its way past the city's renowned landmarks.
OCTOBER 31 - SAN FRANCISCO, U.S.: A man jumps over a burning couch as fans celebrate after the San Francisco Giants beat the Kansas City Royals to win the World Series -- for the third time in five years.
HIDE CAPTION
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
