<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2014 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 10:09:24 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>India Uber case</title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/12/10/world/asia/india-uber-rape-case/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/12/10/world/asia/india-uber-rape-case/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>The Indian Uber driver accused of raping a passenger in New Delhi is awaiting trial in at least four criminal cases in his home state, a police official said Wednesday.</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 03:33:28 EST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141208133457-india-uber-rape-suspect-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141208133457-india-uber-rape-suspect-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>Part of complete coverage on
India
Cities of the future -- in India?
July 18, 2014 -- Updated 0621 GMT (1421 HKT)
In an ambitious plan to upgrade urban India, Prime Minister Narendra Modi says he will build 100 "smart cities" across the country.
New life for Indian boy tied to bus stop
July 17, 2014 -- Updated 1139 GMT (1939 HKT)
A few weeks ago, a young boy tied to a Mumbai bus stop barely received a glance from passersby. Now, he has a home, thanks to a local NGO.
Rape order brings scrutiny on councils
July 15, 2014 -- Updated 1202 GMT (2002 HKT)
When a 14-year-old girl was pulled from her home and raped, police revealed the assault was ordered by the head of her village council.
Has Modi given India its mojo back?
July 10, 2014 -- Updated 2249 GMT (0649 HKT)
If you believe the mood here, India is going to be the next China, the new frontier of global growth.
India's construction time bomb
July 8, 2014 -- Updated 0758 GMT (1558 HKT)
Decrepit constructions that don't conform to safety codes are a big problem in cities and towns across India.
Crying elephant raises awareness
July 11, 2014 -- Updated 1727 GMT (0127 HKT)
When Raju the elephant was rescued after being shackled and abused for five decades, the story and picture of him "crying" went viral.
Can 'water ATMs' quench thirst?
July 3, 2014 -- Updated 1609 GMT (0009 HKT)
The tall cylindrical concrete structures hold solar powered machines that look and function like an ATM. Instead of cash, they dispense water.
World Cup fever hits India
July 8, 2014 -- Updated 0027 GMT (0827 HKT)
Despite not having a national team in the tournament, many Indians have caught World Cup fever. Mallika Kapur reports.
June 23, 2014 -- Updated 1433 GMT (2233 HKT)
An Indian grandmother tells CNN's Mallika Kapur why she tied her grandson to a bus stop.
June 19, 2014 -- Updated 0212 GMT (1012 HKT)
India has a rape crisis -- but it will take a broad effort to change it.
June 17, 2014 -- Updated 0004 GMT (0804 HKT)
Could certain spices help you live longer? CNN's Dr. Sanjay Gupta reports from Delhi, India.
Fighting 'boys will be boys' in India
June 10, 2014 -- Updated 1925 GMT (0325 HKT)
CNN's Mallika Kapur takes a look at the push for change in India after another brutal rape has shocked the nation.
May 27, 2014 -- Updated 1324 GMT (2124 HKT)
Is there a historic opportunity for peace and understanding between the two nations?
May 20, 2014 -- Updated 0310 GMT (1110 HKT)
What will Narendra Modi's India look like? Likely less inclusive and less secular, say analysts.
Sizing up Modi's foreign policy
May 27, 2014 -- Updated 0250 GMT (1050 HKT)
India's new leader is considered a wildcard. Will he be aggressive, or a dove? What is his foreign policy? Does he have a vision?
Modi's energy policy crucial
May 26, 2014 -- Updated 0400 GMT (1200 HKT)
For incoming Prime Minister Narendra Modi, securing India's energy needs over the next decade ranks among his greatest challenges.
May 16, 2014 -- Updated 0738 GMT (1538 HKT)
Narenda Modi's track record leaves some worried about the future, writes Sunny Hundal.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
