<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2014 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 10:09:24 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Attack on Iraqi military base kills 9</title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/12/10/world/meast/iraq-violence/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/12/10/world/meast/iraq-violence/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>A suicide attack outside a military base in Samarra, north of Baghdad, killed nine people and wounded 15 others Wednesday, security officials said.</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 06:18:48 EST</pubDate>
<ExtractedText>Suicide attack on Iraqi military base kills 9
By Ed Payne, CNN
December 10, 2014 -- Updated 1140 GMT (1940 HKT)
(CNN) -- A suicide attack outside a military base in Samarra, north of Baghdad, killed nine people and wounded 15 others Wednesday, security officials said.
Iraqi soldiers were among the dead and wounded, according to the officials, who blamed the truck bombing on ISIS.
Samarra is about 100 kilometers (60 miles) north of Baghdad.
What Beijing can learn from LA
December 10, 2014 -- Updated 0021 GMT (0821 HKT)
Like Beijing today, Los Angeles in the last century went through its own smog crisis. The city's mayor says LA's experience delivers valuable lessons.
Detained in Pyongyang: The last POW
December 9, 2014 -- Updated 0157 GMT (0957 HKT)
A retired executive and Korean War veteran was hauled off his plane at Pyongyang airport at the end of a tourist trip in late 2013. Here's what happened next.
December 9, 2014 -- Updated 0903 GMT (1703 HKT)
Sean Abbott bowls his first balls since his "bouncer" inadvertently killed cricketer Phillip Hughes.
December 10, 2014 -- Updated 0445 GMT (1245 HKT)
CU46 and PIR are among teen codes words to keep adults in the dark.
Man 'spent hour' inside anaconda
December 8, 2014 -- Updated 1802 GMT (0202 HKT)
Paul Rosolie says he was eaten alive by a giant green anaconda, the largest and most powerful snake in the world.
December 6, 2014 -- Updated 0542 GMT (1342 HKT)
At the height of his power, he controlled police forces across China. Now he's under arrest.
Japan's answer to the Orient Express
December 8, 2014 -- Updated 0017 GMT (0817 HKT)
The "Seven Stars in Kyushu" is Japan's answer to the Orient Express, with its seven carriages having space for just 30 people in 14 suites.
Obama: 'This is an American problem'
December 9, 2014 -- Updated 0001 GMT (0801 HKT)
President Barack Obama describes the latest racial tensions in New York as "an American problem when anybody in this country is not being treated equally."
Hashtag: Cops treat white people better
December 4, 2014 -- Updated 1526 GMT (2326 HKT)
If you're white, you may be able to shoplift, drive drunk, even shove a police officer — and not suffer any consequences, according to trending stories.
NASA goes for next giant leap
December 4, 2014 -- Updated 1110 GMT (1910 HKT)
It's the biggest countdown for NASA since the shuttle era ended in 2011 as Orion is set to launch.
Defining Moments: Our changing world
December 10, 2014 -- Updated 1210 GMT (2010 HKT)
Each day, CNN brings you an image capturing a moment to remember, defining the present in our changing world.
Browse through images from CNN teams around the world that you don't always see on news reports.
Loading weather data ...
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
