<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2014 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 12:03:40 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Senior Palestinian dies after protest clash with IDF</title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/12/10/world/meast/palestinian-official-dies/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/12/10/world/meast/palestinian-official-dies/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>Mahmoud Abbas halts coordination with Israel after a senior Palestininan Authority official died following a confrontation with Israeli troops. </description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 12:02:38 EST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141210164904-ziad-abu-ain-poster-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141210164904-ziad-abu-ain-poster-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>Palestinians halt security cooperation with Israel after minister's death
By Ben Wedeman and Kareem Khadder, CNN
December 10, 2014 -- Updated 1437 GMT (2237 HKT)
Palestinian Authority President Mahmoud Abbas, shown here at the UN, declared 3 days of mourning after Ziyad Abu Ein's death.
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
A Palestinian minister, Ziyad Abu Ein, dies after a confrontation with Israeli troops
The Israeli military is investigating the incident, a spokesman says
Palestinian Authority President Mahmoud Abbas stops security cooperation with Israel
Abu Ein's death stirs outrage among Palestinians
Jerusalem (CNN) -- A senior Palestinian Authority official died Wednesday after a confrontation with Israeli troops, prompting President Mahmoud Abbas to halt all security coordination with Israel, according to Palestinian officials.
The Palestinian Ma'an news agency said the death of Ziyad Abu Ein, a minister in Abbas' party Fatah, occurred after protesters clashed with Israeli soldiers near the West Bank city of Ramallah. There were varying reports about exactly how Abu Ein died. He headed the Committee to Resist the Wall and Settlements, the Palestinian state news agency WAFA reported.
The Israeli military is looking into the incident, spokesman Peter Lerner told CNN.
The Palestinian Authority leader declared three days of mourning after Abu Ein's death. Hanan Ashrawi, an executive member of the Palestine Liberation Organization, said Abbas also froze security coordination with Israel. Jibril Rajoub, a member of Fatah's central committee, confirmed this development.
Ashrawi is among the Palestinians outraged by the minister's death, demanding "an international and impartial investigation."
"This is a deliberate and willful act of murder and criminality," she said.
CNN's Greg Botelho contributed to this report.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
