<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2014 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 10:09:24 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>16 gift ideas for foodies, travelers</title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/12/09/travel/gift-guide-foodies-travelers/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/12/09/travel/gift-guide-foodies-travelers/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>Foodies and travelers aren't necessarily the same species, so maybe it's unwise to lump them together in one gift guide.</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 19:59:08 EST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141208175636-01-foodie-travel-gifts-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141208175636-01-foodie-travel-gifts-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>16 gift ideas for foodies, travelers
By Brandon Griggs, CNN
December 10, 2014 -- Updated 0059 GMT (0859 HKT)
Here are 16 gift suggestions for the foodie or travel fiend in your life. This Zoku mini ice cream maker ($26) is a good choice for anyone who enjoys creating their own kitchen concoctions. You put it in the freezer overnight, then add cream, sugar and whatever else (fruit, nuts, mint, etc.) you choose. As you stir, the mixture hardens within minutes into a single ice cream serving -- a sweet reward for all your work.
One of the hottest recent trends in cooking is "sous vide" (French for under vacuum), which involves placing meat or fish in a plastic pouch and submerging it in a hot-water bath. The method relies on precise temperature control to cook foods evenly from edge to edge, without overcooking or drying out. This portable sous vide machine, by Sansaire , costs $199 and is aimed at the home cook.
Tired of aprons that make you look frumpy? Etsy has a whole CreativeChics line of playful, retro-hip aprons in a variety of colors and styles. This polka-dot model with a ruffled skirt is $40.
Mexican food is a lot more than tacos and enchiladas. Famed Mexico City chef and restaurateur Margarita Carrillo Arronte showcases the rich range of her country's cuisine in her Mexico: The Cookbook , complete with gorgeous photos ($49, but cheaper at some online sellers).
Any cook worth his or her salt should have something from Le Creuset , whose cookware is pricey but virtually indestructible. This 3 1/2-quart Dutch oven ($240), made from cast iron, is equally useful in an oven or on a stovetop and will likely last a lifetime.
A food mill separates skins and seeds for pureed soups and sauces and functions as a strainer, too. This model ($40) is from Sur La Table .
One of the oldest, most primitive tools in cooking is a mortar and pestle. This heavy porcelain model from Williams-Sonoma ($50) is ideal for crushing whole spices and fresh herbs to extract maximum flavor.
The seafood lover in your life will dive into School of Fish ($35), a comprehensive cookbook by Ben Pollinger, executive chef of award-winning Manhattan restaurant Oceana. The book contains more than 100 classic seafood recipes, from ceviche to chowder and beyond, organized by technique.
Now, on to the travel stuff. This Tumi packing cube ($45) helps you compress and organize your stuff -- underwear, toiletries, etc. -- inside your suitcase. Made from lightweight fabric, it's 10 inches long and has a see-through window so you can remember what's inside.
Smartphone battery life is a constant issue for travelers. Consider this Alpatronix charging case for the iPhone 6 (the 4.7-inch model), which promises "well over" a 150% charge to last you all day. The case costs $46 and comes in several colors.
Take an armchair trip around the globe with National Geographic's World's Best Cities , a coffee-table book highlighting 220 urban destinations, from iconic cities such as Paris and Tokyo to up-and-coming burgs such as Nairobi and Asheville, North Carolina. The $40 book includes stats, insider tips and, of course, the gorgeous photography National Geographic is known for.
Brookstone bills its Steam Bug ($40) as the world's smallest steam iron, smoothing wrinkled clothes while not hogging your suitcase. The iron heats up in just 15 seconds and features a dual-voltage design so you won't need power adapters when traveling overseas.
This little emergency travel kit by Pinch Provisions ($24 from J. Crew) contains 21 items, including a bandage, safety pin, hair spray, stain remover, mirror, lip balm, sewing kit, clear nail polish, emery board, tampon, dental floss and more.
For urban travelers, fold-out paper maps can be cumbersome and using a smartphone to navigate can drain your battery. Instead consider Palomar's Crumpled City maps (about $15 apiece), which can be stuffed in your pocket over and over without coming apart. Maps are available for 40 cities, including most European capitals.
Globetrotters will want this Satechi Smart Travel Adapter ($30), which offers an AC power cord, a USB port and prongs to fit electrical outlets in over 150 countries. It adapts to fit four of the world's most common plug configurations for charging smartphones, laptops, tablets, music players, cameras, e-readers and so on.
These Bluetooth fleece ear warmers from 180s let you take calls and listen to music from other Bluetooth-enabled devices. They come in three colors ($80) and promise a talk time of 9 hours and a play time of 8 hours without recharging.
HIDE CAPTION
Holiday gifts for foodies, travelers
Holiday gifts for foodies, travelers
Holiday gifts for foodies, travelers
Holiday gifts for foodies, travelers
Holiday gifts for foodies, travelers
Holiday gifts for foodies, travelers
Holiday gifts for foodies, travelers
Holiday gifts for foodies, travelers
Holiday gifts for foodies, travelers
Holiday gifts for foodies, travelers
Holiday gifts for foodies, travelers
Holiday gifts for foodies, travelers
Holiday gifts for foodies, travelers
Holiday gifts for foodies, travelers
Holiday gifts for foodies, travelers
Holiday gifts for foodies, travelers
&lt;&lt;
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
