<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2014 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 10:09:24 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>U.S. girl burned alive</title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/12/09/us/mississippi-girl-burns-to-death/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/12/09/us/mississippi-girl-burns-to-death/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>A mysterious and gruesome crime ended the life of 19-year-old Jessica Chambers.</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 04:01:45 EST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141210032553-dnt-wmc-teen-burned-to-death-00004213-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141210032553-dnt-wmc-teen-burned-to-death-00004213-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>Police look for clues in case of Mississippi teen burned to death
By Martin Savidge and Steve Almasy, CNN
December 10, 2014 -- Updated 0833 GMT (1633 HKT)
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
Jessica Chambers went out to clean her car and get dinner, her mom says
Emergency responders found her badly burned on a rural road in Panola County, Mississippi
"They have ripped everything I have," mother tells CNN affiliate
Chambers was burned over 98% of her body, father says
(CNN) -- A mysterious and gruesome crime ended the life of 19-year-old Jessica Chambers.
She was found badly burned Saturday night on a rural Mississippi road by first responders after a passerby called 911.
"You couldn't recognize her because she was unrecognizable," her father, Ben Chambers, told CNN affiliate WREG .
As her car continued to blaze, emergency workers struggled to hear Chambers' final words. She spoke in a hoarse voice, Jay Hale, the assistant district attorney for Panola County said.
Did she identify her killer?
Hale paused and told CNN that no one was in custody yet, so it's still not known.
Ben Chambers said doctors told him his daughter was burned over 98% of her body.
"They have ripped everything I have," her mother, Lisa Chambers, told CNN affiliate WMC .
Jessica Chambers went to go clean out her car and get something to eat before she was burned alive, her mother said,
Authorities have questioned a few people, but no one has been arrested, Hale said.
They are also trying to get a call record and data from her cell phone, found at the scene near the town of Courtland in northwestern Mississippi.
CNN's Dave Alsup contributed to this report
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
