<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2016 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 15:11:53 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 15:11:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<item>
<title>Why the real problem isn't #OscarsSoWhite</title>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676982/s/4dd117f2/sc/14/l/0L0Scnn0N0C20A160C0A20C230Copinions0Coscars0Eso0Egray0Eseymour0Cindex0Bhtml0Deref0Frss0Ishowbiz/story01.htm</link>
<description>&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392614432/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd117f2/sc/14/rc/1/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392614432/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd117f2/sc/14/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392614432/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd117f2/sc/14/rc/2/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392614432/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd117f2/sc/14/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392614432/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd117f2/sc/14/rc/3/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392614432/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd117f2/sc/14/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392614432/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd117f2/sc/14/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392614432/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd117f2/sc/14/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392614432/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd117f2/sc/14/ach.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392614432/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd117f2/sc/14/ach.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/247392614432/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd117f2/sc/14/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi2.feedsportal.com/r/247392614432/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd117f2/sc/14/a2t2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676982/s/4dd117f2/sc/14/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 11:54:17 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2016/02/23/opinions/oscars-so-gray-seymour/index.html</guid>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160123075719-oscars-statues-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" lang="" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160123075719-oscars-statues-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>1 of 20
20 photos: 20 controversial casting choices
Sometimes, casting directors can't win for losing when selecting actors for an anticipated film. It's too soon to see how the choice of Ben Affleck as Batman will play out, but you couldn't tell the Internet that. When the news arrived, nearly everyone was convinced that his portrayal would be so awful, it'd make history.
Hide Caption
2 of 20
20 photos: 20 controversial casting choices
With "Fifty Shades of Grey," fans were outraged over Dakota Johnson and Charlie Hunnam (who dropped out and was replaced by Jamie Dornan) being named as Anastasia Steele and Christian Grey in the adaptation of E.L. James' racy best-seller.
Hide Caption
3 of 20
20 photos: 20 controversial casting choices
Jennifer Lawrence took criticism of her casting as rugged, resourceful "Hunger Games" heroine Katniss Everdeen in stride. "I'm a massive fan too, so I get it," the actress said in response to fans who thought she had the wrong look for the dystopian character. Some complained that Lawrence is "too big" and had the wrong hair color to properly fill the role, but that whining was quickly snuffed out by the positive reaction from fans, critics and the box office.
Hide Caption
4 of 20
20 photos: 20 controversial casting choices
The war to cast Marlon Brando -- or anyone in "The Godfather's" Corleone family -- was tougher than what was depicted in the film, insiders told Vanity Fair in 2009. Paramount wanted "anyone but Brando" and dropped hints for stars like Laurence Olivier, Ernest Borgnine and Anthony Quinn. But director Francis Ford Coppola knew that Brando was the right man for the part, and after a screen test, executives did, too.
Hide Caption
5 of 20
20 photos: 20 controversial casting choices
Brit actors playing iconic Americans is commonplace these days, but in the late '30s, producers feared backlash if they cast then-unknown English actress Vivien Leigh in the role of Scarlett O'Hara. To bring Margaret Mitchell's "Gone With the Wind" character to life, Leigh would have to adapt a Southern accent and demeanor, and there was also the matter of her scandalous relationship with Laurence Olivier. But instinct paid off: Leigh wound up with an Oscar for her work.
Hide Caption
6 of 20
20 photos: 20 controversial casting choices
Johnny Depp promised to "reinvent" Tonto's relationship with "The Lone Ranger" in 2013's summer flop of the same name, but audiences were wary. Casting Depp to begin with was sketchy, considering that the actor is not a Native American (although he does claim some Native ancestry). That fact coupled with "Lone Ranger's" characterization of Tonto , which critics called heavily reliant on stereotypes, made Depp's promise a nonstarter .
Hide Caption
7 of 20
20 photos: 20 controversial casting choices
Hollywood's portrayal of Egyptian queen Cleopatra has been hotly debated, as some feel that casting a non-woman of color -- most famously done in 1963 with Elizabeth Taylor -- is a classic example of Hollywood whitewashing. When Angelina Jolie was mentioned as a successor to Taylor's iconic performance, many vehemently disagreed , saying that it was time to cast a woman of color.
Hide Caption
8 of 20
20 photos: 20 controversial casting choices
9 of 20
20 photos: 20 controversial casting choices
"Twilight" fans initially hated the very man they'd grow to love. When little-known Brit actor Robert Pattinson was cast as Edward Cullen in the adaptation of Stephenie Meyer's runaway bestseller, fans felt "unanimous unhappiness" over the man picked to fill the gorgeous, sparkling shoes of their favorite vampire. Of course, after five movies in, R-Patz couldn't shake his "Twilight" fame.
Hide Caption
10 of 20
20 photos: 20 controversial casting choices
Given that Audrey Hepburn couldn't sing, her casting in 1964's "My Fair Lady" was a head-scratcher -- particularly when they could've gone with Julie Andrews, who a) could sing and b) had played the role before. The drama came to a head at the 1965 Oscars, when the Academy gave Hepburn the cold shoulder and handed Andrews the Best Actress Oscar for "Mary Poppins."
Hide Caption
11 of 20
20 photos: 20 controversial casting choices
When Anne Hathaway was revealed as the new Selina Kyle in "Dark Night Rises," some moviegoers threatened to boycott as they filled comments sections with alternatives . But Hathaway was a lithe, cunning and sensuous Catwoman, all qualities her critics were positive the actress would never pull off.
Hide Caption
12 of 20
20 photos: 20 controversial casting choices
When Jennifer Lopez was picked to play Mexican-American singer Selena in a biopic about the singer's sadly shortened life, critics shook their heads and a few even protested . How could Lopez, a Puerto Rican-American who had yet to show any vocal range, take on the legacy of immensely talented Tejano songbird? With lip-syncing and commitment. "Selena" wound up being one of Lopez's standout performances.
Hide Caption
13 of 20
20 photos: 20 controversial casting choices
Before the world came to hate Ben Affleck as Batman, they bestowed their angst on Michael Keaton. When Tim Burton cast the actor known for his comedy in 1989's "Batman," reactions ranged from "disappointed to disturbed." In retrospect, though, the 1989 film is a classic (not solely because of Keaton but not in spite of him, either).
Hide Caption
14 of 20
20 photos: 20 controversial casting choices
Daniel Craig brilliantly embodied James Bond in 2012's blockbuster "Skyfall," but when he was first cast as 007 for 2006's "Casino Royale," even director Sam Mendes thought he was the wrong guy for the job. Mendes then had to eat his words as he watched Craig "go through that intense pressure and come through that with flying colors."
Hide Caption
15 of 20
20 photos: 20 controversial casting choices
Jake Gyllenhaal's career has had its high points, but 2010's "Prince of Persia: Sands of Time" was not one of them. Criticism of the film aside, the casting of Gyllenhaal in the title role was awfully suspicious. The Atlantic succinctly summed up what everyone was thinking at the time with the headline "Why is a White actor Playing (the) 'Prince of Persia' title role?"
Hide Caption
16 of 20
20 photos: 20 controversial casting choices
No one hated Tom Cruise's casting as Lestat in 1994's "Interview With the Vampire" more than the character's creator, Anne Rice. The author publicly criticized the choice and said her readers were just as upset. "The very sad thing about Tom Cruise is, he does not have that kind of distinct voice. How is he possibly going to say those lines? How is he gonna exert the power of Lestat?" she said to Movieline . "I don't know how it's gonna work." Somehow, Cruise's voice did the trick, and Rice changed her tune.
Hide Caption
17 of 20
20 photos: 20 controversial casting choices
Zoe Saldana's casting as music legend Nina Simone is a stunning choice, and not just because the actress hasn't shown any proclivity toward jazz (or singing , for that matter). Physically, Saldana bears no resemblance to the icon, and none of the options present have been appealing to moviegoers: Either Saldana maintains her natural appearance and offers an inaccurate portrayal, or the actress would be made to appear darker. Judging from production photos, the creative team behind "Nina" went with the latter.
Hide Caption
18 of 20
20 photos: 20 controversial casting choices
Although it may be hard to make authenticity demands on fictional characters, "Thor" fans didn't hold back with their frustration over Idris Elba's casting in the 2011 film. When Kenneth Branagh tapped his fellow Brit to play Heimdall, some fans complained that a black man couldn't play a Norse god. Elba's response? "We have a man who has a flying hammer and wears horns on his head. And yet me being an actor of African descent playing a Norse god is unbelievable? I mean, Cleopatra was played by Elizabeth Taylor, and Gandhi was played by Ben Kingsley."
Hide Caption
1 of 11
11 photos: Broadway blockbusters
"The Producers," based on the 1968 Mel Brooks movie, was a phenomenon when it debuted in April 2001. Tickets went for a then unheard-of $100 a pop and set single-day box-office records. The show eventually won 12 Tony awards, a record. The original duo of Matthew Broderick and Nathan Lane were replaced by several other performers, including Tony Danza and Roger Bart, seen here.
Hide Caption
2 of 11
11 photos: Broadway blockbusters
"Mamma Mia!" may not have won a Tony for best musical -- it lost to "Thoroughly Modern Millie" -- but the good-natured 2001 show built around ABBA songs ran for almost 14 years. It's the longest-running jukebox musical -- a musical built around previously released pop songs -- in Broadway history.
Hide Caption
3 of 11
11 photos: Broadway blockbusters
"Hairspray" might have seemed an unlikely source for a musical -- a John Waters film about 1960s high schoolers? -- but it was a smash when it debuted in 2002 and ran for more than 2,500 performances. It also picked up a Tony for best musical.
Hide Caption
4 of 11
11 photos: Broadway blockbusters
"Avenue Q" seemed the quintessential off-Broadway show: a little quirky, as if "Sesame Street" were crossed with a black comedy about 20-somethings. But it proved to have great staying power when it came to the Great White Way, running for more than 2,500 performances and winning a Tony for best musical in 2004.
Hide Caption
5 of 11
11 photos: Broadway blockbusters
"Wicked" fell short of a best musical Tony, with "Avenue Q" taking the prize in 2004. But it's had a long life, with devoted fans queueing up many times to see the story of "The Wizard of Oz" from the Wicked Witch's point of view. It's still going on Broadway after more than 5,000 performances.
Hide Caption
6 of 11
11 photos: Broadway blockbusters
Monty Python on Broadway? Eric Idle got the blessing of his cohorts to turn "Monty Python and the Holy Grail" into a musical, and the result won three Tonys, including best musical, in 2005. It ran for more than 1,500 performances and has toured all over the world. At one point, Clay Aiken, pictured, joined the cast as Sir Robin.
Hide Caption
7 of 11
11 photos: Broadway blockbusters
"Jersey Boys" could have been a simple jukebox musical, but the story of the Four Seasons had too much going for it to fit into that (juke) box. The result won best musical at the 2006 Tonys and is still running, more than 4,000 performances later.
Hide Caption
8 of 11
11 photos: Broadway blockbusters
"Billy Elliot: The Musical," based on the 2000 film about a boy who loves ballet in the midst of a grim UK miners' strike, had the benefit of a superstar music writer: Elton John. (Lyrics and book are by Lee Hall.) The show won best musical at the 2009 Tonys, one of 10 honors it received. The show ran for more than three years.
Hide Caption
9 of 11
11 photos: Broadway blockbusters
When the "South Park" guys, Trey Parker and Matt Stone, teamed up with "Avenue Q's" Robert Lopez, who knew what would happen? The result, "The Book of Mormon," was one of the most rapturously reviewed shows of recent years and won nine Tony Awards in 2011, including best musical. It's still running almost six years later.
Hide Caption
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
