<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2016 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 15:11:53 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 15:11:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<item>
<title>'Black girl magic' is more than a hashtag, it's a movement</title>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676982/s/4dd117ef/sc/13/l/0L0Scnn0N0C20A160C0A20C240Cliving0Cblack0Egirl0Emagic0Efeat0Cindex0Bhtml0Deref0Frss0Ishowbiz/story01.htm</link>
<description>&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392614429/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd117ef/sc/13/rc/1/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392614429/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd117ef/sc/13/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392614429/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd117ef/sc/13/rc/2/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392614429/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd117ef/sc/13/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392614429/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd117ef/sc/13/rc/3/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392614429/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd117ef/sc/13/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392614429/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd117ef/sc/13/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392614429/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd117ef/sc/13/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392614429/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd117ef/sc/13/ach.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392614429/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd117ef/sc/13/ach.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/247392614429/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd117ef/sc/13/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi2.feedsportal.com/r/247392614429/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd117ef/sc/13/a2t2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676982/s/4dd117ef/sc/13/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 11:52:50 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2016/02/24/living/black-girl-magic-feat/index.html</guid>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160223160831-maria-borges-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" lang="" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160223160831-maria-borges-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>A photo posted by HAUTE GREEKS COUTURE, INC. (@hautegreekscouture) on
Dec 30, 2015 at 12:32am PST
HauteGreeksCouture is Smith's Instagram clothing boutique. She ships thousands of orders per week, she said, to clients ranging from recent high school graduates to broadcaster Gayle King.  Her apparel boasts messages such as: "Black Women Are Magic," "Black by Popular Demand," and even lyrics from Beyoncé's new song "Formation."
" Formation ," a tribute to Beyoncé's black heritage and the beauty of the black woman, made waves when it was released two weeks ago, with some calling the song and video's message racist or anti-police.
A video posted by LYRIC the DIVA (official page) (@lyrichurd) on
Feb 16, 2016 at 6:01pm PST
By now, anyone plugged into social media has seen the terms #blackgirlmagic, #beingablackgirlislist or #melaninonfleek. These hashtags are accompanied by a range of photos, from black women rocking natural tresses to Beyoncé's backup dancers at Super Bowl 50 or simply a photo of a small child basking in the sun's rays.
But #blackgirlmagic and similar phrases have become more than just a hashtag on social media or a caption for tweets during Black History Month.
"The concept is important because it names and identifies the ways that black women make space for themselves, celebrate themselves, and connect to each other," said Asia Leeds, an assistant professor at Spelman College in Atlanta. "I think that the various hashtags allow us to curate our magic and facilitate new connections and discoveries."
There has even been backlash about the weight that #blackgirlmagic carries.  A writer at Elle.com explained why she's not on board with the movement.  "Black girls aren't magical. We're human," she wrote.
Tianna Sankey, 15, explained what the hashtags mean to her and why they're necessary.
✨✊&#127998;
A photo posted by BLACK BEAUTIES (@blkgirls) on
Feb 14, 2016 at 9:35am PST
The high-schooler created blkgirls , a page on Instagram dedicated to showing beauty and excellence among black women across the world.  She curates this content by using #blackgirlmagic, #melaninonfleek and #blackgirlsmatter. Sankey created the page last year and has already gained over 60,000 followers.
"My entire motive was simply to highlight the beauty of the black woman and promote self-love," said Sankey, who lived in Jamaica until she was 11 and moved to the United States four years ago with her family.
"This type of space was needed because black girls and women need to know it's not OK for those 'black jokes' being made and it's not OK to feel like you're any less than anyone else because of the color of your skin."
Sankey said she gets daily messages from women and young girls telling her that her page has changed how they feel about themselves.
Phrases like #beingablackgirlislit #blackgirlmagic #melaninpopping are being used by black women among each other to affirm their beauty and intellectual prowess, unapologetically celebrating every inch of themselves and each other. Spelman professor Michelle Hite said it's a natural outgrowth of the way black women support each other offline.
A photo posted by Your Worst Nightmare (@blackgoldmelanin) on
Jan 4, 2016 at 5:58pm PST
Hite, who teaches English studies, said the phrases have become a way for black women to say, "I see you [black woman] and I see you excelling and being successful in a context that is hostile to your very presence there, which makes it all the more glorious."  Hite admitted it has been her affirming relationships with black women that have made her "recovery" possible.
Many black women have to recover from the traumas they may experience simply being a black woman in today's society, according to Hite.
Hite recalled that during a group discussion, a student told her about attending a sleepover with white friends. The student came out of the bathroom wearing a headscarf, which was used to protect her hair at night. She said the girls at the sleepover told the student she looked like Aunt Jemima. Hite said the student couldn't muster a response. On an overnight college visit, the student wore the same headscarf and a black student told her she looked like an African princess.
"It was the same scene but the outcome enabled her to recuperate her sense of dignity and a sense of humanity that was no longer humiliated by something that she was doing everyday but all of a sudden in this context with these white girls it became shameful," Hite said.
"It's black women who have acknowledged that 'I've done enough.'  Black women, who have always been the ones who have given me permission to love myself and like myself."
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
