<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2016 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 15:11:53 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 15:11:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<item>
<title>Terry Crews: Porn addiction 'messed up my life'</title>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676982/s/4dd261c1/sc/28/l/0L0Scnn0N0C20A160C0A20C240Centertainment0Cterry0Ecrews0Eporn0Eaddition0Efeat0Cindex0Bhtml0Deref0Frss0Ishowbiz/story01.htm</link>
<description>"Brooklyn Nine-Nine" actor Terry Crews is opening up about his addiction to pornography, which he says "really, really messed up my life."&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392637569/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd261c1/sc/28/rc/1/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392637569/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd261c1/sc/28/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392637569/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd261c1/sc/28/rc/2/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392637569/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd261c1/sc/28/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392637569/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd261c1/sc/28/rc/3/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392637569/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd261c1/sc/28/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392637569/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd261c1/sc/28/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392637569/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd261c1/sc/28/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392637569/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd261c1/sc/28/ach.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392637569/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd261c1/sc/28/ach.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/247392637569/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd261c1/sc/28/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi2.feedsportal.com/r/247392637569/u/89/f/676982/c/35494/s/4dd261c1/sc/28/a2t2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676982/s/4dd261c1/sc/28/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 20:54:10 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2016/02/24/entertainment/terry-crews-porn-addition-feat/index.html</guid>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160224065556-01-terry-crews-file-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" lang="" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160224065556-01-terry-crews-file-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>Facebook Twitter Instagram
&lt;div class="banner" id="cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0_banner"&gt;&lt;span id="cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" class="_fwph"&gt;&lt;form id="_fw_form_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" style="display:none"&gt;&lt;input type="hidden" name="_fw_input_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" id="_fw_input_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" value="ptgt=s&amp;envp=g_js&amp;w=300&amp;h=250&amp;slau=300x250_sync&amp;adUnit=300x250_sync"&gt;&lt;/form&gt;&lt;span id="_fw_container_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" class="cn-shingle__ad"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id="ad_bnr_atf_01" class="ad-ad_bnr_atf_01 ad-refresh-adbanner"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Terry Crews: Porn addiction 'messed up my life'
Updated 2053 GMT (0453 HKT) February 24, 2016
JUST WATCHED
Football player-turned-actor Terry Crews says he overcame an addiction to pornography
Crews: "It affected everything. My wife was literally like, 'I don't know you anymore' "
(CNN)
"Brooklyn Nine-Nine" actor Terry Crews is opening up about his addiction to pornography, which he says "really, really messed up my life."
In a new series of videos posted to Facebook, the former NFL player says he had to go to rehab for his addiction, which consumed him and threatened his marriage.
"Some people say, 'Hey, man ... you can't really be addicted to pornography.' But I'm gonna tell you something: If day turns into night and you are still watching, you probably have got a problem. And that was me," he said.
"It changes the way you think about people. People become objects. People become body parts; they become things to be used rather than people to be loved."
Crews said he kept his porn habit secret from everyone, including his wife. He and singer Rebecca King Crews have been married since 1990 and have five children.
Read More
"It affected everything. My wife was literally like, 'I don't know you anymore. I'm out of here.' I had to change," said the muscled actor, who added that he quit viewing porn six or seven years ago. "I literally had to go to rehab for it."
Crews revealed his porn addiction publicly in 2014, but his new confessional videos have brought heightened attention to his struggles. His first Facebook video, posted two weeks ago, has attracted almost 3 million views and more than 10,000 comments.
"Thank you so much for this message, Terry. Your honesty humbles me," said one man on Facebook. "I don't smoke, I don't drink, I don't do drugs. But I have wrestled for years - YEARS - with pornography. I am grateful today to say that I have a very specific sobriety date and I have stayed clean for some time now. I work at it every day and I do everything I can to remove its power and hold."
21 photos: Surprising celebrity rehab stays
21 photos: Surprising celebrity rehab stays
Probably one of the most-used words in Hollywood -- aside from "scandal" -- is "rehab." It seems nearly every celebrity has sought treatment at one point or another, although reasons can vary from substance abuse to mental health to simply "undisclosed." "Brooklyn Nine-Nine" actor Terry Crews has admitted in a series of Facebook videos that he has sought treatment for a porn addiction that "messed up my life."
Hide Caption
1 of 21
21 photos: Surprising celebrity rehab stays
A representative for actress Hayden Panettiere revealed she had entered a treatment facility to combat postpartum depression, a condition she'd spoken openly about since the birth of her daughter in December 2014.
Hide Caption
2 of 21
21 photos: Surprising celebrity rehab stays
TMZ reported that Jon Hamm of AMC's "Mad Men," shown here on NBC's "Today" show, completed a 30-day stint in rehab to treat an addiction to alcohol.
Hide Caption
3 of 21
21 photos: Surprising celebrity rehab stays
Selena Gomez's rep confirmed that the 21-year-old voluntarily had a two-week stay at an Arizona-based rehab center in January 2014. The rep wouldn't say what she needed treatment for, just that it didn't have anything to do with drugs or alcohol.
Hide Caption
4 of 21
21 photos: Surprising celebrity rehab stays
MTV's "Total Request Live" may be a distant memory, but Mariah Carey's bizarre 2001 appearance on the program can't be forgotten. That year, Carey rolled onto the "TRL" set wheeling an ice-cream cart and wearing an oversized T-shirt, taking host Carson Daly completely by surpise. After the awkward interview -- during which Daly repeatedly asked her, "What are you doing?!" -- Carey went into rehab for what was initially described as an emotional and physical breakdown. The singer later clarified that the only thing that was wrong with her was exhaustion.
Hide Caption
5 of 21
21 photos: Surprising celebrity rehab stays
After announcing her split from Ashton Kutcher in November 2011, Demi Moore was under such stress that she pulled out of a film project and went to rehab the next January. "Demi has chosen to seek professional assistance to treat her exhaustion and improve her overall health," her rep said at the time.
Hide Caption
6 of 21
21 photos: Surprising celebrity rehab stays
Britney Spears' stint in rehab is now among the most famous, so it might be hard to consider this "surprising." But remember that, at the time, Spears' behavior was much more erratic, and the only thing that was certain was that she was going through some things. Before she "voluntarily checked herself into an undisclosed rehab facility" in 2007, Spears reportedly checked into Eric Clapton's Crossroads treatment facility in Antigua but left after just a day, headed to Florida and then infamously shaved her head.
Hide Caption
7 of 21
21 photos: Surprising celebrity rehab stays
It's unclear whether Dean McDermott was trying to address the rumors that he'd cheated on wife Tori Spelling when he announced that he was going to rehab in January 2014 or if that was just unfortunate timing. Either way, the reality star and actor has said that he's seeking help for "some health and personal issues" and that he's "truly sorry for the mistakes I have made and for the pain I've caused my family."
Hide Caption
8 of 21
21 photos: Surprising celebrity rehab stays
In 2012, singer LeAnn Rimes voluntarily entered a treatment program to deal with stress and anxiety after enduring nonstop scrutiny for her marriage to Eddie Cibrian.
Hide Caption
9 of 21
21 photos: Surprising celebrity rehab stays
When no one was looking, Zac Efron slipped into rehab in 2013 to receive treatment for undisclosed reasons. By January 2014, Efron said he was feeling like a new man.
Hide Caption
10 of 21
21 photos: Surprising celebrity rehab stays
After Chris Brown violated his probation in 2013, we were intrigued when a judge sent him off to rehab instead of jail to deal with his anger problems as well as drug abuse.
Hide Caption
11 of 21
21 photos: Surprising celebrity rehab stays
In January 2014, singer Ke$ha announced that she was seeking treatment for an eating disorder and canceled upcoming concert stops in order to stay on track.
Hide Caption
12 of 21
21 photos: Surprising celebrity rehab stays
In December 2013, director Adam Shankman was admitted into an undisclosed rehab facility for an undisclosed reason. The only thing his rep would say is that the "Hairspray" director's family and friends "support him and wish him well on his journey to recovery."
Hide Caption
13 of 21
21 photos: Surprising celebrity rehab stays
Demi Lovato has been open about her substance abuse, but when she first sought help in 2010, her reps made it very clear that she was "in a treatment center" for "emotional and physical issues."
Hide Caption
14 of 21
21 photos: Surprising celebrity rehab stays
Heather Locklear has entered rehab for both substance abuse and psychological issues. In 2008, she headed for an Arizona treatment facility to contend with anxiety and depression and sought care again in 2012 , although her reps said it was not an inpatient program.
Hide Caption
15 of 21
21 photos: Surprising celebrity rehab stays
David Duchovny admitted entering rehab for sex addiction in 2008, saying in a statement at the time that he "voluntarily entered a facility for ... treatment." Interestingly, he was simultaneously portraying a womanizing writer on Showtime's "Californication."
Hide Caption
16 of 21
21 photos: Surprising celebrity rehab stays
Eva Mendes' 2008 trip to rehab caught many off-guard, and what was even more puzzling was the lack of clarity about what she was seeking treatment for. Mendes' silence led to plenty of theories, many of which involved allegations of substance abuse, but the actress brushed them off. "There are so many lies out there regarding my recent trip to Cirque Lodge," she told Interview magazine in 2008. "But I don't care what people think. I just don't care. So I will neither confirm nor deny."
Hide Caption
17 of 21
21 photos: Surprising celebrity rehab stays
Like fellow actress Eva Mendes, Kirsten Dunst spent part of 2008 seeking treatment at Utah's Cirque Lodge facility. At the time, it was speculated that Dunst's stay was prompted by too much partying, but the actress later said that she was suffering from depression.
Hide Caption
18 of 21
21 photos: Surprising celebrity rehab stays
In 2004, amid gossip about her frighteningly frail physique, Mary-Kate Olsen checked into an undisclosed rehab facility to seek treatment for an eating disorder. "This is a challenge that Mary-Kate has made a decision to face," her rep told People magazine at the time. "This is a challenge she will meet."
Hide Caption
19 of 21
21 photos: Surprising celebrity rehab stays
Tiger Woods declined to say why he spent 45 days in rehab around the start of 2010, but given his admission to having multiple extramarital affairs, it wasn't long before the public tried to fill in the blanks. Woods, however, said that he went to rehab "to take a hard look at myself. And I did, and I've come out better."
Hide Caption
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
