<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2014 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 10:09:24 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Perspective-defying photos</title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/29/travel/forced-perspective-photography-irpt/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/29/travel/forced-perspective-photography-irpt/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>It all started when she kissed the Great Sphinx of Giza.</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2014 06:14:43 EDT</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141028150853-perspective-taj-mahal-vogel-irpt-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141028150853-perspective-taj-mahal-vogel-irpt-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>Travel photos that defy perspective
Join the conversation
By Christina Zdanowicz, CNN
October 30, 2014 -- Updated 1636 GMT (0036 HKT)
"I think I'm a bit too young for him," says Alla Shubina, who kissed the Great Sphinx of Giza during her 2010 trip to Egypt. Click the arrows to see a collection of forced perspective photography from travel destinations around the world.
It took Samuel Jacques 30 tries and 45 minutes to create this shot at Salar de Uyuni in Bolivia. A visual effects artist, "I was trying to get rid of all the small things that made the picture look fake," he said.
Wedding photographer Daniel Stoychev was inspired to try his hand at forced perspective during a few of his engagement photo shoots in Riviera Nayarit, Mexico. "I mean who would refuse such a gift, the sun! I find it romantic and the women loved it," he said.
After spending the afternoon watching planes descend at London's Heathrow Airport, Gary Mantile tried to "catch" a plane. Flickr member Lee Mackey directed Mantile on where to position his hand. It took five tries to master this feat of airplane wizardry .
"Sometime in 2007, I came across a collection of photos where a person replaced famous landmarks with souvenirs or postcards in the foreground," says Ryan McFarland. He traveled to the Central Reserve Bank of Peru in Lima in 2009, where he matched up Peruvian money to the bank.
"It's best to find someone who's taken this photo before and understands the effect that I'm trying to achieve," says John Vogel , who posed for a shot in front of the Taj Mahal in Agra, India, in 2000.
Self-described sweet tooth Alla Shubina confesses that this is her favorite shot. Shubina and her husband got some funny looks from people as she posed for this shot in front of the Hershey Store in Niagara Falls, Ontario.
While visiting Bolivia's salt flats, Salar de Uyuni, you can see many people taking forced perspective photos. Former tour guide Michael Moe has had a lot of practice taking these types of photos -- he is the man coming out of the bottle in this 2007 photo. "There just aren't very many places in the world that you can take these kind of pictures," he said.
The Great Sphinx of Giza just got cooler with a signature pair of sunglasses. Brad Bultman used his creativity when posing with the landmark during his July 2014 trip to Egypt.
Magda Bryla shows off her strength during her trip to Paris in July 2012. "The Eiffel Tower is not so heavy. I lifted it up," joked the Polish tourist.
Niranjan Jahagirdar and his now-wife, Joey Ray, took turns touching the noses of the statues at Bayon Temple in the ancient city of Angkor Thom, Cambodia, in 2011. Their tour guide suggested the poses.
"When I was younger, I used to take pictures of people from a distance and pretended that I was pushing them with my finger, or squishing them with my hand," says Jooliana Kim . She "touched" a hoodoo -- a tall, skinny rock formation that protrudes from the ground -- at Bryce Canyon National Park in Utah.
While honeymooning in Hawaii in 2008, Tara Abadir says she kept hearing the song "Puff the Magic Dragon." "In an effort to recreate that song visually , I instructed my new husband [on] what to do. In the end, I knew I had married someone who could set up the shot."
If Sheri D'Rosario could write a caption for this forced perspective photo , it would read, "South America on a shoestring." D'Rosario posed for this quick photo in 2009 while visiting Salar de Uyuni in Bolivia. She had just spent a year traveling and volunteering all over South America.
"I was being nosey and picked this photo. I know, it's snot very nice," jokes Heidi Thompson, who gave the sphinx a helping hand at the Luxor Hotel and Casino in Las Vegas.
Instagram member transitionpete used to host "squish" challenges asking for people to share photos of their fingers "squishing" an object in the background. The idea stuck with Chrissy Magnesi , who used the technique during her recent visit to the historic Biltmore Estate in Asheville, North Carolina.
Seth Harrington's trip to Portland, Oregon, in March got off to a rocky start. He got sick after eating at a restaurant and spent the first three days of the trip in the bathroom. "When I saw this waterfall from a distance, I knew that I had to have a picture to symbolize my Portland trip," he said.
"It's only common courtesy that someone keep this thing from falling over on some unsuspecting locals," jokes Joseph Baca, who kept the Leaning Tower of Pisa from tipping over during his visit to Italy in June 2012.
HIDE CAPTION
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
