<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2014 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 09:49:44 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_entertainment" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_entertainment"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>What's new on Netflix, Amazon and iTunes</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2014/12/01/showbiz/netflix-amazon-december/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~3/UDqAfsn4kyg/index.html</link>
<description>Just in time for winter breaks and vacations, Netflix and Amazon have added new titles to their streaming options.&lt;img src="//feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~4/UDqAfsn4kyg" height="1" width="1" alt=""/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2014 06:35:35 EST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141022105616-belfort-wolf-of-wall-street-ego-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141022105616-belfort-wolf-of-wall-street-ego-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.cnn.com/2014/12/01/showbiz/netflix-amazon-december/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>What's streaming in December on Netflix, Amazon and iTunes
By Lisa Respers France and Breeanna Hare, CNN
December 2, 2014 -- Updated 1953 GMT (0353 HKT)
Yes, Netflix has announced that season 3 of "House of Cards" is coming in February 2015. But until then you have to watch something right? Here's some of what's streaming for the month of December including "The Wolf of Wall Street" (2013), for which Leonardo DiCaprio earned another Oscar nomination for his uninhibited portrayal of the real-life "wolf of wall street," Jordan Belfort. (Netflix, Amazon)
"Comedy Bang! Bang! Season 3": Scott Aukerman and Reggie Watts keep the laughs coming in the third installment of their popular IFC series. (Netflix)
"Anthony Bourdain: Parts Unknown Season 3": In the third installment of Bourdain's CNN program, he travels around the world, from Las Vegas and the Mississippi Delta to Russia and Mexico. (Netflix)
"The Americans: Season 2": Keri Russell and Matthew Rhys star as covert Russian spies living on American soil in this FX drama, which returns for a third season in January. In the meantime, you can catch up with season 2 at the end of December. (Amazon)
"Midnight Cowboy" (1969): This award-winning classic stars Jon Voight, left, as a young Texas dishwasher named Joe Buck who packs up and moves to New York City where he tries to survive as a male prostitute. Dustin Hoffman also stars. (Amazon)
"12 O'Clock Boys" (2014): This gripping documentary centers on a 12-year-old boy named Pug, who dreams of joining a Baltimore dirt bike crew known as the "12 O'Clock Boys." (Amazon)
"A Haunted House 2" (2014): Marlon Waylans' Malcolm thought he'd shaken all the demons from his life with the first "Haunted House," but the spooks return in this comedic horror sequel. (Netflix)
"American Horror Story: Coven": The witchy good times roll in this New Orleans-set season of Ryan Murphy's "American Horror Story." (Netflix)
"Air Force One" (1997): This action flick is one of the many highlights of Harrison Ford's career. The actor stars as a Vietnam War vet-turned-U.S.-president who must use his combat skills and intelligence to ward off terrorists when his plane is hijacked. (Amazon)
"Almost Famous" (2000): Kate Hudson and Patrick Fugit star in Cameron Crowe's rock drama about a young music journalist who goes on tour with an up-and-coming band in the'70s. (Netflix)
"American Beauty" (1999): Kevin Spacey stars in this Oscar-winning film that tells the story of a suburban father in the middle of a midlife crisis who becomes obsessed with his teen daughter's friend. (Netflix)
"Anchorman 2: The Legend Continues" (2013): Will Ferrell, Christina Applegate and more return in this sequel to 2004's hit "Anchorman: The Legend of Ron Burgundy." (Netflix, Amazon)
"Apocalypse Now" (1979): Martin Sheen stars in this now iconic film about the Vietnam War, directed by Francis Ford Coppola. (Amazon)
"Ava &amp; Lala" (2014): An energetic little girl joins forces with an animal named Lala to battle evil forces in this magical film. (Netflix)
"Knights of Badassdom" (2013): All hell breaks loose when a group of roleplayers conjure up a demon. (Netflix)
"Behaving Badly" (2014): A wager about a mobster's son dating a girl sets off a chain of events in this dark comedy. (Netflix)
"Bewitched" (2005): Nicole Kidman and Will Ferrell star in this big screen remake of the popular TV sitcom. (Netflix)
"Bill Burr: I'm Sorry You Feel That Way" (2014): Burr covers everything from the zombie apocalypse to how too many childhood hugs may be the downfall of man in this Netflix original special. (Netflix)
"Borgman" (2013): A vagrant moves in with a well-to-do family in this Dutch thriller. (Amazon)
"Child of God" (2014): James Franco co-wrote and directed this film based on the novel by Cormac McCarthy about a violent man in the mountains of Tennessee. (Netflix)
"Out of the Clear Blue Sky" (2012): Directed by a family member of one of the victims of the September 11 attacks, this documentary tells the story of the aftermath for Cantor Fitzgerald which lost several employees. (Netflix)
"Dark Skies" (2013): A family's life in the suburbs is disturbed by a dark force. (Netflix)
"The Deadly Bees" (1966): A pop singer battles deadly bees in this campy horror film. (Amazon)
"Don't Blink" (2014): A stranded group tries to solve the mystery of their deserted cabin. (Netflix)
Drive Hard (2014): A former race car driver turned instructor is abducted by a thief in this crime comedy. (Netflix)
"Spy Kids" (2001): The children of secret agents must themselves become spies to save their parents in this adventure. (Amazon)
"Fly Away Home" (1996): A father and daughter attempt to lead a flock of orphaned Canada Geese south in this heartwarming tale. (Amazon)
"I, Frankenstein" (2014): Adam Frakenstein is pursued by a pack of demons who want to learn his secret of longevity. (Netflix)
"Friday the 13th: Entire Series": Enjoy all of the horror franchise featuring the killer Jason. (Amazon)
"Goldfinger" (1964): James Bond uncovers a plot to contaminate the gold in Fort Knox in this action packed film. (Amazon)
"Good People" (2014): It turns out fortune isn't exactly smiling on a destitute couple who find a ton of money in their murdered neighbor's apartment. (Netflix)
"The Honourable Woman: Season 1" : A newly ennobled Baroness uses her time and fortune to try and reconcile the Israelis and Palestinians. (Netflix)
"I Am Ali" (2014): This documentary offers a different perspective on the life of legendary boxer Muhammad Ali outside the ring. (Netflix)
"Jake Squared" (2014): A 50-year-old gets more than he bargained for when he hires an actor to play him and starts filming. (Netflix)
"Jessie: Season 3": A Texas teen moves to the New York City and becomes a nanny for a high-profile family. (Netflix)
"Jewtopia" (2012): A friend asks another to help him pass as Jewish to win his dream girl in this romantic comedy. (Netflix)
"A Knight's Tale" (2001): A squire pulls himself up to become a knight in this drama which takes its title (but not the story) from Chaucer's "The Knight's Tale." (Netflix)
"Labor Day" (2013): A single mother and her son harbor a fugitive in this tale which is part thriller, part love story. (Netflix and Amazon)
"Romy and Michele's High School Reunion" (1997): Best friends return for their high school reunion in this comedy that has become a cult classic. (Netflix)
"Sharknado 2: The Second One" (2014): The sequel to the wildly popular Syfy TV movie finds a freak storm of sharks attacking the Big Apple. (Netflix)
HIDE CAPTION
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
New on Amazon and Netflix in December
&lt;&lt;
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
