<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2014 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 10:09:24 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Extreme hikers go the distance</title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/12/05/travel/irpt-extreme-hikes/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/12/05/travel/irpt-extreme-hikes/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>They had been in Nepal for a week trying to reach Thorong La Pass, 17,769 feet above sea level, when they were caught in a snowstorm, unable to make it to the nearest village. </description>
<pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 06:20:36 EST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141122154029-hike-irpt-vietnam-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141122154029-hike-irpt-vietnam-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>Seeking the thrill: Extreme hikers go the distance
Join the conversation
By Henry Hanks, CNN
December 5, 2014 -- Updated 1149 GMT (1949 HKT)
Extreme hiking may be grueling, but it can allow one to see some of the most beautiful views in the world. Jeremy Aerts called this hike through Nepal the most challenging he has done.
On another hike in Sa Pa, Vietnam, this past spring, Aerts got this photo overlooking mountains and rice paddies just as the fog lifted. He believes the country's beauty is often overlooked by Americans.
Mohit Samant hiked 4 miles to the Pacaya volcano in Guatemala last year. "The first 2 were not so bad; the last 2 were brutal."
Yoann Jezequel hiked 5 miles to the Piton des Neiges volcano, the highest point of La Reunion Island, in 2013. The "Cilaos circus" there is a natural enclosure steep-sided, circular or semi-circular depression formed by the eruption.
Suzanne Lewis followed the path of many bold adventurers, hiking 80 miles along the Everest base camp trek in Nepal in 2011.
The hike and magnificent view "still resonates with me," Lewis said.
Lewis is a veteran hiker, but this was by far the longest hike she has done.
Though she doesn't do extreme hikes regularly, Lia Ocampo will never forget her 2012 hike up the crater of Mount Pinatubo in Zambales, Philippines. The group traversed a 3-mile, rocky and muddy trail leading to the crater of the volcano, some 21 years after its explosive eruption.
She went along with some former colleagues with the U.S. Department of Veterans Affairs to explore this very important place in the volcanic history of the world.
David O'Neill enjoys hiking as a meditative activity, requiring him to live in the moment. In 2012, he was first exposed to the steep, challenging environment of the High Atlas Mountains of Morocco.
O'Neill was very concerned about his health on this hike through the Himalayas, at one point worried he might have high-altitude cerebral edema.
Stephen Briggs stands along the Fisherman's Trail section of the Rota Vicentina on the southern Portuguese coast. He covered more than 30 miles over three days in October, and was rewarded with beautiful coastal views and fresh seafood dinners in small seaside villages.
Markku Rainer Peltonen climbed Ben Nevis, the highest mountain in Scotland in 2009, and this remains one of his most memorable hikes over many years. With weather conditions constantly changing, the hike is quite challenging.
HIDE CAPTION
Extreme hikers seek the thrill
Extreme hikers seek the thrill
Extreme hikers seek the thrill
Extreme hikers seek the thrill
Extreme hikers seek the thrill
Extreme hikers seek the thrill
Extreme hikers seek the thrill
Extreme hikers seek the thrill
Extreme hikers seek the thrill
Extreme hikers seek the thrill
Extreme hikers seek the thrill
Extreme hikers seek the thrill
Extreme hikers seek the thrill
&lt;&lt;
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
