<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2014 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 09:49:44 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_entertainment" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_entertainment"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Kourtney K. is having a....</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2014/12/08/showbiz/celebrity-news-gossip/kourtney-kardashian-baby/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~3/iuwjgOyTje4/index.html</link>
<description>&lt;img src="//feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~4/iuwjgOyTje4" height="1" width="1" alt=""/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 08:07:22 EST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141107075423-kourtney-kardashian-scott-disick-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141107075423-kourtney-kardashian-scott-disick-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.cnn.com/2014/12/08/showbiz/celebrity-news-gossip/kourtney-kardashian-baby/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Kourtney Kardashian is having a ...
By Lisa Respers France, CNN
December 8, 2014 -- Updated 1322 GMT (2122 HKT)
It's another boy for Kourtney Kardashian. The "Keeping Up with the Kardashians" star is expecting her third child with partner Scott Disick and revealed the sex during Sunday's episode of her other E! reality show "Kourtney and Khloé Take the Hamptons." The new arrival will join son Mason, 5, and daughter Penelope, 2.
"Nashville" star Hayden Panettiere is expecting her first child with fiance Wladimir Klitschko, and the actress hasn't been shy about showing off her baby bump. Panettiere, seen here at the 2014 Emmy Awards, was spotted earlier this month wearing a two-piece bathing suit.
Britain's Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge, joins Prince William at a ceremony in London on October 21. She has struggled with severe morning sickness , and it was her first public appearance since Buckingham Palace announced that the pair are awaiting baby No. 2 in April.
Stanley Tucci and his wife, Felicity Blunt, are expecting their first child together, but Tucci already has plenty of experience with diaper duty. The "Hunger Games" actor has three other children from his marriage to Kate Tucci, who died of cancer in 2009.
For Blake Lively and Ryan Reynolds, it seems a picture is the best way to say "we're expecting." The couple, who married in 2012, announced their impending arrival with a photo of Lively cradling a growing baby bump on her website Preserve.
With "Avengers: Age of Ultron" wrapped, Cobie Smulders is turning her attention to family. The actress and her husband, Taran Killam, are expecting their second child. They're also parents to daughter Shaelyn, 5.
Donald Faison and CaCee Cobb are adding another member to their family. After welcoming their first child, Rocco, in August 2013, the couple have shared their latest baby news on Instagram. This will be actor Faison's sixth child; he also has four children from prior relationships.
Alfonso Ribeiro had some big news to share during the October 27 episode of "Dancing with the Stars." The actor and "DWTS" competitor revealed that he and his wife, Angela Unkrich, are expecting their second child together. Ribeiro also has a daughter from a prior marriage.
Kimora Lee Simmons has some news that's "Just Fab." The mom of three and president of a shoe and style company is expecting a child with new husband Tim Leissner, whom she wed in February.
Nothing here for Jessica Pare to be "Mad" about! The "Mad Men" actress and her boyfriend, John Kastner, are expecting their first child together.
Steven Tyler has something new to sing about. The Aerosmith frontman's daughter Liv is reportedly expecting her second child. Her 9-year-old son, Milo, is from her marriage to British musician Royston Langdon. Liv Tyler is currently said to be dating David Beckham's pal Dave Gardner.
Linda Perry, left, and Sara Gilbert are adding an addition to their family. The couple, who wed in March, are now expecting their first child together. Gilbert has two kids from a prior relationship with TV producer Allison Adler.
Carrie Underwood tweeted on September 1: "In honor of 'Labor' Day...Ace &amp; Penny would like to make an announcement. Their parents couldn't be happier!"
Shakira and her athlete beau, Gerard Pique, are making room for one more. The Colombian singer announced on August 28 that she and Pique are expecting their second child together. Their first child, son Milan, was born in January 2013.
Milla Jovovich announced via Facebook in August that she and her husband, director Paul W. S. Anderson, are delaying filming "Resident Evil: The Final Chapter" because she is pregnant with their second child.
R&amp;B star Alicia Keys and her husband, Swizz Beatz, will soon be singing more lullabies. The couple celebrated their fourth wedding anniversary on July 31 with the announcement that they're expecting their second child.
After playing coy about Zoe Saldana's growing baby bump, the actress and husband Marco Perego eventually confirmed that they're expecting.
Nick Lachey and wife, Vanessa, are thinking pink. He announced on Twitter that they're expecting their second child together, and it's going to be a girl. "Can't think of a better way to celebrate 3 years of marriage to my beautiful Vanessa than this," he shared. The Lacheys previously welcomed son Camden in 2012.
"Scandal" star Scott Foley will soon have a family of five with his wife, Marika Dominczyk. The pair revealed on Twitter that they're expecting their third child together.
Poppy Montgomery will soon be a mom of three. The "Unforgettable" actress, who's married to Microsoft exec Shawn Sanford, is expecting her third child.
Dax Shepard and Kristen Bell are quickly adding to their family. According to "Entertainment Tonight," the couple are expecting their second child, a year after welcoming daughter Lincoln.
"Obvious Child" actress Gaby Hoffmann showed off an obvious baby bump at her movie's premiere on June 5. According to People magazine , she's expecting her first child.
Rosamund Pike is pregnant with her second child with Robie Uniacke, her rep told US Weekly . The couple are also parents of son Solo.
Tila Tequila surprised her fans on April 18 with the announcement that she's pregnant. The former reality star displayed her growing baby bump on Facebook . "I just couldn't hold it in any longer," the mom-to-be captioned the photo. "(T)his brings me so much joy and happiness to know that there is a baby Tila on the way!" she said.
HIDE CAPTION
Oh, baby! Growing celebrity families
Oh, baby! Growing celebrity families
Oh, baby! Growing celebrity families
Oh, baby! Growing celebrity families
Oh, baby! Growing celebrity families
Oh, baby! Growing celebrity families
Oh, baby! Growing celebrity families
Oh, baby! Growing celebrity families
Oh, baby! Growing celebrity families
Oh, baby! Growing celebrity families
Oh, baby! Growing celebrity families
Oh, baby! Growing celebrity families
Oh, baby! Growing celebrity families
Oh, baby! Growing celebrity families
Oh, baby! Growing celebrity families
Oh, baby! Growing celebrity families
Oh, baby! Growing celebrity families
Oh, baby! Growing celebrity families
Oh, baby! Growing celebrity families
Oh, baby! Growing celebrity families
Oh, baby! Growing celebrity families
Oh, baby! Growing celebrity families
Oh, baby! Growing celebrity families
Oh, baby! Growing celebrity families
&lt;&lt;
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
