<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2014 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 09:49:44 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_entertainment" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_entertainment"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>'Eaten Alive' leaves viewers hungry for more</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2014/12/06/showbiz/discovery-channel-anaconda/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~3/6qethL0H8pY/index.html</link>
<description>Paul Rosolie says he was eaten alive by a giant green anaconda, the largest and most powerful snake in the world.&lt;img src="//feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~4/6qethL0H8pY" height="1" width="1" alt=""/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 14:35:55 EST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141110144930-erin-dnt-moos-man-eaten-by-anaconda-00001219-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141110144930-erin-dnt-moos-man-eaten-by-anaconda-00001219-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.cnn.com/2014/12/06/showbiz/discovery-channel-anaconda/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Rosolie presented himself as prey to the snake after putting on a special reinforced suit with helmet and devices to measure his vital signs, he said before the show aired in a news release on the Discovery Channel website .
Before the special, Rosolie claimed that he spent an hour inside the snake, which was difficult because he's claustrophobic.
"She got me right in the face," Rosolie said. "The last thing I saw was her mouth wide open before everything went black. As this happened, she wrapped around me and took me off of my feet. I felt the suit cracking. It felt as if my arms were ripping out of their sockets."
Rosolie didn't say much more about his experience in the western Amazon, which was filmed in advance, because he wanted everybody to tune in.
Some CNN.com commenters were left hungry for more substance after watching.
"The last 30 minutes of the program shows him wrestling with the snake then trying to get but never getting eaten -- all of this is punctuated by overproduction (i.e., loud music, short scenes and shots cut together like an action movie, etc.) to add drama where there really is none. When all is said and done, I've been swallowed by as many anacondas as he has," wrote one viewer .
In other words, #EatenAlive will be the modern equivalent of Geraldo opening Al Capone's vault.
— Jason Bittel (@bittelmethis) December 8, 2014
The Discovery Channel said that it was Rosolie's "absolute intention to be eaten alive" but that his and the snake's well-being were of the utmost importance.
Some animal rights organizations complained , but Rosolie says the snake came out fine. "I would not have done this if there were any real chance of hurting or stressing out the snake," he said.
Next, he wants to find the biggest anaconda.
"During an earlier expedition in the Amazon, we encountered a 26-foot-long anaconda that weighed hundreds of pounds," he said. "The snake for the 'Eaten Alive' project was big, about 18 feet long, but we know that there are even larger anacondas out there."
CNN's Sarah LeTrent contributed to this report.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
