<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Sports: Sports News, Scores, Analysis, Schedules &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/2010/07/08/AB582vC_page.html?wprss=rss_sports</link>
<description>The Washington Post Sports section provides sports news, video, scores, analysis and updates about high school, college, and pro sports teams, including the Capitals, Nationals, Redskins, United and Wizards. Post Sports also offers blogs and discussions about the latest sports news.</description>
<language>en</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2012 Washington Post Company</copyright>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2013 07:45:23 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2013 07:45:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>Sports: Sports News, Scores, Analysis, Schedules &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<url>http://media3.washingtonpost.com/wp-srv/hp/image/wp_web.gif</url>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/2010/07/08/AB582vC_page.html?wprss=rss_sports</link>
</image>
<item>
<title>Philadelphia’s Nick Foles sees opportunity where many would see room for failure</title>
<link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636679/s/33b1d486/sc/13/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Csports0Cphiladelphias0Enick0Efoles0Esees0Eopportunity0Ewhere0Emany0Ewould0Esee0Eroom0Efor0Efailure0C20A130C110C140Ca510A4f920E4d5e0E11e30Ebe6b0Ed3d28122e6d40Istory0Bhtml0Dwprss0Frss0Isports/story01.htm</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;PHILADELPHIA — &lt;a data-xslt="_http" href="http://stats.washingtonpost.com/fb/playerstats.asp?id=25798&amp;#38;team=21" target="_blank"&gt;Nick Foles&lt;/a&gt; says he’s a natural optimist. The transfer from Michigan State, a disappointing performance at the 2012 NFL combine, and being thrust this season into an offensive system that doesn’t seem to fit his abilities? &lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/philadelphias-nick-foles-sees-opportunity-where-many-would-see-room-for-failure/2013/11/14/a5104f92-4d5e-11e3-be6b-d3d28122e6d4_story.html?wprss=rss_sports"&gt;Read full article &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636679/s/33b1d486/sc/13/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;div class='mf-viral'&gt;&lt;table border='0'&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td valign='middle'&gt;&lt;a href="http://share.feedsportal.com/share/twitter/?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.washingtonpost.com%2Fsports%2Fphiladelphias-nick-foles-sees-opportunity-where-many-would-see-room-for-failure%2F2013%2F11%2F14%2Fa5104f92-4d5e-11e3-be6b-d3d28122e6d4_story.html%3Fwprss%3Drss_sports&amp;t=Philadelphia%E2%80%99s+Nick+Foles+sees+opportunity+where+many+would+see+room+for+failure" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://res3.feedsportal.com/social/twitter.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://share.feedsportal.com/share/facebook/?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.washingtonpost.com%2Fsports%2Fphiladelphias-nick-foles-sees-opportunity-where-many-would-see-room-for-failure%2F2013%2F11%2F14%2Fa5104f92-4d5e-11e3-be6b-d3d28122e6d4_story.html%3Fwprss%3Drss_sports&amp;t=Philadelphia%E2%80%99s+Nick+Foles+sees+opportunity+where+many+would+see+room+for+failure" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://res3.feedsportal.com/social/facebook.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://share.feedsportal.com/share/linkedin/?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.washingtonpost.com%2Fsports%2Fphiladelphias-nick-foles-sees-opportunity-where-many-would-see-room-for-failure%2F2013%2F11%2F14%2Fa5104f92-4d5e-11e3-be6b-d3d28122e6d4_story.html%3Fwprss%3Drss_sports&amp;t=Philadelphia%E2%80%99s+Nick+Foles+sees+opportunity+where+many+would+see+room+for+failure" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://res3.feedsportal.com/social/linkedin.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://share.feedsportal.com/share/gplus/?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.washingtonpost.com%2Fsports%2Fphiladelphias-nick-foles-sees-opportunity-where-many-would-see-room-for-failure%2F2013%2F11%2F14%2Fa5104f92-4d5e-11e3-be6b-d3d28122e6d4_story.html%3Fwprss%3Drss_sports&amp;t=Philadelphia%E2%80%99s+Nick+Foles+sees+opportunity+where+many+would+see+room+for+failure" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://res3.feedsportal.com/social/googleplus.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://share.feedsportal.com/share/email/?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.washingtonpost.com%2Fsports%2Fphiladelphias-nick-foles-sees-opportunity-where-many-would-see-room-for-failure%2F2013%2F11%2F14%2Fa5104f92-4d5e-11e3-be6b-d3d28122e6d4_story.html%3Fwprss%3Drss_sports&amp;t=Philadelphia%E2%80%99s+Nick+Foles+sees+opportunity+where+many+would+see+room+for+failure" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="http://res3.feedsportal.com/social/email.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264152188/u/89/f/636679/c/34656/s/33b1d486/sc/13/rc/1/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264152188/u/89/f/636679/c/34656/s/33b1d486/sc/13/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264152188/u/89/f/636679/c/34656/s/33b1d486/sc/13/rc/2/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264152188/u/89/f/636679/c/34656/s/33b1d486/sc/13/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264152188/u/89/f/636679/c/34656/s/33b1d486/sc/13/rc/3/rc.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264152188/u/89/f/636679/c/34656/s/33b1d486/sc/13/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264152188/u/89/f/636679/c/34656/s/33b1d486/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/180264152188/u/89/f/636679/c/34656/s/33b1d486/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/180264152188/u/89/f/636679/c/34656/s/33b1d486/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;</description>
<category domain="">hp</category>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2013 21:39:33 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/philadelphias-nick-foles-sees-opportunity-where-many-would-see-room-for-failure/2013/11/14/a5104f92-4d5e-11e3-be6b-d3d28122e6d4_story.html?wprss=rss_sports</guid>
<dc:creator>Kent Babb</dc:creator>
<ExtractedText>Explore real-time news, visually
Philadelphia’s Nick Foles sees opportunity where many would see room for failure
Video: Philadelphia Eagles quarterback Nick Foles is putting up very impressive numbers this season. The Post Sports Live crew plays GM and chooses between Foles and RGIII.
By Kent Babb, E-mail the writer
PHILADELPHIA — Nick Foles says he’s a natural optimist. The transfer from Michigan State, a disappointing performance at the 2012 NFL combine and an offensive system this season that doesn’t seem to fit his abilities?
Opportunities, the Philadelphia Eagles quarterback said, not hard times.
Video
The Post Sports Live crew offers bold predictions for what will happen when the Redskins face the Eagles in Philadelphia on Sunday.
More Redskins/NFL coverage
Mike Jones
Facing the Eagles on Sunday, Washington will try to pick up its fourth win of the season.
Optimism keys success for Foles
Kent Babb
The Redskins face an Eagles QB coming off a short run of big success, but it hasn’t always come easily.
NFL Gameday preview: Week 11
Desmond Bieler
Peyton Manning is on track to play when the Broncos face the unbeaten Chiefs in an AFC West Division clash in the marquee matchup of Week 11.
Complete coverage
But the past two games have been different, and he admits that much. The past two weeks, he has combined for 10 passing touchdowns, including seven against Oakland to tie an NFL record. He hasn’t thrown an interception in 136 attempts this season. Heck, the young passer who ran a 5.14-second 40-yard dash before the draft last year even averaged nearly five yards on eight carries in a win Sunday against Green Bay.
No, when it comes to this, Foles said he is a realist.
“I know it’s hard to play at this level every game,” he said, standing at his locker stall this week at the Eagles’ practice facility. “I don’t know of a quarterback in the history of the game that has. I understand that.”
He acknowledged that mistakes are inevitable — a bad pass, a poor half, a disappointing game — but he said he’ll be defined by how he handles it. Which is why so many eyes are on him in Philadelphia and beyond. First-year Coach Chip Kelly has held off on naming Foles his full-time starter, and there are numerous possibilities for this. Is it because Kelly still prefers Michael Vick, the 33-year-old veteran with an injured hamstring, to run an up-tempo, high-speed scheme that relies on a mobile quarterback? Or that Kelly, who has built a coaching career on science and logic, simply doesn’t see the point in revealing his choice?
“Why does it really matter who I say is the starter?” Kelly asked reporters this week.
But the most believable reason is that Foles’s top failure this season is that he hasn’t often failed.  Other than responding to a poor performance against Dallas, he hasn’t yet shown the ability to make in-game adjustments, partly because recently he hasn’t had to.
For Foles’s part, he has handled plenty of obstacles in the past. He signed with Michigan State in 2007 and transferred to Arizona after one season for warmer weather and more likely playing time. Among other things the next three seasons, he made an impression on his future coach by playing his best games against Oregon, where Kelly was building a national power. Foles averaged 387 passing yards in three losses to the Ducks, and it was perhaps enough later to earn Foles a chance when Kelly replaced Andy Reid, who had drafted Foles a year earlier in the third round.
Each time he faced adversity, Foles saw a chance to prove himself.
“I look at it like here’s an opportunity to get better,” he said. “Saying, ‘Here we go again’ doesn’t fix anything. I’m going to be in this situation regardless, so why not look at it with an optimistic attitude?”
Vick beat out Foles to start the season, but Vick has been unable to stay healthy, forcing the second-year passer into the starting lineup the past four games. And though many in Philadelphia speculate the Eagles’ quarterback of the future isn’t yet on the roster, the way Foles has played recently — he has pushed his team with superhuman performances into a first-place tie with Dallas — how could Kelly justify benching him?
Continued
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
