<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2014 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 10:09:24 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Does Mark Wahlberg deserve pardon?</title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/12/09/opinion/yang-mark-wahlberg/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/12/09/opinion/yang-mark-wahlberg/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>Mark Wahlberg's plea for pardon for attacking 2 Vietnamese men exposes race crime inequality, says writer.</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 15:56:02 EST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/140703161556-entt1-mark-wahlberg-07032014-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/140703161556-entt1-mark-wahlberg-07032014-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>Mark Wahlberg doesn't deserve pardon
By Jeff Yang
December 9, 2014 -- Updated 2025 GMT (0425 HKT)
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
Mark Wahlberg petitioned Massachusetts for pardon of his brutal assaults of two men
Jeff Yang: There's a double standard when we judge crimes committed by whites and blacks
In the cases of Eric Garner or Michael Brown, we ask accountability from the victims
Yang: With Wahlberg, he hasn't even show true remorse for the repulsive actions of his youth
Editor's note: Jeff Yang is a columnist for The Wall Street Journal Online and can be heard frequently on radio as a contributor to shows such as PRI's "The Takeaway" and WNYC's "The Brian Lehrer Show." He is the author of "I Am Jackie Chan: My Life in Action" and editor of the graphic novel anthologies "Secret Identities" and "Shattered." The opinions expressed in this commentary are solely those of the author.
(CNN) -- Trayvon Martin. Michael Brown. Eric Garner. The list of names of black men killed by white men who have subsequently gone unpunished -- and in the case of Brown and Garner, untried -- continues to grow. In each of these cases, an ugly theme has been raised in defense of the perpetrators: The victims should have known better.
Why did Garner resist arrest? Why was Martin wearing a hoodie? Why did Brown not meekly get out of the street when ordered to by a police officer? The reasoning goes that their deaths were triggered by their deeds; they need to be held posthumously accountable for their conduct.
When it comes to the actions of their white killers, however, the accountability hawks fall suddenly silent.
Jeff Yang
In their eyes, accountability is apparently only for the dark-skinned (for being "uppity" or vulgar), the poor (for failing to bootstrap themselves into success), the recently immigrated (for failing to "mainstream" into American society) -- and, as we've also seen, for women for failing to avoid sexual predators and LGBTs for being too blatant about their sexuality.
A flagrant new example of this "accountability for thee, but not for me" sensibility emerged last week, when New England Cable News reported that actor Mark Wahlberg -- one of Hollywood's most bankable leading men, who scored a staggering $16 million paycheck for his turn as a heroic father and inventor in the most recent "Transformers" movie -- has petitioned Massachusetts for pardon of his brutal assaults on a pair of Vietnamese men, Tranh Lam and Hoa Trinh, while a teenager in Dorchester, Massachusetts.
Los Angeles Lakers' Kobe Bryant, center, warms up before an NBA basketball game against the Sacramento Kings on Tuesday, December 9, in Los Angeles. The team wore "I Can't Breathe" shirts during warm-ups in support of the family of Eric Garner. Since a grand jury declined to indict a New York police officer in the death of Garner, demonstrators across the country have taken to the streets to express their outrage. Garner, a 43-year-old asthmatic, died in July after he was put in a chokehold by the officer, Daniel Pantaleo.
Protesters gather in front of the Barclays Center during an NBA game in New York on Monday, December 8.
Police clash with demonstrators at the entrance of a Target near the Barclays Center on December 8.
Seven-year-old Elijah Owens, left, stands by people participating in a "die-in" demonstration outside the Philadelphia Eagles' stadium in Philadelphia on Sunday, December 7.
People protest in the streets of Chicago on December 7.
Demonstrators retreat in Berkeley, California, after police deploy tear gas during a protest that turned violent before dawn on December 7.
A police officer in Berkeley clashes with a protester on December 7.
A police officer raises a shotgun toward the crowd in Berkeley on Saturday, December 6.
People in Los Angeles lie down during a "die-in" on Hollywood Boulevard on December 6.
Police stand guard as protesters participate in a "die-in" December 6 at Grand Central Station in New York.
Protesters shut down all eastbound and westbound lanes on Interstate 195, which links Miami Beach to the mainland, on Friday, December 5.
Demonstrators march through the Loop in Chicago on December 5.
Protesters block an intersection in downtown Washington on December 5.
Demonstrators march through a Macy's in Manhattan before staging a "die-in" at the iconic department store on December 5.
Police make an arrest as protesters march through Manhattan early on December 5.
Police officers form a line with demonstrations under way in Oakland, California, on Thursday, December 4.
A demonstrator gets arrested during a protest in New York on December 4.
Police detain a protester in New York on December 4.
Demonstrators gather in New York's Foley Square on December 4.
Police officers in New York staff a barricade at a Brooklyn Bridge exit ramp on December 4.
Demonstrators march across the Brooklyn Bridge on December 4.
"Black Lives Matter" is written across the cheek of Samaria Muhammad as she chants with fellow protesters in Atlanta on December 4.
Demonstrators block the entrance to the Lincoln Tunnel in New York on Wednesday, December 3.
Protesters lie down in Grand Central Station on December 3.
A demonstrator cries at a protest in Philadelphia on December 3.
Demonstrators block traffic on Interstate 395 in Washington on December 3.
A woman speaks during a demonstration in Oakland on December 3.
Police officers stand guard in New York's Times Square on December 3.
Protesters rally near Rockefeller Center during a ceremony to light the Rockefeller Center Christmas Tree in New York.
Protesters face off with police in Oakland.
Demonstrators lie in the streets of St. Louis on December 3.
Protests after Eric Garner grand jury decision
Protests after Eric Garner grand jury decision
Protests after Eric Garner grand jury decision
Protests after Eric Garner grand jury decision
Protests after Eric Garner grand jury decision
Protests after Eric Garner grand jury decision
Protests after Eric Garner grand jury decision
Protests after Eric Garner grand jury decision
Protests after Eric Garner grand jury decision
Protests after Eric Garner grand jury decision
Protests after Eric Garner grand jury decision
Protests after Eric Garner grand jury decision
Protests after Eric Garner grand jury decision
Protests after Eric Garner grand jury decision
Protests after Eric Garner grand jury decision
Protests after Eric Garner grand jury decision
Protests after Eric Garner grand jury decision
Protests after Eric Garner grand jury decision
Protests after Eric Garner grand jury decision
Protests after Eric Garner grand jury decision
Protests after Eric Garner grand jury decision
Protests after Eric Garner grand jury decision
Protests after Eric Garner grand jury decision
Protests after Eric Garner grand jury decision
Protests after Eric Garner grand jury decision
Protests after Eric Garner grand jury decision
Protests after Eric Garner grand jury decision
Protests after Eric Garner grand jury decision
Protests after Eric Garner grand jury decision
Protests after Eric Garner grand jury decision
Protests after Eric Garner grand jury decision
HIDE CAPTION
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
