<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2013 18:54:09 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_sport" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_sport"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Marquez makes history </title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://edition.cnn.com/2013/11/10/sport/motorsport/motorsport-marquez-youngest-world-champion/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~3/m6mx-KBage8/index.html</link>
<description>Spain's Marc Marquez became the youngest rider to ever win the MotoGP world championship on Sunday after finishing third at the final race of the season in Valencia.&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~4/m6mx-KBage8" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 09:14:10 EST</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/11/10/sport/motorsport/motorsport-marquez-youngest-world-champion/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Marc Marquez becomes youngest MotoGP world champion
November 10, 2013 -- Updated 2235 GMT (0635 HKT)
Marc Marquez is hoisted aloft after claiming the MotoGP title. The 20-year-old Spaniard is the youngest rider ever to win the world championship.
Marquez (right) made an immediate impression in MotoGP, finishing third in the opening race of the season. Jorge Lorenzo (center) won the race with Valentino Rossi finishing second.
Marquez stormed to victory in only the second race of season at GP Circuit of the Americas. At 20 years and 63 days old, Marquez became the youngest winner of a MotoGP race beating U.S. rider Freddie Spencer's record (20 years, 196 days).
Marquez has claimed nine pole positions, six wins and been on the podium in every race he has finished this season.
Marquez had won the previous four races before the British GP in September and was almost out of sight in the world championship standings. But reigning world champion Jorge Lorenzo reignited his title challenge with a stunning win over his young compatriot at Silverstone.
Race marshalls show Marquez the black flag at the Australian GP in October. The Honda rider was disqualified for exceeding the maximum number of laps allowed before a driver must complete a pit stop. Lorenzo took the checkered flag to keep his title chances alive.
Jorge Lorenzo secures a seventh win of the season in the penultimate race of the season at the Motegi Circuit in Japan.
HIDE CAPTION
Spanish rookie creates history after an incredible MotoGP season
Twenty-year-old Marquez beats U.S. rider Freddie Spencer's record set in 1983
Honda rider is also the first rookie to win since Kenny Roberts in 1978
Double world champion Jorge Lorenzo finishes four points behind Marquez
(CNN) -- Spain's Marc Marquez became the youngest rider to ever win the MotoGP world championship on Sunday after finishing third at the final race of the season in Valencia.
The 20-year-old rookie only needed to finish fourth to ensure that the 13-point lead he took into the race could not be overhauled and he duly delivered.
Two-time world champion, Jorge Lorenzo did all he could to put the pressure on his young rival taking the chequered flag to claim his eighth win of the season with Dani Pedrosa finishing second. But it was Marquez who stole all the headlines.
At 20 years and 266 days old, the Honda rider beats the previous record set by American Freddie Spencer who won the 500cc title in 1983 when he was 21 years, 258 days old.
I cannot explain what I feel, (it is) a dream come true
Marc Marquez
"I cannot explain what I feel, (it is) a dream come true," Marquez said.
"Maybe I was clear too early (in the season) and then Jorge came charging at the end and I had to keep my nerve in the final race. I am overjoyed," he added.
Lorenzo finally ran out of track in his attempt to reign in the lead Marquez built in the first half of the season. Five wins in the final seven races made for a thrilling climax with Lorenzo finishing just four points adrift of his compatriot.
MotoGP: 2013 final standings
In a season where records tumbled, the young Catalan announced his arrival with a fastest lap in qualifying and a podium finish in the opening race in Qatar.
At the next race he claimed his maiden MotoGP win at the Grand Prix of the Americas to become the youngest ever winner of a premier class GP.
Five more wins followed but it was Marquez's incredible consistency that proved the difference with podium placings in every race he finished (16 out of 18).
Marquez also becomes the first rookie to win motorcycling's premier racing class since America's Kenny Roberts achieved the feat in 1978.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
