<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Post Politics: Breaking Politics News, Political Analysis &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/politics?wprss=rss_politics</link>
<description>Post Politics from The Washington Post is the source for political news headlines, in-depth politics coverage and political opinion, plus breaking news on the Obama administration and White House, Congress, the Supreme Court, elections and more.</description>
<language>en</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2012 Washington Post Company</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 16:41:09 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 16:41:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>Post Politics: Breaking Politics News, Political Analysis &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<url>http://media3.washingtonpost.com/wp-srv/hp/image/wp_web.gif</url>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/politics?wprss=rss_politics</link>
</image>
<item>
<title>The Fix: Hillary Clinton is the ultimate Washington insider. That’s not necessarily a bad thing.</title>
<link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636655/s/414ef1a0/sc/36/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cpolitics0Chillary0Eclinton0Eis0Ethe0Eultimate0Ewashington0Einsider0Ethats0Enot0Enecessarily0Ea0Ebad0Ething0C20A140C120C10A0Cc51a7bf20Eb82d0E4a2e0Ea0A820E4d923948336f0Istory0Bhtml0Dwprss0Frss0Ipolitics/story01.htm</link>
<description>&lt;p/&gt; &lt;p&gt;If there's one thing we learned in the last few elections, it's that people hate Washington. And being associated with Washington is a huge political liability.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Right? Well, maybe not.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Witness this data from &lt;a data-xslt="_http" href="http://www.bloomberg.com/politics/articles/2014-12-08/clinton-trumps-republican-rivals-on-leadership-vision-for-2016"&gt;Bloomberg's latest poll&lt;/a&gt;. The poll asked people about several aspects of Hillary Clinton's resume, and whether they thought each was a plus or a minus.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/hillary-clinton-is-the-ultimate-washington-insider-thats-not-necessarily-a-bad-thing/2014/12/10/c51a7bf2-b82d-4a2e-a082-4d923948336f_story.html?wprss=rss_politics"&gt;Read full article &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636655/s/414ef1a0/sc/36/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612680053/u/89/f/636655/c/34656/s/414ef1a0/sc/36/rc/1/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612680053/u/89/f/636655/c/34656/s/414ef1a0/sc/36/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612680053/u/89/f/636655/c/34656/s/414ef1a0/sc/36/rc/2/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612680053/u/89/f/636655/c/34656/s/414ef1a0/sc/36/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612680053/u/89/f/636655/c/34656/s/414ef1a0/sc/36/rc/3/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612680053/u/89/f/636655/c/34656/s/414ef1a0/sc/36/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612680053/u/89/f/636655/c/34656/s/414ef1a0/sc/36/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612680053/u/89/f/636655/c/34656/s/414ef1a0/sc/36/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/214612680053/u/89/f/636655/c/34656/s/414ef1a0/sc/36/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;</description>
<category domain="">Campaign 2016</category>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 16:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/hillary-clinton-is-the-ultimate-washington-insider-thats-not-necessarily-a-bad-thing/2014/12/10/c51a7bf2-b82d-4a2e-a082-4d923948336f_story.html?wprss=rss_politics</guid>
<dc:creator>Aaron Blake</dc:creator>
<ExtractedText>By Aaron Blake December 10 at 11:38 AM Follow @aaronblakewp
Former U.S. Secretary of State Hillary Rodham Clinton speaks to the Economic Club of Chicago at Fairmont Hotel in Chicago on Wednesday, Oct. 8, 2014. Clinton lent a hand to Illinois Gov. Pat Quinn's re-election campaign Wednesday with a fundraiser and a quick, controlled public appearance in a chat over coffee. (AP Photo/Nam Y. Huh)
If there's one thing we learned in the last few elections, it's that people hate Washington. And being associated with Washington is a huge political liability.
Right? Well, maybe not.
Witness this data from Bloomberg's latest poll . The poll asked people about several aspects of Hillary Clinton's resume, and whether they thought each was a plus or a minus.
Almost all of these statements are some variation on Clinton being a D.C. insider. And Clinton gets positive marks on each of them. She even gets positive marks for "She has close ties to Wall Street," which is a statement that could just as easily appear in an attack ad against Hillary Clinton.
Clinton's best marks, in fact, are on the only statement actually mentioning Washington: "She has lived in Washington and worked in the federal government"; 78 percent say that's an advantage, versus just 20 percent who said it's a disadvantage. And despite President Obama's approval rating being around 40 percent, about six in 10 Americans say Clinton's work in the Obama Administration is a good thing for her.
Clinton's overall favorable rating in the poll, we would point out, is 52 percent. In other words, plenty of people who otherwise don't really like her think her lengthy career in government and insider status is a feather in her cap rather than a liability.
Those numbers call into question whether it's really a bad thing to be a "Washington insider." We suspect it is a bad thing when the candidates aren't very well-known. In that case, voting for the non-Washington candidate is the easiest way to show your contempt for Congress. When it's businessman David Perdue versus Congressman Jack Kingston in the Georgia GOP Senate runoff, that "congressman" label probably isn't helpful to people who don't really know Kingston. (We have made this argument before in regards whether the Republican Party would actually nominate a confirmed tea partier for president. We were dubious.)
When it comes to someone like Clinton, though, it's hard to argue that her being a Washington insider -- or even another Clinton, for that matter -- is a massive problem for her.
In fact, this poll suggests it just might help.
Aaron Blake covers national politics and writes regularly for The Fix.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
