<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Post Politics: Breaking Politics News, Political Analysis &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/politics?wprss=rss_politics</link>
<description>Post Politics from The Washington Post is the source for political news headlines, in-depth politics coverage and political opinion, plus breaking news on the Obama administration and White House, Congress, the Supreme Court, elections and more.</description>
<language>en</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2012 Washington Post Company</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 15:51:24 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 15:51:24 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>Post Politics: Breaking Politics News, Political Analysis &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<url>http://media3.washingtonpost.com/wp-srv/hp/image/wp_web.gif</url>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/politics?wprss=rss_politics</link>
</image>
<item>
<title>Obama’s foreign policy plans collide with wars abroad and politics at home</title>
<link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636655/s/414e213a/sc/1/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cpolitics0Cobamas0Eforeign0Epolicy0Eplans0Ecollide0Ewith0Ewars0Eabroad0Eand0Epolitics0Eat0Ehome0C20A140C120C10A0C2675f3d60E7fc50E11e40E88820E0A3cf0A8410Abeb0Istory0Bhtml0Dwprss0Frss0Ipolitics/story01.htm</link>
<description>&lt;p&gt;President Obama has staked much of his foreign policy legacy on ending America’s wars and unwinding what he has described as the excesses of the post-9/11 era.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The release Tuesday of an investigation into &lt;a data-xslt="_http" href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/world/national-security/senate-report-on-cia-program-details-brutality-dishonesty/2014/12/09/1075c726-7f0e-11e4-9f38-95a187e4c1f7_story.html"&gt;brutal CIA interrogation techniques&lt;/a&gt; relegated some of the worst excesses firmly to the past, Obama said, but it also was a reminder of just how much remains to be done.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/obamas-foreign-policy-plans-collide-with-wars-abroad-and-politics-at-home/2014/12/10/2675f3d6-7fc5-11e4-8882-03cf08410beb_story.html?wprss=rss_politics"&gt;Read full article &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636655/s/414e213a/sc/1/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/obamas-foreign-policy-plans-collide-with-wars-abroad-and-politics-at-home/2014/12/10/2675f3d6-7fc5-11e4-8882-03cf08410beb_story.html?wprss=rss_politics</guid>
<dc:creator>Greg Jaffe, Juliet Eilperin</dc:creator>
<ExtractedText>By Greg Jaffe and Juliet Eilperin December 10 at 10:00 AM Follow @GregJaffe Follow @eilperin
President Obama has staked much of his foreign policy legacy on ending America’s wars and unwinding what he has described as the excesses of the post-9/11 era.
The release Tuesday of an investigation into brutal CIA interrogation techniques relegated some of the worst excesses firmly to the past, Obama said, but it also was a reminder of just how much remains to be done.
This list includes the chaotic aftermath of an Iraq war that the president once derided as “dumb,” a still-violent Afghanistan and an offshore military prison that Obama has called “a mess” and “ misguided experiment .”
With two years left in his administration, the president’s major foreign policy goals are colliding with the demands of U.S. politics, lingering fears of another terror attack and a Middle East that increasingly seems on the verge of chaos.
The White House hasn’t abandoned any of its most ambitious foreign policy goals, especially closing the prison at Guantanamo Bay, Cuba .
“Closing Guantanamo is very important to the president,” said Ben Rhodes, deputy national security adviser for strategic communications. “He recognizes that it is emblematic of this entire set of policies and we aren’t going to move past this chapter with Guantanamo open.”
But even some of Obama’s top priorities appear to be in danger. No issue embodies this time crunch and the president’s frustrations more completely than the Guantanamo Bay prison, which for Obama remains a potent symbol of the country’s fearful reaction to the Sept. 11 terror attacks.
Since taking office, Obama has tried to overcome congressional opposition to closing the facility with lofty appeals grounded in American ideals and morality. “Imagine a future 10 or 20 years from now when the United States of America is still holding people who have been charged with no crime on a piece of land that is not part of our country,” he urged an audience at National Defense University last year. “Is this who we are?. . . Is that the America we want to leave to our children?”
In other instances, he has relied on more rational arguments, maintaining that the military prison is costly, inefficient and unnecessary. “No person has ever escaped one of our super-max or military prisons here in the United States — ever,” he said.
Early in his administration, the president insisted Guantanamo was bad foreign policy, undermining America’s “moral authority” in the world.
None of those arguments has moved the United States closer to shutting the prison. The Obama administration seems to have settled on a more incremental approach, stepping up transfers of prisoners who have been cleared for release but can’t be returned to their home countries. About half of the 136 prisoners remaining at Guantanamo fall into this category. Earlier this week, the United States transferred six prisoners — four Syrians, a Tunisian and a Palestinian — to Uruguay after painstaking negotiations that spanned months.
On his recent trip to Asia, the president asked multiple U.S. allies to consider taking in detainees who had been cleared for release, said a senior administration official who asked for anonymity to discuss ongoing negotiations. The official added the administration expects “there to be additional transfers in the coming weeks and months.”
“With persistence and a little bit of luck, we might get the total number of prisoners at Guantanamo down to 50 or 60,” another senior White House official said.
The best hope for the administration is that the smaller number of prisoners and the passage of time will yield a less emotional debate and a compromise with Congress, which has prevented the president from transferring inmates to prison facilities in the United States.
“The real problem in closing Guantanamo is the politics and not the policy,” said Steve Vladeck, a law professor at American University. “That’s what the president has to change.”
In Iraq and Syria, Obama’s biggest challenge isn’t domestic politics, but a policy that his critics say is ill-suited for the bloody, sectarian war that has swept through the region. Two weeks before Islamic State fighters took Iraq’s second largest city, the president in a speech at the United States Military Academy outlined his vision for a foreign policy that would be less reliant on military force. Instead of firepower, the United States would rely more heavily on tools such as foreign aid, military training and economic sanctions to “steer the currents of history.”
That new model, however, collided with a rapacious enemy in the Islamic State .
The president largely is sticking to the playbook that he outlined at West Point. About 3,000 U.S. advisers are training Iraqi forces in several facilities inside Iraq. A coalition of 40 foreign military leaders recently gathered in Washington to discuss the war, “an unprecedented diplomatic moment,” said Dafna H. Rand , a former White House official with the Center for a New American Security.
U.S. planes and helicopters, meanwhile, are attacking Islamic State fighters daily.
White House officials said that the ongoing fight doesn’t represent a return to a war footing in Iraq, where the United States maintained close to 150,000 troops for eight years.
“I acknowledge that it perpetuates the notion that we are engaged militarily against a terrorist enemy,” said Rhodes of the current fight against the Islamic State. “But people can and should see the differences here. There’s a big difference between 150,000 troops and 3,000 troops.”
Another big difference: The president has placed an emphasis on keeping American soldiers out of combat, even if they will be making regular trips to the war zone. “We believe it is a national security objective to not be losing service members in wars,” Rhodes said.
The question facing the White House is whether such modest measures will be enough, especially if the conflicts drag on for years with little progress on the ground.
“Time isn’t on our side,” said James Jeffrey, who served as ambassador to Iraq and has pressed for U.S. advisers to accompany Iraqi forces into combat. “I don’t understand why the administration is dragging its heels.”
Meanwhile, on the Syrian front, Robert Ford , a former U.S. ambassador to the country, called the American plan to train moderate Syrian forces as “a fantasy.”
The White House is preaching patience in Iraq, where Iraqi Army and militia forces have made some modest gains on the ground in recent weeks. In Syria, the battle against the Islamic State likely will stretch well past Obama’s presidency.
There is little talk of victory in the White House. Instead, the focus is keeping the battle on a “sustainable footing” for the next two years.
Such talk isn’t likely to appease those calling for a larger U.S. response in Iraq. Obama also is keenly aware that many of the people who helped put him in office have become frustrated by his inability to deliver on pledges in Iraq and Guantanamo that propelled his candidacy. As he shopped for Christmas presents with his daughters at the Politics and Prose bookstore — a gathering spot for Washington’s intelligentsia — one of his fellow shoppers yelled out what he intended to do about Guantanamo.
“We’re working on it,” Obama replied. “Any other issues?”
juliet.eilperin@washpost.com
Greg Jaffe covers the White House for The Washington Post, where he has been since March 2009.
Juliet Eilperin is a White House correspondent for The Washington Post, covering domestic and foreign policy as well as the culture of 1600 Pennsylvania Avenue. She is the author of two books—one on sharks, and another on Congress, not to be confused with each other—and has worked for the Post since 1998.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
