<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Post Politics: Breaking Politics News, Political Analysis &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/politics?wprss=rss_politics</link>
<description>Post Politics from The Washington Post is the source for political news headlines, in-depth politics coverage and political opinion, plus breaking news on the Obama administration and White House, Congress, the Supreme Court, elections and more.</description>
<language>en</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2012 Washington Post Company</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 16:15:08 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 16:15:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>Post Politics: Breaking Politics News, Political Analysis &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<url>http://media3.washingtonpost.com/wp-srv/hp/image/wp_web.gif</url>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/politics?wprss=rss_politics</link>
</image>
<item>
<title>GovBeat: More governors have won without majority support in the 2010s than in any decade in the past century</title>
<link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636655/s/414e2780/sc/7/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Cmore0Egovernors0Ehave0Ewon0Ewithout0Emajority0Esupport0Ein0Ethe0E20A10As0Ethan0Ein0Eany0Edecade0Ein0Ethe0Epast0Ecentury0C20A140C120C10A0C56fd70Ae30E7b5a0E49290E87890E6b6cdc3662370Istory0Bhtml0Dwprss0Frss0Ipolitics/story01.htm</link>
<description>&lt;p/&gt; &lt;p&gt;The rate of governors being elected without majority voter support is already higher in the 2010s than it has been in any decade in the past century.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In the first four years of the decade, 26.7 percent of gubernatorial elections have been won with just a plurality of the vote. That rate — and the overall number, 24 — was higher only once in the past century. It reached 40 percent in the 1910s, when 76 governors were elected with a mere plurality of the vote, according to &lt;a data-xslt="_http" href="http://blog.lib.umn.edu/cspg/smartpolitics/2014/12/plurality-winning_governors_at.php"&gt;a review of 1,850 gubernatorial elections since 1900&lt;/a&gt;, conducted by Eric Ostermeier, a research associate at the University of Minnesota’s Humphrey School of Public Affairs who writes the blog Smart Politics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/more-governors-have-won-without-majority-support-in-the-2010s-than-in-any-decade-in-the-past-century/2014/12/10/56fd70e3-7b5a-4929-8789-6b6cdc366237_story.html?wprss=rss_politics"&gt;Read full article &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636655/s/414e2780/sc/7/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612678635/u/89/f/636655/c/34656/s/414e2780/sc/7/rc/1/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612678635/u/89/f/636655/c/34656/s/414e2780/sc/7/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612678635/u/89/f/636655/c/34656/s/414e2780/sc/7/rc/2/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612678635/u/89/f/636655/c/34656/s/414e2780/sc/7/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612678635/u/89/f/636655/c/34656/s/414e2780/sc/7/rc/3/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612678635/u/89/f/636655/c/34656/s/414e2780/sc/7/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612678635/u/89/f/636655/c/34656/s/414e2780/sc/7/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612678635/u/89/f/636655/c/34656/s/414e2780/sc/7/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/214612678635/u/89/f/636655/c/34656/s/414e2780/sc/7/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;</description>
<category domain="">newsletter</category>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 16:00:44 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.washingtonpost.com/more-governors-have-won-without-majority-support-in-the-2010s-than-in-any-decade-in-the-past-century/2014/12/10/56fd70e3-7b5a-4929-8789-6b6cdc366237_story.html?wprss=rss_politics</guid>
<dc:creator>Niraj Chokshi</dc:creator>
<ExtractedText>By Niraj Chokshi December 10 at 11:00 AM Follow @NirajC
In this file photo, Rhode Island governor-elect Gina Raimondo can be seen speaking to supporters in early September. She was elected with just under 41 percent of the vote. (AP Photo/Steven Senne)
The rate of governors being elected without majority voter support is already higher in the 2010s than it has been in any decade in the past century.
In the first four years of the decade, 26.7 percent of gubernatorial elections have been won with just a plurality of the vote. That rate — and the overall number, 24 — was higher only once in the past century. It reached 40 percent in the 1910s, when 76 governors were elected with a mere plurality of the vote, according to a review of 1,850 gubernatorial elections since 1900 , conducted by Eric Ostermeier, a research associate at the University of Minnesota’s Humphrey School of Public Affairs who writes the blog Smart Politics.
Incumbents may have largely held on to their seats last month, but that doesn’t mean the races weren’t close. Notably, 10 winning candidates won without the support of a majority of voters.*
“If that sounds like a lot – it is,” Ostermeier wrote. “For it’s just the third time in the last century that the number of governors elected with a plurality of the vote has reached double digits – all since 2002.”
The number and share of governors elected without majority support has steadily risen over the past few decades, a trend Ostermeier partially blames on (or credits to?) a rise in more-viable independent and third party campaigns.
“The last time the U.S. has seen this rate of governors elected without the support of the majority of the electorate was a century ago when Progressives split the Republican Party and support for the Socialist Party was peaking,” he wrote.
Securing only a plurality of the vote is not a great sign for reelection. Of all the plurality governors since 1900 who were not term-limited, only 46 percent were reelected.
* From Ostermeier: “Plurality winners in the 2014 cycle are independent Bill Walker of Alaska (48.1 percent), Democrats John Hickenlooper of Colorado (49.3 percent), David Ige of Hawaii (49.5 percent), John Kitzhaber of Oregon (48.9 percent), Gina Raimondo of Rhode Island (40.7 percent), and Peter Schumlin of Vermont (46.4 percent), and Republicans Rick Scott of Florida (48.1 percent), Sam Brownback of Kansas (49.9 percent), Paul LePage of Maine (48.2 percent), and Charlie Baker of Massachusetts (48.4 percent).”
Niraj Chokshi reports for GovBeat, The Post's state and local policy blog.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
