<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2013 20:08:10 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Entertainment</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/SHOWBIZ/index.html?eref=rss_showbiz</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_entertainment" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_entertainment"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>ABC's Amy Robach has cancer </title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2013/11/11/showbiz/celebrity-news-gossip/amy-robach-gma-cancer/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~3/y-KSZijb-Qw/index.html</link>
<description>ABC News reporter Amy Robach didn't want to get a mammogram, but it ended up saving her life.&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_entertainment/~4/y-KSZijb-Qw" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 09:50:01 EST</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.cnn.com/2013/11/11/showbiz/celebrity-news-gossip/amy-robach-gma-cancer/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>ABC's Amy Robach discovers cancer after on-air mammogram
By Lisa Respers France, CNN
November 12, 2013 -- Updated 0028 GMT (0828 HKT)
Getting a mammogram live on "Good Morning America" for cancer awareness month revealed to ABC's Amy Robach that she had breast cancer. She's not the only high-profile person to battle the disease...
Radio personality Robin Quivers has quietly battled cancer for months, but had happy news to share with "Howard Stern" listeners in September 2013. On the show, Quivers revealed that her doctors now believe she's cancer-free, after receiving treatment, including chemotherapy.
Singer Melissa Etheridge became an advocate for the use of medical marijuana after her 2004 breast cancer diagnosis.
Sharon Jones, performing here in 2011, held off plans to tour and release a new album with the Dap-Kings after being diagnosed with stage 1 bile duct cancer.
Michael Douglas offers some interesting insight as to how he may have developed the throat cancer that he was diagnosed with in August 2010. Douglas later told the "Today" show that his tumor was gone.
Buffalo Bills Hall of Fame quarterback Jim Kelly has been diagnosed with cancer of the upper jaw bone . "Doctors have told me that the prognosis for my recovery is very good," Kelly said in a statement from his former club .
Actress Christina Applegate had a bilateral mastectomy in 2008. Doctors had diagnosed her with cancer in her left breast and offered her the options of either radiation treatment and testing for the rest of her life or removal of both breasts.
In 2006, singer Sheryl Crow underwent minimally invasive surgery for breast cancer. In 2012, she revealed she had a noncancerous brain tumor.
KISS band member Peter Criss sat down with CNN's Elizabeth Cohen in 2009, a year after his battle with breast cancer. The musician said he wanted to increase awareness of the fact that men can also get the disease.
Cynthia Nixon not only joined the cast of Showtime's "The Big C," about a woman battling the disease, and portrayed a woman with cancer in the Broadway play "Wit" -- Nixon was diagnosed with breast cancer in 2006.
Zoraida Sambolin was diagnosed with breast cancer on April 9, and has chosen to have a double mastectomy. "Angelina empowered me to share my story," she writes for CNN.
"Good Morning America" co-host Robin Roberts had been cancer-free for five years in 2012 after beating breast cancer when she revealed she had been diagnosed with myelodysplastic syndrome, also called MDS.
"Three's Company" star Suzanne Somers spoke with CNN's Piers Morgan in 2012 about her stem cell surgery and her bout with breast cancer. She was diagnosed in 2001, which is when she began researching alternative methods to reconstructive surgery.
Olivia Newton-John was diagnosed in 1992, and the singer has become an advocate for breast self-examination.
Actress Kathy Bates didn't share news of her battle until 2012 , eight years after she was diagnosed with ovarian cancer.
Australian singer Kylie Minogue was only 36 when she was diagnosed with breast cancer in 2005.
HIDE CAPTION
Celebrities and battles with cancer
Celebrities and battles with cancer
Celebrities and battles with cancer
Celebrities and battles with cancer
Celebrities and battles with cancer
Celebrities and battles with cancer
Celebrities and battles with cancer
Celebrities and battles with cancer
Celebrities and battles with cancer
Celebrities and battles with cancer
Celebrities and battles with cancer
Celebrities and battles with cancer
Celebrities and battles with cancer
Celebrities and battles with cancer
Celebrities and battles with cancer
Celebrities and battles with cancer
Celebrities and battles with cancer
&lt;&lt;
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
