<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Technology</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/TECH/index.html?eref=rss_tech</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2013 14:41:49 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Technology</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/TECH/index.html?eref=rss_tech</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_technology" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_technology"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Team rebuilding world's first website</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2013/04/30/tech/web/first-website-cern/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_technology/~3/CFo0Sz9cFDA/index.html</link>
<description>Twenty years ago, a team of researchers shared the Web with the world. Now they want to show a generation that grew up online what it was like in its earliest days.&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_technology/~4/CFo0Sz9cFDA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2013 11:54:51 EDT</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://www.cnn.com/2013/04/30/tech/web/first-website-cern/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Team rebuilding world's first website
By Doug Gross, CNN
May 2, 2013 -- Updated 1831 GMT (0231 HKT) | Filed under: Web
The Web's first site was created by CERN in 1989. On April 30, 1993, they made it available to the world royalty-free. The design of the site is very different from Web pages today, but also showed the roots of what was to come. It can be fun to look back through Internet history, so CNN consulted the Internet Archive Wayback Machine to find out what early versions of other websites looked like. Click through the gallery for a trip back in time.
A white background with bright, blue links helped yahoo.com users find what they were looking for in October 1996.
The altavista.com site is now an iconic darling of Internet history. The October 1996 version of the site boasted a search field, banner ad and some fun extras.
For those looking to find a sense of community online, the geocities.com of October 1996 presented a colorful option.
A commenter with the username Kandric suggested several memorable websites from the 1990s. Shown here are nhl.com and nfl.com as they appeared in December 1996, plus CNET.com as it was seen in October 1996.
The whitehouse.gov of December 1996 included a search feature and a text-only site.
The New York Times front page , as it appeared in December 1996, is compact by modern Web design standards.
Still getting CD-ROMs in the mail? Primary colors and an article on "marginal behavior" online were viewed by aol.com visitors in December 1996.
Ready to jet? Get flight information and more from the usairways.com website of October 1997.
Go ahead, ask the Internet a question. The askjeeves.com site, shown in October 1997, boasted an online butler of sorts.
This screenshot of news.bbc.co.uk in December 1998 exemplifies the narrow, vertical design of websites in the 1990s to accommodate lower-resolution monitors.
News, information and various web services could be found at the netscape.com homepage of May 1998.
Hampsterdance.com , shown here as it looked in April 1999, gained popularity for its catchy background tune and cute rodent graphics.
The Google.com landing page of October 1999 looks similar to its current version. But the site now offers many other services beyond search.
"The first website I ever went to was Cartoon Network's, circa 1998," said a commenter named maxemoose36. "I remember I was looking for something about Johnny Bravo." This screenshot of cartoonnetwork.com is from October 1999.
"Baaaah," said goat mascot Frank of livejournal.com . This screenshot shows the social blogging site as it appeared in November 1999.
You can make a weblog and communicate with people online. Just visit blogger.com in October 1999 to get started; it's like "magic," just like the site says.
Purple and lavender accents adorned the CNN.com homepage in August 2000. Election season was well under way.
"Your digital video repository" could have been at Youtube.com in July 2005.
Visitors to myspace.com , shown here as it looked in July 2006, connected with friends against the backdrop of a slightly different layout.
HIDE CAPTION
Digging back through website history
Digging back through website history
Digging back through website history
Digging back through website history
Digging back through website history
Digging back through website history
Digging back through website history
Digging back through website history
Digging back through website history
Digging back through website history
Digging back through website history
Digging back through website history
Digging back through website history
Digging back through website history
Digging back through website history
Digging back through website history
Digging back through website history
Digging back through website history
Digging back through website history
Digging back through website history
&lt;&lt;
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
