<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2014 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 08:57:44 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_sport" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_sport"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Baboon bamboozles golfer</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://edition.cnn.com/2014/12/06/sport/golf/golf-baboon-bamboozes-donald/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~3/h0d0A-9LZ6Q/index.html</link>
<description>Birdies are one thing but baboons on the golf course are not quite so welcome as Luke Donald finds out...&lt;img src="//feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~4/h0d0A-9LZ6Q" height="1" width="1" alt=""/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2014 16:04:36 EST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141206210025-baboon-golf-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141206210025-baboon-golf-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<feedburner:origLink>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/12/06/sport/golf/golf-baboon-bamboozes-donald/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Baboon bamboozles golfer Luke Donald in South Africa
December 6, 2014 -- Updated 2104 GMT (0504 HKT)
Luke Donald has had to cope with baboons on the course before at the Sun City event.
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
A baboon interrupts play at the Nedbank Golf Challenge in South Africa
Luke Donald leaps out of the way, but jokes his reaction was "pathetic"
Baboons have been seen before at the event in Sun City
Donald holds the lead going into the final round of the European Tour event
Follow us at @WorldSportCNN and like us on Facebook
(CNN) -- Birdies are one thing but baboons on the golf course are not quite so welcome.
Luke Donald had to dodge a baboon that cut across play at the Nedbank Golf Challenge in Sun City, South Africa.
The former world No. 1 jumped out of the way as the large primate bounded between the bunkers during the second round.
Donald tweeted afterwards: "Couple of things happened to me that haven't happened in a while....one I shot 63, and two I let a baboon play through on the course.
"The fact that my caddy Johnnie didn't even flinch makes my reaction look even more pathetic!!"
At least the Englishman can say he was not put off his stroke by the monkey business.
Donald holds a one-shot lead over countryman Danny Willett going into the final round.
Here's the vid incase you missed it! https://t.co/Be5ehlmbUH
— Luke Donald (@LukeDonald) December 5, 2014
It is not the first time that baboons have made an appearance at the Sun City event and animals on the golf course are nothing new in the global game.
A three-legged alligator at last year's Zurich Classic in New Orleans gave a new meaning to the golfing term water hazard.
A herd of hopping kangaroos at the 2013 Ladies' Australian Open in Canberra provided an interesting wildlife distraction for spectators.
Swiss golfers had to contend with a golf ball eating fox , whose antics made worldwide news.
Top tips to improve your slumber
November 12, 2014 -- Updated 1129 GMT (1929 HKT)
"Sleep, as far as mental and physical recovery goes, has never been more important ..." says sport sleep coach Nick Littlehales.
6,000 calories to go the distance
November 4, 2014 -- Updated 1024 GMT (1824 HKT)
Joe Miller is devouring his second steak of the day and the clock has barely nudged 2pm. You need lots of fuel to smash a drive 474 yards.
The feelgood sports story of 2014?
October 13, 2014 -- Updated 1449 GMT (2249 HKT)
There have been many dark days for Oliver Wilson, but golf's unluckiest loser is finally riding an upward swing of his career roller coaster.
Is this the ultimate hipster sport?
October 7, 2014 -- Updated 1648 GMT (0048 HKT)
They dress like it's the 1930s and they swing antique equipment that eschews cutting-edge technology -- this is hickory golf.
From Mary Queen of Scots to Rio 2016
September 15, 2014 -- Updated 1609 GMT (0009 HKT)
CNN's Living Golf focuses on women's golf, charting the growth of the sport from royal pastime to multi-million dollar machine.
The dark arts of golf's glamor girl
October 1, 2014 -- Updated 0846 GMT (1646 HKT)
"I don't know how to paint happy," says golf's poster girl Michelle Wie. "I think it releases a lot of the darker feelings in me."
September 29, 2014 -- Updated 1213 GMT (2013 HKT)
If you're a U.S. golf fan, or Tom Watson, look away now.
Selfies rule OK at Ryder Cup
September 25, 2014 -- Updated 2318 GMT (0718 HKT)
A ban on uploading social media pictures from the course at Gleneagles was dropped for the Ryder Cup.
Ryder wives treated 'like stars'
September 24, 2014 -- Updated 1052 GMT (1852 HKT)
A spot of shopping, the odd spa day and some serious flag waving. Welcome to the life of a Ryder Cup WAG.
Why golf legend battles with Twitter
September 23, 2014 -- Updated 1301 GMT (2101 HKT)
Tom Watson has learned plenty in the 21 years since he was last U.S. Ryder Cup captain, but social media is proving to be problematic.
Do you love the U.S. THIS much?
September 22, 2014 -- Updated 1243 GMT (2043 HKT)
Patriotism will reach fever pitch when the USA and Europe collide in golf's Ryder Cup ... and it looks like Rickie Fowler has let it go to his head.
September 22, 2014 -- Updated 1342 GMT (2142 HKT)
Pressure is inescapable in the cauldron of Ryder Cup competition -- pressure and ping pong.
Pressure putt that revived a career
September 23, 2014 -- Updated 1150 GMT (1950 HKT)
Millions of golf fans were watching on television with great anticipation. All Martin Kaymer could think about was getting his phone out.
Loading weather data ...
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
