<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2014 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 08:57:44 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_sport" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_sport"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Castan brain surgery success</title>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://edition.cnn.com/2014/12/03/sport/football/roma-leandro-castan-neurosurgery/index.html</guid>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~3/lSc_cWSqz7E/index.html</link>
<description>Roma defender Leandro Castan underwent successful neurosurgery Wednesday, having previously complained of acute dizziness during an Italian Serie A match in September.&lt;img src="//feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_sport/~4/lSc_cWSqz7E" height="1" width="1" alt=""/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2014 17:03:59 EST</pubDate>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141203174355-leandro-castan-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141203174355-leandro-castan-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<feedburner:origLink>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/12/03/sport/football/roma-leandro-castan-neurosurgery/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Roma defender undergoes successful brain surgery
By CNN Staff
December 3, 2014 -- Updated 1819 GMT (0219 HKT)
Leandro Castan was taken off against Empoli after complaining of dizziness.
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
Roma's Leandro Castan undergoes successful neurosurgery
The defender originally complained of acute dizziness in a match in September
The 28-year-old to remain in intensive care for the next 24 hours
Follow us at @WorldSportCNN and like us on Facebook
(CNN) -- Roma defender Leandro Castan underwent successful neurosurgery Wednesday, having previously complained of acute dizziness during an Italian Serie A match in September.
Castan reported the problem during halftime of his side's 1-0 victory against Empoli, and after facing tests earlier this month, he went under the knife to remove the cavernoma -- a cluster of abnormal blood vessels -- in his brain.
The three-and-a-half-hour procedure was "carried out using a surgical microscope and neuronavigator," according to an official Roma statement , while the player's "neurophysiological activity was constantly monitored."
The cavernoma, which measured three centimeters, was "completely removed."
Forza @l_castan , see you on the field soon! Tweet us a message for Leo using the hashtag #ForzaCastan pic.twitter.com/c96nFW39Vp
— AS Roma (@OfficialASRoma) December 3, 2014
The statement added: "Castan has now woken up and is breathing unaided, and has been informed of the operation's successful outcome.
"He will remain in intensive care for the next 24 hours, after which a prognosis will be formed."
While Wednesday's operation should ensure that Castan will be able to play football again, reports suggest that he will not be ready to return to action for up to eight months.
The 28-year-old, who arrived at Roma from Corinthians in 2012, has made just one appearance for the Italian Serie A club this season, having been sidelined since being substituted at halftime against Empoli.
Castan has become a key player for Roma since joining, making 36 appearances last term as the club booked their place in Europe's Champions League.
$500m stadium with a glowing 'skin'
October 28, 2014 -- Updated 1253 GMT (2053 HKT)
They splash the cash on the world's best players, now Real Madrid are giving the Bernabeu the same treatment with a bling makeover.
Loss of a South African 'icon'
October 27, 2014 -- Updated 1309 GMT (2109 HKT)
Football world mourns South African captain Senzo Meyiwa who was shot and killed during a botched robbery in a township near Johannesburg.
Pallotta: Rome's newest gladiator?
October 21, 2014 -- Updated 1348 GMT (2148 HKT)
From the ancient ruins of Rome, a new empire rises. But the eyes of the city's newest gladiator light up at thoughts of the Colosseum.
From Jewish football to ISIS suspect
October 21, 2014 -- Updated 1622 GMT (0022 HKT)
Once part of Germany's largest Jewish sports club, now he's the first ISIS suspect to stand trial in a country left shocked by his alleged radicalization.
Where has 'Super' Mario gone?
October 17, 2014 -- Updated 1411 GMT (2211 HKT)
One goal in eight matches for new club Liverpool, and dumped by the Italian national team -- Mario Balotelli has yet to shine on his English return.
Should rapist return to work?
October 18, 2014 -- Updated 1819 GMT (0219 HKT)
Should a convicted rapist, who has served their time in prison, be allowed to resume their old job? What if that job was as a high-profile football player?
Messi: A decade of goals
October 16, 2014 -- Updated 1247 GMT (2047 HKT)
After 10 years of golden glory, it's easy to see how Lionel Messi has taken his place among the football gods.
'Sleeping' Milan giant seeks makeover
October 16, 2014 -- Updated 1034 GMT (1834 HKT)
When will the tears stop? A leading Italian football club is pursuing a new direction -- under the guidance of its new Indonesian owner.
October 13, 2014 -- Updated 2241 GMT (0641 HKT)
Norwegian 15-year-old Martin Odegaard is the youngest player ever to feature in a European Championships qualifying match.
Will India's new pro league succeed?
October 10, 2014 -- Updated 1310 GMT (2110 HKT)
After revolutionizing cricket with its glitzy Twenty20 league, India has now thrown large sums of money at a new football venture.
Ferdinand: Get ruthless on racism
October 2, 2014 -- Updated 1453 GMT (2253 HKT)
Get ruthless. That is Rio Ferdinand's message to soccer's authorities in the fight to tackle the scourge of racism.
Football's most coveted teenager
September 10, 2014 -- Updated 1328 GMT (2128 HKT)
He's just 15 and the world is seemingly already at his feet. Norway's Martin Odegaard is being sought by Europe's top clubs.
Loading weather data ...
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
