<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2016 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 12:26:56 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 12:26:56 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<item>
<title>Horses on ice: White Turf racing</title>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676991/s/4dda08ca/sc/13/l/0Ledition0Bcnn0N0C20A160C0A20C250Csport0Cgallery0Cwhite0Eturf0Elake0Est0Emoritz0Cindex0Bhtml0Deref0Frss0Isport/story01.htm</link>
<description>The White Turf races take place on Lake St. Moritz each February, with 35,000 spectators flocking to the Engadine Valley to watch horse racing on ice.&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392807167/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dda08ca/sc/13/rc/1/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392807167/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dda08ca/sc/13/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392807167/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dda08ca/sc/13/rc/2/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392807167/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dda08ca/sc/13/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392807167/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dda08ca/sc/13/rc/3/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392807167/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dda08ca/sc/13/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392807167/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dda08ca/sc/13/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392807167/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dda08ca/sc/13/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392807167/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dda08ca/sc/13/ach.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392807167/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dda08ca/sc/13/ach.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/247392807167/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dda08ca/sc/13/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi2.feedsportal.com/r/247392807167/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dda08ca/sc/13/a2t2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676991/s/4dda08ca/sc/13/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2016 17:19:22 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://edition.cnn.com/2016/02/25/sport/gallery/white-turf-lake-st-moritz/index.html</guid>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160217125533-white-turf-13-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" lang="" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160217125533-white-turf-13-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>1 of 16
16 photos: Horse racing on Lake St. Moritz
Scenic route – Nestled in the Engadine Valley in the Swiss Alps, the lake of St. Moritz has been playing host to the White Turf races every year since 1907, with each meeting featuring flat racing, hurdling, skijoring and winter-style trotting.
Hide Caption
2 of 16
16 photos: Horse racing on Lake St. Moritz
Once in a lifetime – "What makes White Turf so special is the fact that it is unique, there is no such event anywhere else like it worldwide," White Turf vice-president Luigi Sala tells CNN. "It's an internationally known event that one has to see at least once in a lifetime."
Hide Caption
3 of 16
16 photos: Horse racing on Lake St. Moritz
Sunday times – Traditionally taking place across three Sundays every February, this year's edition of the White Turf races got off to a sticky start, with the opening meeting on February 7 canceled because of a lack of snow in January. It was business as usual on February 14, however, with the event ending on February 21.
Hide Caption
4 of 16
16 photos: Horse racing on Lake St. Moritz
Spectator sport – Some 35,000 spectators flock to White Turf each year, eager to take in the sight of the horses thundering across the frozen lake among the snow-capped mountains of St. Moritz.
Hide Caption
5 of 16
16 photos: Horse racing on Lake St. Moritz
Something magical – "There is something magical about the setting and racing on a frozen lake," Sala says. "The whole event area is built on 30 cm (12 inches) of snow, which lies on ice 50-60 cm thick, which in turn floats over 35-45 metres of water. So it has to be something special."
Hide Caption
6 of 16
16 photos: Horse racing on Lake St. Moritz
Champagne on ice – The champagne is always on ice for spectators, who are kept occupied by White Turf's gourmet catering, art exhibitions, funfair and live music -- when their attention is not turned to the race track.
Hide Caption
7 of 16
16 photos: Horse racing on Lake St. Moritz
Five-star service – "It's all made accessible for families, as well as for the high society who spend their winter holidays in our region -- a one-of-a-kind melting pot," Sala explains. "The VIP tent is able to satisfy even the most demanding of guests. A five-star hotel on a frozen lake."
Hide Caption
8 of 16
16 photos: Horse racing on Lake St. Moritz
Skijoring – St. Moritz remains the spiritual home of skijoring, which was dreamed up among its valleys in 1906. Thirteen men came up with the idea of racing their horses, not on horseback or seated in a sled, but by being pulled along on skis.
Hide Caption
9 of 16
16 photos: Horse racing on Lake St. Moritz
Exclusive – "Skijoring is a truly exciting race and exclusive to St. Moritz," Sala says. "Eight to 10 fearless drivers on skis pulled by their racehorses at 30-40 mph over a 1.67-mile track -- you can imagine how difficult it is to transmit orders to the horse through a five meter rope!"
Hide Caption
10 of 16
16 photos: Horse racing on Lake St. Moritz
King of the Engadine – The skijoring races at White Turf -- a clear crowd favorite -- are traditionally combined over the three Sundays, with participants competing for one prize at the end of it all. The skier with the highest number of points after the final event is crowned "King of the Engadine."
Hide Caption
11 of 16
16 photos: Horse racing on Lake St. Moritz
New shoes – Before setting hoof onto the snow, competing horses have to undergo a change of shoes, with regular horseshoes replaced by a pair containing winter grips and a unique layer of silicone to prevent snow sticking to hooves.
Hide Caption
12 of 16
16 photos: Horse racing on Lake St. Moritz
Start again – "Every year we build the whole infrastructure of White Turf anew," Sala adds. "This gives us the opportunity to implement new ideas and keep the interest of our many fans intact."
Hide Caption
13 of 16
16 photos: Horse racing on Lake St. Moritz
After dark – The action doesn't stop when the sun goes down, as White Turf spectators are treated to night-time racing under the lights.
Hide Caption
14 of 16
16 photos: Horse racing on Lake St. Moritz
Jackpot – With 500,000 Swiss francs ($501,000) on offer in total as prize money, White Turf surpasses all other jackpots when it comes to Swiss racing. The "Gubelin" event alone, taking place on the final Sunday, boasts a prize purse of 111,111 Swiss francs.
Hide Caption
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
