<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>World business news - CNNMoney.com</title>
<link>http://money.cnn.com/news/international/?section=money_news_international</link>
<description>CNNMoney.com, the business website of CNN, combines business news and in-depth market analysis with practical advice and answers to personal finance questions.</description>
<language>en-us</language>
<copyright>© 2014 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 11:00:49 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>World business news - CNNMoney.com</title>
<link>http://money.cnn.com/news/international/?section=money_news_international</link>
<url>http://i.cnn.net/money/images/cnnmoney_logo_144x30.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>30</height>
<description>CNNMoney.com, the business website of CNN, combines business news and in-depth market analysis with practical advice and answers to personal finance questions.</description>
</image>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/money_news_international"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_business" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_business"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Swedish police shut down Pirate Bay</title>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_business/~3/KIEZeX-guPU/index.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://money.cnn.com/2014/12/10/technology/pirate-bay-shut/index.html?section=money_news_international</guid>
<media:thumbnail height="90" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/money/dam/assets/141210140445-pirate-bay-founder-120x90.jpg" width="120"/>
<description>Swedish police have shut down The Pirate Bay just days after movies stolen from Sony appeared on the site.&lt;img src="//feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/money_news_international/~4/vDO6iix1gAU" height="1" width="1" alt=""/&gt;&lt;img src="//feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_business/~4/KIEZeX-guPU" height="1" width="1" alt=""/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 10:28:13 EST</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://money.cnn.com/2014/12/10/technology/pirate-bay-shut/index.html?section=money_news_international</feedburner:origLink>
<feedburner:origLink>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/money_news_international/~3/vDO6iix1gAU/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Swedish police shut down Pirate Bay
By Ivana Kottasova   @ivanakottasova December 10, 2014: 10:28 AM ET
Pirate Bay founder Peter Sunde was recently released from prison.
LONDON (CNNMoney)
Sweden has shut down The Pirate Bay just days after several movies stolen from Sony ( SNE ) appeared on the file-sharing site.
The website -- used by tens of millions to swap movies and music -- was taken offline after a police raid in Stockholm.
Paul Pinter, the Swedish police national coordinator for intellectual property enforcement, said "quite a few" servers and computers were confiscated because of suspected copyright infringement.
Films leaked from Sony during a recent hacking attack -- including "Fury" and "Annie," which is scheduled to premiere December 19 -- were among the Top 100 downloaded movies on Pirate Bay.
The raid was triggered by a complaint from the Rights Alliance, a Swedish group that fights cybercrime. The complaint -- one of several made against the site -- was based on the group's own independent investigation, said Sara Lindback, a lawyer for the alliance.
 
Sony hack could lead to censorship
The Pirate Bay is huge. It had 40 million active users at the time it was shut down this week.
"It was the 88th most popular site globally," Lindback said.
Related: Why the Sony hack is one of the worst hacks ever
Sweden's battle against The Pirate Bay has been going on for years. The site was taken down once before, in 2006, although the shutdown lasted only three days.
The website's founders have argued they are not breaching copyright law, because Pirate Bay users download files from each other via peer-to-peer links, rather than from the site itself.
But that argument was thrown out by Sweden's courts.
Four co-founders were convicted of collaborating to violate copyright law in 2009. They were sentenced to eight months in prison and ordered to pay fines of several million dollars.
The website continued to operate throughout their time in prison.
First Published: December 10, 2014: 9:46 AM ET
Most Popular
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
