<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>World business news - CNNMoney.com</title>
<link>http://money.cnn.com/news/international/?section=money_news_international</link>
<description>CNNMoney.com, the business website of CNN, combines business news and in-depth market analysis with practical advice and answers to personal finance questions.</description>
<language>en-us</language>
<copyright>© 2014 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 11:00:49 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>World business news - CNNMoney.com</title>
<link>http://money.cnn.com/news/international/?section=money_news_international</link>
<url>http://i.cnn.net/money/images/cnnmoney_logo_144x30.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>30</height>
<description>CNNMoney.com, the business website of CNN, combines business news and in-depth market analysis with practical advice and answers to personal finance questions.</description>
</image>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/money_news_international"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition_business" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info uri="rss/edition_business"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Toddlers stress test the iPad Air 2</title>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/edition_business/~3/YR8rDL6dHJE/index.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://money.cnn.com/2014/12/09/technology/toddler-ipad-air-2-stress-test/index.html?section=money_news_international</guid>
<description>Read full story for latest details.&lt;img src="//feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/money_news_international/~4/XUJ2HHoEUXs" height="1" width="1" alt=""/&gt;&lt;img src="//feeds.feedburner.com/~r/rss/edition_business/~4/YR8rDL6dHJE" height="1" width="1" alt=""/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 09:23:41 EST</pubDate>
<feedburner:origLink>http://money.cnn.com/2014/12/09/technology/toddler-ipad-air-2-stress-test/index.html?section=money_news_international</feedburner:origLink>
<feedburner:origLink>http://rss.cnn.com/~r/rss/money_news_international/~3/XUJ2HHoEUXs/index.html</feedburner:origLink>
<ExtractedText>Toddler vs. Apple iPad Air 2: Stress Test
By Erica Fink   @EricaFink December 10, 2014: 9:23 AM ET
 
Toddler vs. iPad: Real life stress test
NEW YORK (CNNMoney)
Classic battles: Ali vs. Frazier. Yankees vs. Red Sox. Toddler vs. iPad?
Well, not exactly.
CNNMoney gave two nursery school classmates a brand new iPad Air 2 and let them loose in our studios for a (very) non-scientific stress test.
Good news for iPad owners: You can literally throw the device from the top of a 12-foot staircase and see it survive. (A note: CNN's newsrooms have a thin layer of carpeting, but the iPad endured nearly a dozen such plunges.)
We mistakenly thought that when the toddlers grew tired, we'd see how well the tablet withstood a full-blown tantrum. Many parents use Apple ( AAPL , Tech30 ) iPads for educational games and general preschooler entertainment, so this seemed like a potential real-world scenario.
Related: Samsung's Galaxy Note Edge is the latest WTF phone
Turns out, getting them to drop the tablet a mere two or three feet required undoing years of parenting: They knew it was wrong.
Even when being encouraged to mimic the actions of elders dropping the iPad, they stopped short of actually letting it fall.
Eventually, after a fair bit of encouragement from our production crew, they started to explore the limits of the device. How might Siri react if held down for minutes at a time? How does the LCD display do under the sole of a Spiderman Stride Rite? And most perilously, how does the anodized aluminum case do when dropped many, many times?
The answer: very well.
Related: The best gifts to get for the holidays
Standing on the anchor desk on CNN's newsroom set, testers Sofia and Tzuri tossed the iPad roughly six feet on to a wood floor. They repeated this exercise fourteen times, at least six of them resulting in a glass-first fall. The screen remained pristine -- not even a scratch.
Upping the ante, we brought them on the staircase in our main newsroom.
They nudged the iPad Air over the railing or threw it off the edge nine different times.
Apart from a small dent on one its beveled edges, the device remained unscathed.
First Published: December 9, 2014: 10:54 PM ET
Most Popular
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
