<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2016 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 12:26:56 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 12:26:56 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<item>
<title>Champions League: Man City cruises past Kiev</title>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676991/s/4dd41a65/sc/13/l/0Ledition0Bcnn0N0C20A160C0A20C240Csport0Cchampions0Eleague0Edynamo0Ekiev0Emanchester0Ecity0Cindex0Bhtml0Deref0Frss0Isport/story01.htm</link>
<description>Manchester City took a giant stride towards the quarterfinals of the Champions League after an emphatic 3-1 win at Dynamo Kiev.&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392696039/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dd41a65/sc/13/rc/1/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392696039/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dd41a65/sc/13/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392696039/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dd41a65/sc/13/rc/2/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392696039/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dd41a65/sc/13/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392696039/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dd41a65/sc/13/rc/3/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392696039/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dd41a65/sc/13/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392696039/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dd41a65/sc/13/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392696039/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dd41a65/sc/13/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392696039/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dd41a65/sc/13/ach.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392696039/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dd41a65/sc/13/ach.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/247392696039/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dd41a65/sc/13/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi2.feedsportal.com/r/247392696039/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4dd41a65/sc/13/a2t2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676991/s/4dd41a65/sc/13/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 12:25:15 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://edition.cnn.com/2016/02/24/sport/champions-league-dynamo-kiev-manchester-city/index.html</guid>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160224204309-aguero-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" lang="" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160224204309-aguero-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>Facebook Twitter Instagram
&lt;div class="banner" id="cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0_banner"&gt;&lt;span id="cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" class="_fwph"&gt;&lt;form id="_fw_form_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" style="display:none"&gt;&lt;input type="hidden" name="_fw_input_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" id="_fw_input_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" value="ptgt=s&amp;envp=g_js&amp;w=300&amp;h=250&amp;slau=300x250_sync&amp;adUnit=300x250_sync"&gt;&lt;/form&gt;&lt;span id="_fw_container_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" class="cn-shingle__ad"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Champions League: Manchester City cruises past Dynamo Kiev
James Masters, CNN
Updated 2213 GMT (0613 HKT) February 24, 2016
6 photos: Champions League: City slickers ease to victory
Manchester City traveled to Dynamo Kiev for its last 16 Champions League tie. The English club, which has never reached the quarter final stage, threatened early on through Sergio Aguero.
Hide Caption
1 of 6
6 photos: Champions League: City slickers ease to victory
It was Aguero who gave City a 15th minute lead with a fine finish after good work by Yaya Toure.
Hide Caption
2 of 6
6 photos: Champions League: City slickers ease to victory
Kiev was chasing shadows as City dominated the first half. The visitors dominated possession and looked a threat each time it moved forward.
Hide Caption
3 of 6
6 photos: Champions League: City slickers ease to victory
City had already created a number of chances to extend its lead so it was little surprise when David Silva popped up at the far post to roll home his side's second.
Hide Caption
4 of 6
6 photos: Champions League: City slickers ease to victory
City looked home and dry at the interval with Kiev having failed to test the visiting defense. Silva, Aguero and Raheem Sterling were all enjoying themselves.
Hide Caption
5 of 6
6 photos: Champions League: City slickers ease to victory
Dynamo found a way back into the game when Vitaliy Buyalskiy's effort deflected off Nicolas Otamendi and flew into the corner. But any hopes the home side had of a comeback were killed off when Toure netted City's third late on.
Hide Caption
Manchester City defeats Dynamo Kiev in Champions League
Sergio Aguero and David Silva on target in first half
Yaya Toure added a third late on
Atletico Madrid held to goalless draw at PSV Eindhoven
(CNN)
Manchester City took a giant stride towards the quarterfinals of the Champions League after an emphatic 3-1 win at Dynamo Kiev.
City, aiming to qualify for the last eight for the first time in its history, made light work of the Ukrainian side with a stylish performance.
Sergio Aguero, David Silva and Yaya Toure were all on target as City made light of its recent poor form.
City had led 2-0 at the interval before Vitaliy Buyalskiy gave Dynamo hope with a deflected effort.
But Toure's wonderful curling effort settled the contest and leaves City very much in control going into the second leg.
Proper poacher's pounce from Aguero. https://t.co/pZpEfPVYJo
— Gary Lineker (@GaryLineker) February 24, 2016
Read More
Troubling times
Manchester City has struggled in recent weeks despite having one of the most expensive squads in the world game.
City, fourth in the Premier League, is six points adrift of surprise leader Leicester City while it also crashed out of the FA Cup with a 5-1 defeat by Chelsea last weekend.
Manuel Pellegrini's side, which had lost its two previous league games against Leicester and Tottenham, came under fire for resting a number of key players for the game at Stamford Bridge.
It was back to full strength for this clash in Kiev with Aguero restored to the attack and Vincent Kompany, the captain, starting in defense.
And it was Aguero who made the difference for City as it roared into a two-goal lead before the interval.
The Argentine forward showed his predatory instincts to fire City ahead on 15 minutes after meeting Toure's knock down.
He could have had another couple by the time City moved further ahead courtesy of Silva.
Aguero's backheel released Raheem Sterling and his cross was converted at the far post by the Spanish playmaker.
Dynamo done?
Not since 1999 has Dynamo Kiev reached the last four of the competition -- in fact, it has not played a knockout tie in the competition since then.
On that occasion it boasted the supreme strike force of Andriy Shevchenko and its now manager, Sergiy Rebrov.
Kiev, which defeated the likes of Arsenal and Real Madrid on its way to the semifinals 17 years ago, was eventually beaten by Bayern Munich.
This current generation does not have the star quality which Shevchenko and Rebrov enjoyed but it has talent of its own.
Andriy Yarmolenko, the Ukrainian international, is just one player who has caught the eye in recent years.
Last season he helped Dynamo reach the quarterfinals of the Europa League by starring in his side's victory over Everton.
He scored 18 goals last season and had 13 in 23 appearances this year going into this tie.
But it was his teammate Buyalskiy who got Dynamo back in this game just before the hour mark.
City, which had looked comfortable for much of the contest, failed to clear its lines and Buyalskiy unleashed a fierce effort which flew into the net with the aid of a deflection.
Tense finale
Dynamo, which hadn't played a competitive fixture since December with the Ukrainian season still on its winter break, continued to push forward.
Joe Hart, the City goalkeeper, produced a fine save to deny Buyalskiy an equalizer while Toure missed a wonderful chance at the other end when he headed wide from close range.
But the Ivorian soon atoned for his miss by curling home a sumptuous effort with a minute of the contest remaining.
"I'm very happy because it is a very good result," Pellegrini told BT Sport.
"It is not finished but playing away and having a two-goal lead is very good. The team played well and had lots of chances.
"Maybe when it was 2-1 we had moments of doubt, but then we got the third goal.
"Is the tie settled? No. It is important in football to never think it is finished. But to have that third goal gives us more confidence for the second leg."
Atletico held
In the night's other tie, Atletico Madrid could only manage a goalless draw at  10-man PSV Eindhoven.
Gaston Pereiro's red card left the home side facing an uphill struggle to take something from the contest.
But the Dutch side battled hard and will hope to pull off a surprise result when the two teams meet again on March 15.
Build your dream Champions League team and share it, challenging your friends to beat your Ultimate XI
Choose your team
Tap team shirts left or right
Tap a player to add them to your team
Tap to view player stats
Your formation will update as you add players
Tap on the trash can to clear your selections
Tap done to show and share your team results
Got it
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
