<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2016 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 18:09:16 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 18:09:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<item>
<title>Chinese president's $300m 'happiness plan'</title>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676991/s/4de14513/sc/13/l/0Ledition0Bcnn0N0C20A160C0A20C260Cfootball0Cchina0Efootball0Eambition0Etransfer0Ewindow0Cindex0Bhtml0Deref0Frss0Isport/story01.htm</link>
<description>With the world's football authorities occupied with electing the next FIFA president, China's billionaire club owners have been busy putting the European soccer establishment on notice with over $300 million spent on foreign players.&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392856810/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4de14513/sc/13/rc/1/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392856810/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4de14513/sc/13/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392856810/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4de14513/sc/13/rc/2/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392856810/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4de14513/sc/13/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392856810/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4de14513/sc/13/rc/3/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392856810/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4de14513/sc/13/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392856810/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4de14513/sc/13/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392856810/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4de14513/sc/13/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392856810/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4de14513/sc/13/ach.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392856810/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4de14513/sc/13/ach.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/247392856810/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4de14513/sc/13/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi2.feedsportal.com/r/247392856810/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4de14513/sc/13/a2t2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676991/s/4de14513/sc/13/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 18:08:52 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://edition.cnn.com/2016/02/26/football/china-football-ambition-transfer-window/index.html</guid>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160226171507-china-football-tease-2-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" lang="" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160226171507-china-football-tease-2-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>1 of 18
18 photos:
On Wednesday, the premiere Chinese football club Guangzhou Evergrande paid $45.8 million to sign Atletico Madrid striker Jackson Martinez -- a record transfer price for the burgeoning Chinese Super League.
Hide Caption
2 of 18
18 photos:
Brazilian Ramires of Chelsea was signed by Jiangsu Suning of the China Super League on January 27, 2016 for a reported initial fee of nearly $28 million -- shattering the transfer record for China.
Hide Caption
3 of 18
18 photos:
Corinthians playmaker Renato reportedly turned down a lucrative offer from a German club to join Beijing Guoan. "There was a very good offer from Germany, three times more than I make here at Corinthians," Renato was quoted as saying by the South China Morning Post. "But then came an offer I couldn't refuse."
Hide Caption
4 of 18
18 photos:
Darko Matic (right) with Beijing Guoan teammate Lang Zheng has had a lot to celebrate since moving to China nearly 10 years ago. Matic has learned Mandarin and is considering remaining in the country after his career ends.
Hide Caption
5 of 18
18 photos:
Former Arsenal and Roma winger Gervinho (seen playing for Ivory Coast) recently completed a nearly $20 million transfer to Hebei China Fortune in the China Super League.
Hide Caption
6 of 18
18 photos:
Colombian Fredy Guarin (right) was moved by Inter Milan to Shanghai Greenland Shenhua for a reported fee of $14 million in January.
Hide Caption
7 of 18
18 photos:
Former England manager Sven-Goran Eriksson (R) attending a training session of his team Shanghai SIPG of the Chinese Super League on April 18, 2015. Eriksson signed former Sunderland and Al-Ain striker Asamoah Gyan last year.
Hide Caption
8 of 18
18 photos:
Former Brazil and Chelsea manager Luiz Felipe Scolari -- now head coach of Asian Champions League winners FC Guangzhou Evergrande -- reacts during the international friendly match against Bayern Munich on July 23, 2015.
Hide Caption
9 of 18
18 photos:
Erik Paartalu (#6 with former team Brisbane Roar) lasted one year in the Chinese Super League with Tianjin Teda F.C. -- an experience he called "one of the most challenging times in my life, but also one of the most rewarding."
Hide Caption
10 of 18
18 photos:
Former NBA All-Star Stephon Marbury has found a welcoming home in China, where he has remained since 2010. He is pictured celebrating after his team, the Beijing Ducks, won their first-ever Chinese championship behind his 41 points in March, 2012.
Hide Caption
11 of 18
18 photos:
Alibaba founder Jack Ma recently purchased a 50% stake in FC Guangzhou Evergrande, representing a new wave of businessman investors in Chinese soccer.
Hide Caption
12 of 18
18 photos:
Didier Drogba (far left) and Nicolas Anelka (second from right) attending a training session in Shanghai. Their spells in China didn't last long though and the pair exited in 2013.
Hide Caption
13 of 18
18 photos:
Shanghai Shenhua fans reacted with fervor after Drogba arrived at Pudong international airport in Shanghai on July 14, 2012. Though Drogba was reportedly signed on a £200,000 per week salary, he left China only six months later.
Hide Caption
14 of 18
18 photos:
An Ultra supporter of Beijing Guoan shows a tattoo of the team's badge during a match against Chongcing Lifan  on June 28, 2015 in Beijing, China.
Hide Caption
15 of 18
18 photos:
There are growing legions of ardent supporters and fans of Chinese football clubs. The government is also trying to foster a football culture in the country by mandating football programs in 20,000 Chinese schools in a recent plan devised by President Xi Jinping to make China a football power.
Hide Caption
16 of 18
18 photos:
This photo taken on June 20, 2015 shows fans (foreground) wearing the colors of the Beijing Guoan team as they watch the team's Chinese Super League  match against Tianjin Teda in Beijing.
Hide Caption
17 of 18
18 photos:
Chinese football's top tier is now the most watched league in Asia, and in a strictly controlled society matches offer the rare sight of tens of thousands of people in spontaneous displays of emotion, joy and anger.
Hide Caption
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
