<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Sports: Sports News, Scores, Analysis, Schedules &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/2010/07/08/AB582vC_page.html?wprss=rss_sports</link>
<description>The Washington Post Sports section provides sports news, video, scores, analysis and updates about high school, college, and pro sports teams, including the Capitals, Nationals, Redskins, United and Wizards. Post Sports also offers blogs and discussions about the latest sports news.</description>
<language>en</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2012 Washington Post Company</copyright>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 15:57:11 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 15:57:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>Sports: Sports News, Scores, Analysis, Schedules &amp; More - The Washington Post</title>
<url>http://media3.washingtonpost.com/wp-srv/hp/image/wp_web.gif</url>
<link>http://www.washingtonpost.com/2010/07/08/AB582vC_page.html?wprss=rss_sports</link>
</image>
<item>
<title>Caps Insider: Postgame: In ‘benchmark’ game vs. Tampa Bay, Capitals extend winning streak</title>
<link>http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636679/s/414858bd/sc/13/l/0L0Swashingtonpost0N0Csports0Cpostgame0Ein0Ebenchmark0Egame0Evs0Etampa0Ebay0Ecapitals0Eextend0Ewinning0Estreak0C20A140C120C10A0C3ba16cd10E0A69f0E45df0Eb1560E3da0A9d63bb3a0Istory0Bhtml0Dwprss0Frss0Isports/story01.htm</link>
<description>&lt;p/&gt; &lt;p&gt;TAMPA — Here was the test the &lt;a data-xslt="_http" href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/capitals/"&gt;Washington Capitals&lt;/a&gt; wanted, at the barn from which few visitors emerge content, against an ornery &lt;a data-xslt="_http" href="http://stats.washingtonpost.com/nhl/teamstats.asp?teamno=20&amp;#38;type=schedule"&gt;Tampa Bay Lightning&lt;/a&gt; team that had not lost as Amalie Arena since mid-November. Sure, the Capitals had won two straight at Metropolitan Division opponents, but once the regular season ended, positively or not, who would remember beating Carolina and New Jersey? &lt;a data-xslt="_http" href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/capitals-insider/wp/2014/12/09/after-two-wins-over-losing-teams-capitals-face-big-test-in-tampa/"&gt;They understood the added meaning this trip could provide.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/postgame-in-benchmark-game-vs-tampa-bay-capitals-extend-winning-streak/2014/12/10/3ba16cd1-069f-45df-b156-3da09d63bb3a_story.html?wprss=rss_sports"&gt;Read full article &amp;#62;&amp;#62;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://feeds.washingtonpost.com/c/34656/f/636679/s/414858bd/sc/13/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612629257/u/89/f/636679/c/34656/s/414858bd/sc/13/rc/1/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612629257/u/89/f/636679/c/34656/s/414858bd/sc/13/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612629257/u/89/f/636679/c/34656/s/414858bd/sc/13/rc/2/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612629257/u/89/f/636679/c/34656/s/414858bd/sc/13/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612629257/u/89/f/636679/c/34656/s/414858bd/sc/13/rc/3/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612629257/u/89/f/636679/c/34656/s/414858bd/sc/13/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612629257/u/89/f/636679/c/34656/s/414858bd/sc/13/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/214612629257/u/89/f/636679/c/34656/s/414858bd/sc/13/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/214612629257/u/89/f/636679/c/34656/s/414858bd/sc/13/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 05:57:47 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.washingtonpost.com/sports/postgame-in-benchmark-game-vs-tampa-bay-capitals-extend-winning-streak/2014/12/10/3ba16cd1-069f-45df-b156-3da09d63bb3a_story.html?wprss=rss_sports</guid>
<dc:creator>Alex Prewitt</dc:creator>
<ExtractedText>By Alex Prewitt December 10 at 12:57 AM Follow @alex_prewitt
Braden Holtby finished with 33 saves against the Lightning, out-dueling the Eastern Conference’s wins leader, goaltender Ben Bishop of the LIghtning. (AP Photo/Chris O’Meara).
TAMPA – Here was the test the Washington Capitals wanted, at the barn from which few visitors emerge content, against an ornery Tampa Bay Lightning team that had not lost as Amalie Arena since mid-November. Sure, the Capitals had won two straight at Metropolitan Division opponents, but once the regular season ended, positively or not, who would remember beating Carolina and New Jersey? They understood the added meaning this trip could provide.
“You always want to try to put separation between teams lower in the standings, but you have to catch teams ahead of you in the standings,” forward Troy Brouwer said. “With how many divisional games there are now and how many ties there are as well, you have to be able to get points against teams above you in the standings and gain ground whenever you can.”
After a 5-3 victory Tuesday, the Capitals returned to D.C. for a brief home respite powered by momentum from their most complete effort of the season , against a team that had previously lost just four times at Amalie Arena this season.
Forward Alex Ovechkin ended a four-game scoring drought with a goal before half the building had sat down, then added an empty-netter once most everyone had left. Forward Troy Brouwer found his first five-on-five goal since late October and led a rejuvenated effort by his line. Defenseman Matt Niskanen scored on the power play, Washington killed three penalties and goaltender Braden Holtby outdueled the Eastern Conference’s wins leader, Ben Bishop.
Sure, there were sequences the Capitals wished they could have avoided, but inside the visiting locker room, nothing but feel-goods emerged. Forward Andre Burakovsky, scratched for the second straight game, photo-bombed Niskanen’s interview . Coach Barry Trotz joked about a recent family trip to the zoo, which the Epix cameras captured, and saw one of their crew members frightened by the lions. They have won three straight in regulation, their longest since April 2013.
“I think we see that when we play the way we need to play, we can play with the top teams,” Trotz said. “They’re good benchmarks for us. They’ve got a deep team, they’ve got an outstanding record. We don’t right now. We’re trying to improve that. Staying on the one-game focus right now, there’s so many good teams in this league, it’s hard to gain ground. We’ve just got to focus on the next game now.”
The Capitals would be wise to not overlook Columbus before a rematch with the Lightning on Saturday at Verizon Center, but with a three-game trip to the Panthers (11-8-7), Blue Jackets (10-15-2) and Devils (11-13-5) looming next week, they also have a decent opportunity to expand the streak and keep climbing the standings.
“It’s just more important to worry about our own game as opposed to who we’re playing,” defenseman Brooks Orpik said. “Any team can beat any team in this league. We’ve seen that over the last couple years. I think every year the parity increases throughout the year. We’ve been pretty good on the road here throughout the season. We have to start getting better at home.”
A decent springboard would be mimicking their start against the Lightning, with Ovechkin bulldozing opponents and a quick goal gifting them early momentum. Another stalwart effort from Holtby, who made 33 saves, would help too. So would snuffing three penalties, all within the second period, getting goals from every line except the fourth, forcing 10 giveaways and winning 55 percent of faceoffs.
“We’re adding things to our game,” Trotz said. “The five-on-five, we talked about all the stats that we’ve had when we don’t score five on five or if [Nicklas Backstrom] and Ovie don’t score, we haven’t been able to win games in the past. And we’re trying to change that. We feel we can play with four lines, we can play with a little bit of relentless attitude and the pack mentality and be firm on people and make them pay a price to get out of their zone, make them pay a price to score a goal. There’s a good commitment right now.”
Said Brouwer: “It’s a big week. We’ve got a big win tonight, but we play them in a few days as well. We can’t just give them that game back later on. We have a game in between, but we’re excited at the challenge to play them again in a few days here.”
Alex Prewitt covers the Washington Capitals. Follow him on Twitter @alex_prewitt or email him at alex.prewitt@washpost.com .
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
