<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2013 08:41:49 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Vehicle explodes in heart of Kabul</title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/11/16/world/asia/afghanistan-violence/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/11/16/world/asia/afghanistan-violence/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>An explosive-laden vehicle detonated in the heart of Kabul Saturday, a spokesman for the Afghan interior ministry told CNN. </description>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2013 07:40:36 EST</pubDate>
<ExtractedText>Vehicle explodes in heart of Kabul, 6 dead
From Masoud Popalzai, CNN
November 16, 2013 -- Updated 1428 GMT (2228 HKT)
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
A vehicle exploded in the heart of Kabul
At least 6 people are dead, police say
No one has claimed responsibility for the attack
(CNN) -- An explosive-laden vehicle detonated in the heart of Kabul on Saturday, killing at least six people, an Afghan interior ministry spokesman told CNN.
Both civilians and military personnel were among the victims, spokesman Sediq Sediqqi said.
The government gave a lower death toll than what local police reported earlier.
Sediqqi said that 22 others were injured and 17 vehicles were damaged.
The explosion happened close to the venue where a large meeting of Afghan elders is scheduled to take place at the end of the week.
The meeting, or Loya Jirga, is to discuss the signing of a bilateral security agreement between Afghanistan and the United States.
No one has claimed responsibility for Saturday's attack, but the Taliban has said that it condemned the meeting and would attack anyone participating in it.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
