<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2013 08:41:49 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>Take Viagra to cure ... jetlag? </title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/11/12/travel/jetlag-cures/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/11/12/travel/jetlag-cures/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>The curious ways some passengers adapt their body clocks.</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2013 20:51:33 EST</pubDate>
<ExtractedText>Exercise, alcohol and Viagra -- best cures for jet lag?
By CNN Staff
November 13, 2013 -- Updated 0048 GMT (0848 HKT)
Stretching and doing some light exercise in flight is recommended for avoiding muscle cramps and deep-vein thrombosis, but 61% of the Singaporean fliers polled by Skyscanner also claimed to do it to avoid jetlag. Some 51% of people who tried this cure said it worked, making it the most successful jetlag cure on the list.
In 48% of cases popping a sleeping pill is a quick and easy way to ensure you don't fall asleep in that 4 p.m. meeting once at your destination. Sleeping pills were the second most successful remedy on the list.
Eating well and not too much is good advice whether you're flying long distance or not, and in 46% of cases it also helps jetlag, according to those surveyed.
46% also said setting your watch to the new time zone before you got there helped you get over jetlag quicker.
"No no sweetheart, it's for the jetlag, honest." Viagra started as a treatment for high blood pressure and angina, became popular as a cure for erectile dysfunction and now, it seems, is good for jetlag, at least in 45% of cases, making it the fifth-equal most successful cure mentioned.
Getting some exercise and fresh air pre-flight was tied with Viagra as a jetlag cure in fifth place. Incheon Airport's spacious golf driving range could help there.
In 42% of reported cases, avoiding alcohol completely was the key to adapting to a new destination's hours quickly.
With a 42% success rate for jetlag, herbal cures were surprisingly successful. The survey unfortunately didn't detail which remedies were chosen.
We don't think you need this much booze to keep the jetlag devil at bay, but several people -- 41% -- said it helped them get over their travel fatigue quicker.
Staying awake in flight isn't a choice for the light sleepers among us, even with a sumptuous cabin like this. Some 40% said it helped cure their jetlag.
HIDE CAPTION
1. Stretch/light exercise on flight
2. Sleeping tablets
3.= Light and healthy diet
3.= Set watch to new time zone
5.= Viagra
5.= Exercise/fresh air before flight
7.= Avoid alcohol completely
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
