<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2013 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2013 08:41:49 EST</pubDate>
<ttl>10</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Top Stories</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<width>144</width>
<height>33</height>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://rss.cnn.com/rss/edition" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="rss/edition"/>
<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" rel="hub"/>
<item>
<title>'Typhoon babies' cling to life </title>
<guid>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/11/16/world/asia/phillippines-baby-clinic/index.html</guid>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/2013/11/16/world/asia/phillippines-baby-clinic/index.html?eref=edition</link>
<description>In a makeshift neonatal clinic for premature babies in the Philippines, parents are forced to hand-pump air to keep their children alive. They don't always succeed. </description>
<pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2013 09:11:43 EST</pubDate>
<ExtractedText>A baby born in wreckage clings to life
By Jethro Mullen and Ivan Watson, CNN
November 16, 2013 -- Updated 1326 GMT (2126 HKT)
STORY HIGHLIGHTS
This baby was born premature after the storm
The baby's mother rush to a clinic that does not have electricity
"We're improvising," doctor says
Tacloban, Philippines (CNN) -- The tiny, baby girl barely moves as she lies wrapped in a bundle of yellow plastic and green cloth on a peeling brown mattress made for a child far larger than she.
Her eyes are closed, her black hair slicked to her scalp. An intravenous drip runs into her covers, the only clear sign of medical treatment -- and far less than she needs in her fight to survive the coming days.
She was born prematurely Saturday morning, weighing 1.3 kilograms in a ramshackle hospital in Tacloban, the Philippine city that has suffered an enormous human toll from Super Typhoon Haiyan.
Outside the half-opened window by her bed lies debris from the storm. Doctors in the gloomy, humid pediatric ward say her prognosis is "unstable." The next 24 hours will be critical.
The hospital, the Eastern Visayas Regional Medical Center, has no incubator to offer her to help her breathe, they say. And even if it did, there is no electricity to power it.
Typhoon Haiyan: Eight days later
Finding strength after the storm
Trapped residents protect themselves from the dust as a U.S. Navy helicopter leaves on Saturday, November 16, on Manicani Island, in central Philippines. Troops and aid organizations have encountered blocked roads and devastating damage in the aftermath of Super Typhoon Haiyan, one of the strongest storms in history. See how you can help.
Trapped residents prepare to unload relief supplies November 16 from a U.S. Navy helicopter.
A U.S. Army Ranger unloads aid from a U.S. Marines Osprey aircraft at Balangiga City, Samar Province, on November 16.
U.S. service men load emergency supplies onto a helicopter at the airport in Tacloban on November 16.
Victims hold tight onto a box of relief goods from a U.S. Navy Sea Hawk helicopter in the town of Salcedo, Samar Island province, Philippines, on November 16.
A U.S. helicopter flies above as a U.S. Marine watches on at the airport in Tacloban on November 16.
A Philippine soldier guards U.S. aid in the aftermath of the typhoon at Tacloban airport on November 15.
Volunteers prepare relief goods for victims of Super Typhoon Haiyan in Manila on Thursday, November 14.
Stranded passengers board a plane at a damaged airport in Tacloban, Philippines, on Wednesday, November 13.
Soldiers evacuate a sick survivor at an airport in Tacloban on November 13.
Relief supplies for the victims in the Philippines are loaded into an aircraft in Germany on November 13.
Soldiers load relief goods onto a truck in Tacloban on November 13.
People wait in line to receive relief goods in Leyte on Tuesday, November 12.
Evacuees send e-mails to their family members and relatives at a free Internet cafe set up by the Philippines government on November 12 in Tacloban.
Aid workers arrive in Leyte to assist survivors on November 12.
People wait at a bus stop November 12 in Tacloban, Philippines.
People board a U.S. military plane to evacuate Tacloban on November 12.
People carry sacks of goods November 12 in Tacloban.
A member of the Japanese Disaster Relief Team carries goods in Tacloban on November 12.
Rescuers in Guigang City, China, search a flooded road by boat on November 12. China and Vietnam were also hit hard by the typhoon.
Residents line up to receive treatment and supplies at the Tacloban airport on Monday, November 11.
Staff load a Hercules airplane with equipment November 11 at the Orebro airport in central Sweden. The Swedish Civil Contingencies Agency, together with its humanitarian partners, sent equipment to support the United Nations' relief work in the Philippines.
Philippine troops load boxes of water at Villamor Air Force Base in Manila, Philippines, on November 11.
A man seeking aid paints a message on a basketball court November 11 in Anibong, Philippines.
Villagers in Hernani, Philippines, run toward government officials hoping for food November 11.
A military helicopter delivering food prepares to land at the airport in Guiuan, Philippines, on November 11.
Emily Ortega rests on November 11 after giving birth to Bea Joy at an improvised clinic at the Tacloban airport.
Typhoon survivors line up at the Tacloban airport on November 11 to board a U.S. military plane bound for Manila.
Philippine Air Force personnel prepare to load relief supplies at the Tacloban airport on November 11.
Philippine police commandos prepare to board a military plane in Manila on Sunday, November 10.
A Tacloban resident carries boxes of milk November 10 as he passes by ships washed ashore by the powerful storm.
Residents carry relief goods along the bay in Tacloban on November 10.
Typhoon Haiyan relief efforts
Photos: Typhoon Haiyan relief efforts
Family separated by storm finally reunites
Instead, she will have to try her luck in the intensive care unit, which in reality is the hospital's chapel, situated on the second floor of the building next to a large pool of dirty black water.
In the repurposed chapel, newborn babies -- both healthy and sick -- live out their first few days with their mothers on and among the wooden pews.
Baby born from stress
The tiny girl's 16-year-old mother, Elivie Udtohan, went into labor after 32 weeks of pregnancy. The early birth was the result of the stress and strain of a grueling and unsuccessful attempt to escape this devastated, nonfunctional city, her family says.
How to help Typhoon Haiyan survivors
The family walked two hours from their storm-wrecked home to Tacloban airport, joining hundreds of others who are waiting desperately there for a place on a flight out of the chaos and decay.
Not wanting Elvie to give birth in such an unsafe and unsanitary setting, the family planned to go and stay with relatives in Manila. But after spending a night at the airport, they were refused spaces aboard a military cargo plane that they thought they had been promised.
Angry, disheartened and worried, they retraced their steps back into the city, past the stinking wreckage of countless houses that had been devoured by Haiyan's deadly storm surge.
When they arrived home, the scenario they so badly hoped to avoid began to unfold when Elvie went into labor.
After the birth Saturday morning, several of Elvie's family members sat keeping watch over the yet-to-be-named baby girl. Elvie rested up in the chapel, lying on a bare wooden pew in a black and red floral dress. Like her daughter, she was hooked up to a drip.
By the baby's bedside, Elvie's own mother, Elizada Udtohan, 41, listed her worries.
The family is concerned about the baby's ability to survive in this dirty, damaged hospital, she said. They are also fearful that the hospital authorities will ask for payment, a demand the family is too poor to meet.
Doctors Without Borders help survivors
Journey lead singer helps typhoon survivors
Typhoon victim dies from broken leg
Burying the dead in the Philippines
Beyond that, they don't know where they will go or what they will do next, with a frighteningly fragile life to consider. The baby's father is separated from Elvie and no longer involved in her life, her mother said.
Others share the same plight
The Udtohans' plight is similar to that faced by many others in and around Tacloban at the moment. Impoverished people who lost what little they had in the storm are left at the mercy of a crippled medical system that lacks basic elements needed to care for patients.
More than a week after the typhoon struck, authorities are making progress clearing mounds of debris from the streets. But in the hospitals, they are still struggling to fix problems that are proving deadly for some.
Six babies have died at the regional medical center during the typhoon's aftermath, doctors at the pediatric ward said. The doctors say they have been told that a big generator may be brought in to provide power for some vital services, but they have no idea when.
Two of the doctors working in the ward are volunteers from medical facilities in Manila. They came into Tacloban earlier this week to relieve the exhausted local staff, many of whom were also victims of the typhoon.
The Manila doctors were shocked by the conditions they found at the storm-ravaged, unsterile medical center.
"We're improvising," said Dr. Em-Em Pua, who delivered Elvie's baby on Saturday. The plastic and cloth wrapped around the baby is their best attempt with the materials they have to maintain the warm environment the infant needs, she said.
Not far from the regional medical center is the Divine Ward Hospital, a private clinic that is taking on some of the patients the public hospital can't handle.
But the clinic is also deprived of basic needs, and the situation is costing lives. On Friday, a 27-year-old man died from septic shock at Divine Ward resulting from an infection after he broke his leg.
The young man, Richard Pulga, suffered the treatable injured in Haro, an area outside Tacloban, but medical care came too late and underequipped to save him.
"The problem is we didn't have blood," said Dr. Mauro Bravo, who operated on Pulga, whose wound became infected after going three or four days untreated.
There is apparently no blood for transfusions available to hospitals in Tacloban. Like the regional medical center's generator, it has been promised but is yet to materialize.
In the meantime, the doctors battle on. Bravo and his colleague, Dr. Richie Sorilla, came to Tacloban in recent days from Davao, part of the southern Philippine island of Mindanao that was struck by a typhoon that killed more than 1,000 people barely a year ago.
Because of the lack of blood, the doctors are having to resort to amputations to deal with infections.
They had to remove the gangrenous fingertips of a 6-year-old boy who trapped his hand in a door, they said. In all, they've carried out six amputations out of the 17 operations they've undertaken since they arrived.
Back at the regional medical center, the baby girl clings to life.
During a brief moment of levity, her grandmother jokes that the family should name her "Yolanda," after the Philippine name for the devastating typhoon.
In the chapel, which at night is lit by candlelight and flashlights, the baby receives hydration, antibiotics and some oxygen.
One of the other 26 babies in the room is in even more critical condition, having to receive oxygen hand pumped by her parents. Doctors say her prognosis is poor.
Another family receives better news, though. Doctors tell Catherine Pindot, 20, that her son, who was born Monday, will be able to move out of the chapel.
It's too early to tell which of those two paths is more likely for Elvie's tiny daughter.
Until authorities start providing hospitals here with vital equipment and supplies, she will have to continue her struggle without the treatment she really needs.
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
