<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Technology</title>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/TECH/index.html?eref=rss_tech</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2016 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 17:18:21 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 17:18:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Technology</title>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<link>http://www.cnn.com/TECH/index.html?eref=rss_tech</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<item>
<title>Can 'superblimp' unlock hidden riches of Africa?</title>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676977/s/4dd2d22b/sc/40/l/0L0Scnn0N0C20A160C0A20C240Cafrica0Csuperblimp0Eafrica0Cindex0Bhtml0Deref0Frss0Itech/story01.htm</link>
<description>&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392669319/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4dd2d22b/sc/40/rc/1/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392669319/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4dd2d22b/sc/40/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392669319/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4dd2d22b/sc/40/rc/2/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392669319/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4dd2d22b/sc/40/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392669319/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4dd2d22b/sc/40/rc/3/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392669319/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4dd2d22b/sc/40/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392669319/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4dd2d22b/sc/40/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392669319/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4dd2d22b/sc/40/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392669319/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4dd2d22b/sc/40/ach.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392669319/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4dd2d22b/sc/40/ach.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/247392669319/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4dd2d22b/sc/40/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi2.feedsportal.com/r/247392669319/u/89/f/676977/c/35494/s/4dd2d22b/sc/40/a2t2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676977/s/4dd2d22b/sc/40/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2016 17:57:47 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.cnn.com/2016/02/24/africa/superblimp-africa/index.html</guid>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160224103057-hyrbid-airship-4-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" lang="" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160224103057-hyrbid-airship-4-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>Facebook Twitter Instagram
&lt;div class="banner" id="cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0_banner"&gt;&lt;span id="cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" class="_fwph"&gt;&lt;form id="_fw_form_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" style="display:none"&gt;&lt;input type="hidden" name="_fw_input_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" id="_fw_input_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" value="ptgt=s&amp;envp=g_js&amp;w=300&amp;h=250&amp;slau=300x250_sync&amp;adUnit=300x250_sync"&gt;&lt;/form&gt;&lt;span id="_fw_container_cnn_300x250_sync_freewheel-rail_0" class="cn-shingle__ad"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
Can 'superblimp' unlock hidden riches of Africa?
Updated 1528 GMT (2328 HKT) February 24, 2016
19 photos:
The Hybrid Airship from Lockheed Martin and Hybrid Enterprises is the product of 20 years of development. It can travel thousands of kilometers in a single journey, at speeds of up to 60 knots, the company says.
Hide Caption
1 of 19
19 photos:
The airship is designed to allow the delivery of large loads of cargo to otherwise inaccessible areas. It can carry a 20 ton load.
Hide Caption
2 of 19
19 photos:
Lockheed says its airship uses only one tenth of the fuel required by helicopters per ton and, like helicopters, can access remote areas around the world as it does not require an airstrip to land on.
Hide Caption
3 of 19
19 photos:
The design could allow mining of areas such as the frozen North of Canada, or low-infrastructure regions of Guinea.
Hide Caption
The ships are currently undergoing FAA certification, and could be available in 2018.
Hide Caption
The price has not been disclosed, but each ship will likely cost over $10 million.
Hide Caption
6 of 19
19 photos:
Lockheed Martin are not the only firm looking to bring back the blimp. The Airlander 10 is a hybrid airship designed by UK-based firm Hybrid Air Vehicles.
Hide Caption
7 of 19
19 photos:
The lightweight airship, seen here in a concept illustration, can carry up to 10 tons and stay in the air for five days continuously.
Hide Caption
8 of 19
19 photos:
Airlander 10 was originally designed for the U.S. military to use for surveillance of troops and conflict zones overseas, but a lack of funding grounded the project.
Hide Caption
9 of 19
19 photos:
HAV brought the technology back and is underway with plans to lift off again thanks to a £3.4 million ($5.1 million) grant from the UK government, aimed at helping emerging technologies and job creation.
Hide Caption
Another cargo-carrying blimp in the works is the Aeroscraft from U.S.-based aviation company, Aeros.
Hide Caption
11 of 19
19 photos:
The Aeroscraft is designed to carry large loads of cargo over long distances to areas where there is little or no infrastructure.
Hide Caption
12 of 19
19 photos:
Aeroscorp, which also makes advertising airships, is testing a smaller version of the Aeroscraft at the company's massive flight test hangar in Tustin, California.
Hide Caption
13 of 19
19 photos:
Other airships in development include Raytheon's JLENS aerostat, designed to carry out surveillance missions, hovering high in the air 24 hours a day, seven days a week for 30 days at a time.
Hide Caption
14 of 19
19 photos:
Airships were once hailed as the future of flight. Glamorous, luxurious and fast, they were one of the icons of the Art Deco era.
Hide Caption
15 of 19
19 photos:
They developed from the hot air balloon; the Montgolfier brothers launched the first manned balloon flight in Paris in 1783.
Hide Caption
16 of 19
19 photos:
Hydrogen-filled balloons were used for surveillance and reconnaissance during the American Civil War in the 1860s.
Hide Caption
17 of 19
19 photos:
But the Hindenburg disaster at Lakehurst, New Jersey, in 1937, put paid to the era of passenger-carrying airships.
Hide Caption
18 of 19
19 photos:
Over the decades, they have continued to be used for advertising, and at sporting events, such as this one at the London 2012 Olympics.
Hide Caption
The new Hybrid Airship is a helium-powered design capable of hauling 20 tons
The ship may allow the mining of precious minerals in remote parts of Africa
(CNN)
Best known for floating aimlessly above sports stadiums, and for their slightly comic, bloated shape, blimps are an unlikely subject for a 21st century revival.
But after 20 years of development, Lockheed Martin and Hybrid Enterprises are poised to unleash a revolutionary new design that could unlock resources worth billions of dollars across the African continent.
The Hybrid Airship is a helium-powered craft that can cover thousands of kilometers in a single journey, with a top speed of 60 knots. The craft can take off and land without a runway, and the cavernous interior can carry loads of 20 tons.
JUST WATCHED
MUST WATCH
Superblimp: "No roads, no problem" 01:06
At the recent African Mining Indaba event in Cape Town, the Airship was presented as a vital asset for mining companies across the continent. Using the tag "No roads, No problem," promoters emphasized its ability to access remote but lucrative mineral sources.
"It will land on water, sand, a field, even ice," said a Hybrid Enterprises spokesperson.
Read More
13 photos: Kenya's $50 billion megaprojects
13 photos: Kenya's $50 billion megaprojects
Mombasa rail station – Kenya is already an infrastructure powerhouse of East Africa -- leading the region for investment . But the next few years may see a quantum leap forward, with tens of billions of dollars to be spent on some of the world's most spectacular transport, energy and technology projects -- such as the new Mombasa rail station (above).
Through a program entitled Kenya Vision 2030 , the government hopes to deliver a "newly industrialized, middle-income country providing a high quality of life to all its citizens by 2030."
Whether this ambitious goal will actually be achieved remains to be seen. But the following ventures certainly bear the potential to transform the landscape.
Hide Caption
1 of 13
13 photos: Kenya's $50 billion megaprojects
Standard Gauge Railway – The Standard Gauge Railway (SGR) has been described as the most ambitious project in Kenya's independent history -- replacing the antiquated tracks left by the British regime.
Around $4 billion has been invested in 600 kilometers of raised track connecting the hub cities of Nairobi and Mombasa, but it is hoped the line will be a net contributor to the economy for years to come. The SGR should be open for business in 2017.
Hide Caption
2 of 13
13 photos: Kenya's $50 billion megaprojects
Voi Railway Station – The SGR project also includes the construction of state-of-the-art new passenger stations at Nairobi, Voi, and Mombasa.
Hide Caption
13 photos: Kenya's $50 billion megaprojects
Jomo Kenyatta International Airport – Jomo Kenyatta International -- Kenya's premier airport -- is to receive multiple upgrades.
A new greenfield terminal designed by architects Pascall + Watson will be the largest in Africa when it opens in 2017, serving 20 million passengers a year, at a cost of around $650 million.
A second runway will be inaugurated the same year.
Hide Caption
4 of 13
13 photos: Kenya's $50 billion megaprojects
Lamu Port – The multi-faceted Lamu Port and Lamu-Southern Sudan-Ethiopia Transport Corridor (LAPSSET) project is as big as the name suggests, with an outlay of $23 billion across three countries.
The city of Lamu at the southern end of the Corridor is a cornerstone of the project. It will be transformed into a trade hub through the construction of a new 32-berth port, which will be used to supply locations along the line.
Hide Caption
5 of 13
13 photos: Kenya's $50 billion megaprojects
LAPSSET Pipeline – One of the most lucrative commodities to travel the route will be crude oil, through a new pipeline that connects Kenya's oil fields in Turkana Basin with Ugandan and South Sudanese sites. A new refinery will also be constructed.
Hide Caption
6 of 13
13 photos: Kenya's $50 billion megaprojects
Highways – Highways are another key component of Lapsset, with hundreds of kilometers of pristine, new road laid to facilitate transport of goods and people.
The Isiolo -- Marsabit -- Moyale stretch (above) has been completed, connecting to Ethiopia, and facilitating travel to Kenya's safari parks.
Hide Caption
7 of 13
13 photos: Kenya's $50 billion megaprojects
Resort cities – The LAPSSET project will also see three resort cities constructed in Lamu, Isiolo and Lokichogio.
The new sites will be pitched at affluent visitors -- with luxury hotels, entertainment and wildlife reserves.
Hide Caption
8 of 13
13 photos: Kenya's $50 billion megaprojects
Konza Tech City – The much-hyped Konza Tech City - or "Silicon Savannah" - is hoped to be a world-class hub of entrepreneurship.
The $15 billion site, set in 5,000 acres to the south of Nairobi, will accommodate almost 200,000 people, complete with universities, research facilities, and IT centers.
Hide Caption
9 of 13
13 photos: Kenya's $50 billion megaprojects
Konza Tech City – Several delays have marred the project and discouraged some investors, but the government maintains the site will be operational in April 2017.
Hide Caption
10 of 13
13 photos: Kenya's $50 billion megaprojects
Geothermal energy – Kenya has embraced geothermal energy in a big way, aiming to serve one-quarter of its energy needs through this source.
New ventures such as the Ol-Karia IV power plant (pictured) make it one of the world's leading producers, and investment is set to increase.
Hide Caption
13 photos: Kenya's $50 billion megaprojects
Isiolo airport – Apart from Jomo Kenyatta, several smaller airports are undergoing major upgrades.
The provincial Isiolo airport is receiving a new terminal building and a new runway, in anticipation of higher visitor numbers.
Hide Caption
12 of 13
13 photos: Kenya's $50 billion megaprojects
Two Rivers Mall – The largest mall in East Africa will open in Nairobi in March. The 62,000 square meter facility will include housing, hotels, office space and -- of course -- extravagant shopping.
Hide Caption
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
