<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
<language>en-US</language>
<copyright>Copyright 2016 Cable News Network LP, LLLP.</copyright>
<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 12:26:56 GMT</pubDate>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 12:26:56 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<ttl>5</ttl>
<image>
<title>CNN.com - Sport</title>
<url>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/1.0/logo/cnn.logo.rss.gif</url>
<link>http://edition.cnn.com/SPORT/index.html?eref=rss_sport</link>
<description>CNN.com delivers up-to-the-minute news and information on the latest top stories, weather, entertainment, politics and more.</description>
</image>
<item>
<title>New cars for 2016 F1 season</title>
<link>http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676991/s/4db52a3e/sc/13/l/0Ledition0Bcnn0N0C20A160C0A20C190Cmotorsport0Cgallery0C20A160Eformula0Eone0Ecars0Ein0Ephotos0Cindex0Bhtml0Deref0Frss0Isport/story01.htm</link>
<description>Photos of all the new Formula One cars ready to race in 2016.&lt;br clear='all'/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392047363/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4db52a3e/sc/13/rc/1/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392047363/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4db52a3e/sc/13/rc/1/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392047363/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4db52a3e/sc/13/rc/2/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392047363/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4db52a3e/sc/13/rc/2/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392047363/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4db52a3e/sc/13/rc/3/rc.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;&lt;img src="http://rc.feedsportal.com/r/247392047363/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4db52a3e/sc/13/rc/3/rc.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392047363/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4db52a3e/sc/13/a2.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://da.feedsportal.com/r/247392047363/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4db52a3e/sc/13/a2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392047363/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4db52a3e/sc/13/ach.htm"&gt;&lt;img src="http://adchoice.feedsportal.com/r/247392047363/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4db52a3e/sc/13/ach.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi.feedsportal.com/r/247392047363/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4db52a3e/sc/13/a2t.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width="1" height="1" src="http://pi2.feedsportal.com/r/247392047363/u/89/f/676991/c/35494/s/4db52a3e/sc/13/a2t2.img" border="0"/&gt;&lt;img width='1' height='1' src='http://rss.cnn.com/c/35494/f/676991/s/4db52a3e/sc/13/mf.gif' border='0'/&gt;</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 14:52:25 GMT</pubDate>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://edition.cnn.com/2016/02/19/motorsport/gallery/2016-formula-one-cars-in-photos/index.html</guid>
<media:thumbnail height="51" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160219174111-new-formula-one-ferrari-car-2016-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<media:content height="51" lang="" type="image/jpeg" url="http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/160219174111-new-formula-one-ferrari-car-2016-top-tease.jpg" width="90"/>
<ExtractedText>Revealed! The new race cars for the 2016 Formula One season
Updated 1120 GMT (1920 HKT) February 24, 2016
19 photos: Revealed! The new race cars for the 2016 Formula One season
Uncovered! After winning back-to-back team titles, Lewis Hamilton (back) and teammate Nico Rosberg (front) take the covers off the new Mercedes Formula One car.
Hide Caption
1 of 19
19 photos: Revealed! The new race cars for the 2016 Formula One season
Will the aptly-named W07 have a license to thrill in 2016? "When you get to drive a new car for the first time it's still really exciting", says Hamilton. "It's like when you buy a new road car and drive it home for the first time."
Hide Caption
2 of 19
19 photos: Revealed! The new race cars for the 2016 Formula One season
World champion Hamilton gets back on track as he takes the new Mercedes for a spin during the first day of testing at Barcelona's curvaceous Circuit de Catalunya, home to the Spanish Grand Prix.
Hide Caption
3 of 19
19 photos: Revealed! The new race cars for the 2016 Formula One season
Ferrari reveals its new-look red and white racer in an online launch beamed across the globe from Italy. Team principal Maurizio Arrivabene set his intention for 2016: "We would like to fight for the world championship until the end."
Hide Caption
4 of 19
19 photos: Revealed! The new race cars for the 2016 Formula One season
Ferrari drivers Sebastian Vettel and Kimi Raikkonen have five world titles between them. "We work as one team," says Raikkonen at the SF16-H launch. "Obviously we try to beat each other on the track..."
Hide Caption
5 of 19
19 photos: Revealed! The new race cars for the 2016 Formula One season
Sebastian Vettel's Ferrari leads Nico Rosberg's Mercedes in pre-season testing but will the Silver Arrows return to dominance in the opening Australian Grand Prix in Melbourne?
Hide Caption
6 of 19
19 photos: Revealed! The new race cars for the 2016 Formula One season
The Red Bull Formula One team breaks cover in 2016, introducing the livery for the new RB12 racer on a freezing February day in East London.
Hide Caption
7 of 19
19 photos: Revealed! The new race cars for the 2016 Formula One season
Australian racer Daniel Ricciardo tells CNN the 2016 car has a "stealth, aggressive look." Ricciardo won three races with Red Bull in 2014 and after a fallow 2015 he says: "If I can get one this year that will be a good step in the right direction."
Hide Caption
8 of 19
19 photos: Revealed! The new race cars for the 2016 Formula One season
Looking good from above. The Red Bull Racing pit crew get set as Ricciardo brings his new racer back into the pits at the Circuit de Catalunya, the home of F1's winter testing.
Hide Caption
9 of 19
19 photos: Revealed! The new race cars for the 2016 Formula One season
Here's what the first American F1 car for 30 years looks like! Industrialist and NASCAR team owner Gene Haas joins the F1 grid in 2016 with his eponymous Haas F1 Team and the VF-16 car.
Hide Caption
10 of 19
19 photos: Revealed! The new race cars for the 2016 Formula One season
French racer Romain Grosjean -- who has 10 podiums in F1 --  is the first to run the rule over the car in winter testing. Haas has a technical agreement with Ferrari and, because of that, is not necessarily expected to be at the back during its first season.
Hide Caption
11 of 19
19 photos: Revealed! The new race cars for the 2016 Formula One season
Williams raced to third place in the team championship in 2015. It's new FW38 is finished in British red, white and blue and team principal Frank Williams declared: "Only winning will ever be good enough."
Hide Caption
12 of 19
19 photos: Revealed! The new race cars for the 2016 Formula One season
Felipe Massa and Valtteri Bottas are charged with driving the new Williams to success. "We can't wait to get it out on track to see how it feels and how fast it is," says Finland's Bottas, who is still chasing his first victory in F1.
Hide Caption
13 of 19
19 photos: Revealed! The new race cars for the 2016 Formula One season
The 2009 world champion Jenson Button heads to the hills as he stretches the McLaren MP4-31 in Barcelona. The McLaren team is hoping for a brighter 2016 after its engine left them trailing the pack last season.
Hide Caption
14 of 19
19 photos: Revealed! The new race cars for the 2016 Formula One season
Force India's Nico Hulkenberg (left) and Sergio Perez (right) find a new use for the VJM09 car as it is unveiled in winter testing. Let's just hope those tires are super-soft and not hard to sit on.
Hide Caption
15 of 19
19 photos: Revealed! The new race cars for the 2016 Formula One season
The returning Renault team unveil a striking new black livery but suggest there may be another paint job before the first race in Australia on 20 March.
Hide Caption
16 of 19
19 photos: Revealed! The new race cars for the 2016 Formula One season
Renault President Carlos Ghosn (center) is placing the hopes of the French car manufacturer's race team in the hands of British rookie Jolyon Palmer (left) and former McLaren driver Kevin Magnussen (right).
Hide Caption
17 of 19
19 photos: Revealed! The new race cars for the 2016 Formula One season
German driver Pascal Wehrlein gives the new Manor car, the MRT05, its track debut in Barcelona. Wehrlein, who is mentored by the Mercedes team, is hotly-tipped as one to watch as he makes his F1 bow this season.
Hide Caption
18 of 19
19 photos: Revealed! The new race cars for the 2016 Formula One season
Carlos Sainz Jr crosses the line in winter testing but the new Toro Rosso car is far from finished. The Italian team are yet to unveil the new livery for the car.
Hide Caption
</ExtractedText>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
